The world of investing can be a jungle.
華爾街
Bulls. Bears.
牛市  熊市
Danger at every turn.
危機四伏
That's why we at Stratton Oakmont
我們斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的員工
pride ourselves on being the best.
作為叢林之王感到無比自豪
Trained professionals to guide you
我們有訓練有素的專業人員
through the financial wilderness.
引領您穿越金融領域的荒野險境
Stratton Oakmont.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
Stability.
堅實可靠
Integrity.
誠實經營
Pride.
讓您引以為傲
One!
一
Two!
二
Three!
三
Twenty-five grand to the first cocksucker who nail a bull's-eye!
第一個扔中靶心的混蛋我白送兩萬五千塊
Come on! Let's go!
來吧  開始
One!
一
Two!
二
Three!
三
My name is Jordan Belfort.
我叫喬丹·貝爾福
Not him.
不是他
Me. That's right.
是我  沒錯
I'm a former member of the middle class
我以前是個中產階級
raised by two accountants
父母都是會計
in a tiny apartment in Bayside, Queens.
在皇后區貝賽的一個小公寓里長大
The year I turned 26,
我26歲那年
as the head of my own brokerage firm,
作為老總在自己的經濟公司
I made $49 million,
賺了4900萬
which really pissed me off
說來還真讓我不爽
because it was three shy of a million a week.
還差300萬就是一周賺100萬了
No, no, no. My Ferrari was white,
不不不   我的法拉利是白色的
like Don Johnson's in Miami Vice.
和《邁阿密風云》里唐·約翰遜的一樣
Not red.
不是紅的
See that humongous estate down there?
看見那座莊園了嗎
That's my house.
那是我的房子
My wife, Naomi,
我妻子內奧米
the Duchess of Bay Ridge, Brooklyn,
布魯克林灣脊區的女公爵
a former model and Miller Lite girl.
以前是模特  拍過美樂淡啤的廣告
Yeah.
沒錯
She was the one with my cock in her mouth in the Ferrari.
剛在法拉利里給我口交就是她
So put your dick back in your pants.
所以把你的老二塞回褲襠里吧
In addition to Naomi and my two perfect kids,
除了內奧米和兩個可愛的孩子
I own a mansion, a private jet,
我還有一座豪宅  一架私人飛機
six cars, three horses,
六輛豪車  三匹駿馬
two vacation homes, and a 170-foot yacht.
兩處度假別墅和一艘170英尺長的游艇
Anchors aweigh!
起錨了
I also gamble like a degenerate. I drink like a fish.
我還賭博成癮  嗜酒成性
I fuck hookers maybe five, six times a week.
一周能上五六次小姐
I have three different federal agencies looking to indict me.
三所不同的聯邦機構盯著想起訴我
Oh, yeah, and I love drugs.
我還酷愛嗑藥
One more round.
再來一輪
- Oh, you like it? - Yeah.
-你喜歡嗎  -喜歡
Pull up. Pull up!
拉起來  快拉起來
We're gonna crash, for Christ sake!
快墜機了  老天
Relax!
放松
Just relax.
別緊張
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm all right.
-你還好吧  -沒事
Good job.
好樣的
You get in there safe, all right?
回去小心
Till the next time, brother.
下次見  老兄
Till next time.
下次見
Yup, on a daily basis I consume enough drugs
我每天吃的藥量足夠把
to sedate Manhattan, Long Island and Queens for a month.
曼哈頓  長島和皇后區放倒一個月
Okay, Mr. Jordan.
喬丹先生
I take Quaaludes 10 to 15 times a day for my "Back pain,"
我每天吃10到15片安眠酮緩解"背疼"
Adderall to stay focused,
一種治療注意力缺失的藥
Xanax to take the edge off, pot to mellow me out,
吃佳樂定抗焦慮  抽點大麻放松
cocaine to wake me back up again and morphine, well,
嗑點可卡因清醒一下  再來點嗎啡
because it's awesome.
因為那玩意真是一級棒
Good morning, Nathan.
早上好  奈森
But of all the drugs under God's blue heaven,
但是世界上所有的藥中
there is one that is my absolute favorite.
有一種我最為愛不釋手
You see, enough of this shit'll make you invincible.
嗑夠了這鬼東西你就所向披靡了
Able to conquer the world,
足以征服全世界
and eviscerate your enemies.
殺得敵人片甲不留
And I'm not talking about this.
我說的不是這個
I'm talking about this.
我說的是這個
See, money doesn't just buy you a better life,
金錢不僅能給你帶來更好的生活
better food, better cars, better pussy.
更精美的食物  更好的車  更美的妞
It also makes you a better person.
還能讓你成為更好的人
You can give generously to the church
你可以慷慨資助教會
or political party of your choice.
或你支持的政黨
You can save the fucking spotted owl with money.
錢甚至能拯救瀕危的斑點貓頭鷹
I always wanted to be rich.
我一直都想當富翁
So let me go back.
回頭看看過去
I'm 22 years old, newly married,
22歲的我  剛結婚
and already a money-crazed little shit.
就已經是個追名逐利的小混蛋了
So what do I do?
那我怎么辦呢
I go to the one place on earth
我去了唯一一個
that befit my high-minded ambitions.
能滿足我野心的地方
I love you.
我愛你
You are lower than pond scum.
你的地位還不如水藻
You got a problem with that,
有什么意見嗎
Jordan?
喬丹
No. No problem at all.
沒  完全沒有
Good. Because that is what you are.
很好  因為你現在就這地位
Pond scum.
水藻
Your job is connector,
你的工作是聯絡員
which means
也就是說
that you'll be dialing the phone over 500 times a day
你每天要打500多次電話
trying to connect me with wealthy business owners.
想法讓我聯系上有錢的大老板
And until you pass your Series 7,
在你考下證券經紀人執照前
that is all you're gonna fucking be doing. Sit.
你他媽也只能干這個  坐下
Sit!
坐下
Now just so you know, last year I made over $300,000.
我告訴你  我去年賺了30多萬
The other guy you'll be working for, he made over a million.
你的另一個頭兒  他賺了100多萬
A million dollars?
100萬
I could only imagine what a douchebag that guy must be.
可想而知那家伙得多變態
- Jordan Belfort. - Yes, sir.
-喬丹·貝爾福  -是  先生
- Mark Hanna. - A pleasure to meet you.
-我是馬克·漢納  -很高興認識您
And you as well.
我也是
I see you've already met the village asshole.
我看你已經見過那個地頭蛇了
Smile and dial.
撥號并微笑
And don't pick up your fucking head until 1:00.
1點前別他媽抬頭
Hey, fuck him.
甭管他
I'm the senior broker here.
我才是高級經紀人
He's just a worthless piker.
他就是個當差的
Why don't you blow me, Hanna?
來給我吹個簫吧  漢納
Now did you really pitch a stock in your job interview?
你真在面試的時候賣出去一股嗎
I had to do something to stand out.
想脫穎而出總得干點實事
Right, sir?
是吧  先生
I fucking love that.
就喜歡你這樣的
- Lunch. Today. - Yeah.
-中午一起吃飯  -好
We don't start dialing at 9:30
如果我們不在9點半整立刻開始打電話
because our clients are already answering the phone.
我們的客戶就占線了
Three. Two. One.
三  二  一
Let's fuck!
干起來吧
You want to know what money sounds like?
你想知道金錢聽上去什么樣嗎
Go to a trading floor on Wall Street.
去華爾街的交易大廳聽聽吧
"Fuck" This, "Shit" That.
操這個日那個的
"Cunt," "Cock," "Asshole."
婊子  雞巴  屁眼什么的
I couldn't believe how these guys talked to each other.
這些人說的話簡直讓我難以置信
- Good fucking package... - Piece of shit!
-這一攬子交易真他媽好  -爛狗屎
I was hooked in seconds.
我當時就著迷了
It was like mainlining adrenaline.
跟打了雞血似的
Yeah. Fuckface, look at where the stock's at today, huh?
混賬  看看今天股票怎么樣
You motherfucker,
日你媽
you can't get any at 44...
要是44你什么也撈不到
- Pick up the cocksucking phone! - Sorry...
-快他媽打電話去  -抱歉
You are such a fucking douchebag, Hanna.
你真是個臭傻逼  漢納
We don't give two shits about how technology works
我們才不管什么技術
because all we care about is getting fucking rich.
我們只關心他媽怎么能賺錢
- Solid, 2,000. - Jordan Belfort.
-定了  2000  -喬丹·貝爾福
Done!
成功了
Time to paint the tape.
該抬價了[以不正當手段哄抬股價]
2,000. Microsoft. Going in the hole!
微軟  2000股  上鉤了
Come on.
過來
Live. Live. Hold on, that is hot.
直播  拿著  小心燙手
In. In. Shut that motherfucker. Shut it! Shut it! Shut it!
放進去  把那玩意關上  關上關上
Sold!
成交了
Tootski?
可卡因來點
Oh, no. Thank you, though.
不用了  謝謝
Mr. Hanna,
漢納先生
what can I bring for you on this glorious afternoon?
這么美好的午后  您要來點什么
Well, Hector, here's the game plan.
赫克托  我告訴你怎么玩
You're gonna bring us two Absolut Martinis.
給我們上兩杯馬丁尼
You know how I like them. Straight up.
你知道我的口味  要純的
And then precisely seven and one half minutes after that,
整7分半后
you're gonna bring us two more.
再上兩杯
Then two more after that every five minutes
然后每5隔分鐘上兩杯
until one of us passes the fuck out.
直到我倆喝倒一個為止
Excellent strategy, sir.
這想法不錯  先生
I'm good with water for now.
我現在喝水就好
Thank you.
謝謝
It's his first day on Wall Street.
他今天剛來華爾街工作
Give him time.
他會習慣的
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-謝謝  -謝謝
Mr. Hanna?
漢納先生
You're able to do drugs during the day
你白天嗑了藥
and then still function, still do your job?
還能正常工作嗎
How the fuck else would you do this job?
不然你以為怎么正常工作
Cocaine and hookers, my friend.
就憑可卡因和妓女了  哥們
Right.
是
Well, I got to say,
我想說
I'm incredibly excited to be a part of your firm. I mean...
能加入你們我真的很高興
The clients you have are absolutely...
你們的客戶實在是...
Fuck the clients.
去他媽的客戶
Your only responsibility is to put meat on the table.
你唯一的職責就是引他們上鉤
You got a girlfriend?
你有女朋友嗎
I'm married. I have a wife.
我結婚了
Her name is Teresa. She cuts hair.
我妻子叫泰瑞莎  理發的
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
-恭喜  -謝謝
Think about Teresa.
多想想泰瑞莎
Name of the game.
你要干的就是
Move the money from your client's pocket into your pocket.
把你客戶兜里的錢揣到你兜里
Right.
是
But if you make your clients money at the same time,
但如果同時能幫客戶賺錢
it's advantageous to everyone. Correct?
不是互惠互利嗎
No.
不
Number one rule of Wall Street.
華爾街第一要義
Nobody...
沒有人
I don't care if you're Warren Buffett
不管你是沃倫·巴菲特也好
or if you're Jimmy Buffett.
吉米·巴菲特也好
Nobody knows if a stock is gonna go up, down,
沒人知道股票是漲是跌
sideways, or in fucking circles.
是持平還是兜圈子
Least of all stockbrokers, right?
股票經紀人更不知道  懂嗎
It's all a fugazi. You know what a fugazi is?
都是掩的  你知道什么叫掩吧
Fugayzie. It's a fake.
"贗"嗎  就是假的
Fugayzi, fugazi, it's a whazy, it's a woozy, it's...
什么掩啊贗啊  嫖啊飄啊的
Fairy dust. It doesn't exist.
都是虛無縹緲的  根本不存在
It's never landed. It is no matter.
看不見摸不著
It's not on the elemental chart.
元素周期表上找不到
It's not fucking real.
根本都他媽是假的
- Right? - Right.
-對不  -對
Stay with me.
繼續聽我講
We don't create shit. We don't build anything.
我們屁都不創造  什么都不建
No.
的確
So if you got a client who bought stock at eight
所以假設你有個客戶花8塊買了一股
and it now sits at 16, he's all fucking happy.
現在漲到16了  他樂開花了
He wants to cash in, liquidate,
就想兌現清算
take his fucking money and run home.
拿上錢打包走人
- You don't let him do that. - Okay.
-這可不行  -好的
- 'Cause that would make it real. - Right.
-因為那樣就成真錢了  -是
No. What do you do?
那該做什么
You get another brilliant idea.
你得繼續給他出金點子
A special idea.
額外的想法
Another "situation."
制造另一種"情況"
Another stock to reinvest his earnings and then some.
讓他拿收益再投一支股票  不斷投
And he will, every single time.
他每次也一定會投
'Cause they're fucking addicted.
因為他們全都他媽是癮君子
And you just keep doing this,
你就一直這么干
again and again and again.
延綿不斷  無休無止
Meanwhile, he thinks he's getting shit rich,
他這時覺得自己要成土豪了
which he is, on paper.
理論上他的確賺了
But you and me, the brokers,
但我們這些經紀人
we're taking home cold hard cash
從中收的傭金
via commission, motherfucker.
可都是實打實的現金  學著沒
Right.
是
That's incredible, sir.
這太神奇了  老板
I can't tell you how excited I am.
我都激動的無以言表了
You should be.
你就該興奮
There's two keys to success in the broker business.
做經紀人這行的成功要素有兩點
First of all...
首先
- You gotta stay relaxed. - Yeah.
-你得淡定  -是
Do you jerk off?
你平時擼嗎
Do I... Do I jerk off?
擼...擼嗎
Yeah. Yeah, I jerk off. Yeah.
擼  擼啊  我當然擼
How many times a week?
每周幾次
Like three or four.
三四次吧
Three or four times, maybe five.
三四次  有時五次
Gotta pump those numbers up.
你得多擼啊
Those are rookie numbers in this racket.
干這行  你這次數太菜鳥了
I myself, I jerk off at least twice a day.
我本人吧  每天至少兩發
Once in the morning right after I work out,
早晨健身之后來一發
then once right after lunch.
午飯后再來一發
Really?
真的嗎
I want to. That's not why I do it.
我喜歡擼  但我擼不是因為喜歡
I do it 'cause I fucking need to.
全他媽是被逼的
Think about it. You're dealing with numbers.
你想想  你是跟數字打交道的
All day long, decimal points, high frequencies.
整天都是什么小數點啊  高頻交易啊
Fucking digits.
全他媽是數
All very acidic above-the-shoulders mustard shit.
每天重任在肩  喘不過氣啊
All right?
對吧
It kind of wigs some people out. Right.
太讓人抓狂了  是吧
You got to feed the geese to keep the blood flowing.
所以就得多擼  保持血液流通順暢
I keep the rhythm below the belt.
私底下控制住節奏
Done.
懂了
This is not a tip, this is a prescription.
我這可不是提醒你  我給你開處方呢
Trust me.
相信我
If you don't, you will fall out of balance,
你不這么干  就沒法平衡了
split your differential and tip the fuck over.
差額搞不清楚你就載了
Or worse yet,
還有更糟的
I've seen this happen, implode.
我親眼見過  猝死
No, I don't want to implode, sir.
別介  我可不想猝死  老板
No. No, you don't.
當然  沒人想
I'm in it for the long run, you know?
我干這行看得很長遠的
- Implosions are ugly. - Yeah.
-猝死可不是什么好事  -是
Pop off to the bathroom, work one out any time you can.
所以有空就去洗手間來一發
When you get really good at it,
等你擼順手了
you'll fucking be stroking it
一邊擼著
and you'll be thinking about money.
一邊腦子里想的都是錢
Second key to success in this racket
干這行成功要素之二
is this little baby right here.
就是這瓶子里的寶貝
It's called cocaine.
叫可卡因
Right.
是
It'll keep you sharp between the ears.
能讓你耳聰目明
It'll also help your fingers dial faster.
還能讓你撥號指速如飛
And guess what?
你猜怎么著
That's good for me.
你撥號快了  我就賺了
Yes, sir.
好了  先生
Revolutions. You follow?
周轉不息  明白嗎
Revolutions.
周轉不息
Keep the clients on the Ferris wheel.
讓客戶坐上摩天輪
And it goes.
我們就開賺
The park is open 24/7, 365,
游樂園365天全天候給他開著
every decade, every goddamn century.
十年如一日  百年也他媽這樣
That's it.
就這么回事
The name of the game.
這就是游戲規則
Halkidiki?
嘗嘗希臘橄欖
Thank you.
謝謝
Come on.
一起來
We're the common denominator.
我們是公分母
Keep it up for me.
繼續
You've seen the echo
你懂這回事
And the money comes in
我們談著錢
The parade comes to town
游行進了城
Going down Broadway
走到百老匯
It's a one-way street
不管往哪去
Whichever way I go
都沒回頭路
The next six months,
之后的六個月
I got to know the ins and outs of Wall Street.
我開始了解華爾街的門道
Earning shit money as I geared up to take my Series 7.
邊賺小錢邊準備考執照
Oh, fuckers.
真他媽爽
Then I was a licensed broker at last,
后來我終于拿下了執照
ready to make my fortune.
準備開始掙大錢了
My first day as a future Master of the Universe.
那天起我開始向未來宇宙之王邁進
I have Exxon at 86 and a quarter six months ago.
六個月前埃克森還是86塊2毛5
Today it is trading at 36 and a half.
現在都跌到36塊5了
Mr...
先生  先...
They called it Black Monday.
他們管那天叫黑色星期一
No shit.
真不是鬧著玩的
By 4:00 p.m., the market had dropped 508 points.
下午4點  股市已經暴跌了508個點
The biggest plummet
是自1929年大蕭條以來
since the crash of '29.
最嚴重的一次崩盤
I know your family, you know mine.
我了解你的家庭  你也了解我的
No, I don't know. Some fucking country in Europe took a shit.
我不知道  歐洲某個傻逼國家干的
Let them do what they want to fucking do.
讓他們玩兒蛋去吧
Our market's solid.
我們的市場固若金湯
This is not something that you want to sell.
你不該賣掉這個
You know what happened? A fucking tsunami.
你知道怎么回事嗎  簡直金融海嘯
I think you're making a big mistake.
我覺得你這樣以后要后悔的
Yes, I will talk to your wife.
好  我可以和你妻子談
Trust me, do not answer the phone.
相信我  別接電話
A lot of people are gonna be calling you,
會有許多人給您致電
trying to get your dirty laundry.
要挖您的家丑
We don't know what's going on here.
我們不知道怎么回事
I know. I know.
我知道  我知道
Holy
我了個
fucking shit!
大操
Unbelievable.
難以置信
My first shitty day as a broker.
我剛當上經濟人就這么操蛋
Within a month,
不到一個月
L.F. Rothschild,
L.F.羅斯柴爾德
an institution since 1899,
一所始建于1899年的投資銀行
closed its doors.
關門大吉了
Wall Street had swallowed me up
華爾街把我吃干抹凈
and shit me right back out again.
又把我拉出來了
We could pawn my engagement ring if we needed to.
實在不行我們可以把訂婚戒指當掉
- Babe... - Because I don't mind.
-親愛的...-我不介意
If we needed to, I'm saying...
我是說實在不行的話
- Will you listen to me? - Okay.
-能聽我說嗎  -好吧
You're not pawning anything. Okay?
什么都不用典當  好嗎
- Okay. - What do I always tell you?
-好  -我一直怎么跟你說的
You're gonna be a millionaire.
你會成為百萬富翁
That's right. Okay? Just let me look.
沒錯  讓我再看看
We'll find something.
會找到工作的
- How about this? - What?
-這個怎么樣  -什么
Nobody Beats the Wiz, the electronics store.
奇才必勝  那個電器店
Stock boy. What do you think?
存貨管理員 電器  電視  音響 奇才           必勝
You're not gonna work at that place.
你不能去那地方工作
Yeah, but, you know, you start off...
但是先從...
Jordan, you're gonna be miserable at that place
喬丹  你去那兒的話
- if you go there. - I know.
-會痛苦死的  -我知道
It's sales. You work your way up, you'll be a general manager.
先是做銷售  就能一路爬到總經理了
- You're not gonna be a stock boy. - Why not?
-你不能做貨品管理員  -為什么
'Cause you're a stockbroker.
因為你是股票經紀人
You understand that nobody's hiring stockbrokers right now?
你知道現在沒人雇股票經紀人了吧
You understand that?
你知道吧
Okay?
好嗎
This place is.
這地方要
- What? - What's that say?
-什么  -上面寫什么
"Stockbrokers."
股票經紀人
In Long Island?
在長島
- Stockbrokers in Long Island? - Yeah.
-去長島做股票經紀人  -對
It's in Long Island. So what?
是在長島  那又如何
Hey, I'm looking for Investor's Center.
我找投資者中心
What's that? You want to invest?
那是什么  你要投股票嗎
No. Investor's Center. I'm looking for Investor's Center.
不  投資者中心  我找投資者中心
Yeah, yeah, that's us. Hey. This is it. This is it.
對對  就是我們  就是這兒
- I'm Dwayne. - You're Dwayne?
-我叫德維恩  -你就是德維恩
Hi, Dwayne. We spoke on the phone.
你好  德維恩  我們在電話里談過
I'm Jordan Belfort.
我是喬丹·貝爾福
I'm the broker from Rothschild in New York.
那個紐約羅斯柴爾德的經紀人
Yes, yeah. Have a seat. How are you?
是  請坐  你好嗎
We had a conversation...
我們談過...
We spoke on the phone earlier, right?
我們之前講過電話  對吧
- Two hours ago. - Right.
-兩小時前  -對
Yeah.
沒錯
They're up and comers. That's what that means.
它們都是潛力股  就是這意思
It's three cents a share, that's $3!
一股3分錢  就是3塊錢
You cheap fuck!
你個小氣鬼
So...
那么
So where are your Quotrons here?
你們的科特龍在哪呢
- Quotrons? - Yeah. Your computers.
-科特龍  -對  就是電腦
No, no. We don't even need computers here.
不  我們這兒不用電腦
We just trade right off the pink sheets here.
就在這些粉色股票單上交易
- Pink sheets? - Yeah, they're penny stocks.
-粉色股票單  -對  都是仙股
You know, companies that can't get listed on NASDAQ,
就那些資金不足  沒法在納斯達克
they don't have enough capital?
上市的公司
Their shares trade here.
這些股票就在這兒交易
- Penny stocks? - Yeah.
-仙股  -對
This one, Aerodyne, is a really interesting...
這個艾洛帶因就是家非常有意思...
Or Aerotyne...
還是叫艾洛泰因來著
Aerotyne, yeah.
艾洛泰因  對
Aero... Aerotyne...
艾洛  艾洛泰因
Aerotyne. Yeah.
艾洛泰因  沒錯
Very hot stock right now.
現在炙手可熱
Oh, yeah?
是嗎
They're just a couple of brothers that are making
是幾個兄弟在車庫里
radar detectors out of their garage.
造的雷達探測器
They're out in Dubuque.
在迪比克市
Maybe it's microwaves. I'm not sure.
也許是微波爐  我也不清楚
But you call the company's main line,
但撥他們公司的主機
their mom, Dorothy, answers and she is so sweet.
是他們的媽媽多蘿西接  人特別好
- Good company. - I actually don't know what else to...
-真是家好公司  -我都不知道還有什么
I don't know anything else about them other than that.
除了這些  我對他們一無所知
Six cents a share?
一股6分錢嗎
Hey, come on. Who buys this crap?
拜托  這種垃圾誰買
Well, I mean... Honestly, mostly schmucks.
其實買主大多是些蠢貨
Postmen, there's always postmen.
郵差  總少不了郵差
Plumbers.
管道工
They see our ads in the back of
在《皮條客》和《大眾機械》的封底
Hustler and Popular Mechanics.
看到我們的廣告
Our ads actually say they can get rich quick.
我們廣告寫著能快速致富
- Hustler? - Yeah.
-《皮條客》  -對
You know, those girlie magazines.
就那種色情雜志
Yeah, yeah. Nudie mag.
是啊  裸女雜志
A lot.
一絲不掛
We're helping them finance houses,
我們要幫他們買房
we're helping them buy their wife a diamond ring...
給老婆買鉆戒
a boat maybe.
也可能是買船
Is this... Is this stuff regulated or are you guys...
這地方有人管嗎  還是你們...
What are you doing here?
你們這是干什么呢
Sort of.
算是吧
Jesus Christ, the spread on these is huge.
天哪  這買賣差額好大
Yeah. And that's the point, that's...
是  重點就在這兒
What's your name again?
你叫什么來著
Mine... Jordan Belfort.
我  叫喬丹·貝爾福
Jordan, what do you get on that blue chip stock?
喬丹  藍籌股你賺多少傭金
I make one percent. Or I did make one percent.
1%  我原來賺1%
Pink sheets, it's 50.
粉色股票單上你賺50%
50% commission?
50%的傭金嗎
- Yup. - For what?
-沒錯  -為什么
It's our markup for our services.
這就是我們服務的加價
And so if I... If I...
這么說  如果我
If I sell a stock at $10,000,
一支股賣出去一萬塊錢
my commission is 5,000 bucks?
我的傭金就是5000塊
If you sell $10,000 worth of this stock,
如果你這支股賣出去1萬塊錢
I will personally give you a blowjob for free.
我親自免費給你吹簫
And I hope it happens.
我翹首以盼
Hello, John, how are you doing today?
你好  約翰  今天怎么樣
You mailed in my company a postcard a few weeks back
你幾周前寄了一張明信片到我公司
requesting information on penny stocks that had
咨詢上漲潛力巨大
huge upside potential with very little downside risk.
下跌風險極小的仙股嗎
Does that ring a bell?
還記得嗎
Yeah, I may have sent something.
我好像的確寄過
Okay, great. The reason for the call today, John, is,
太好了  約翰  我今天打電話給你
something just came across my desk, John.
因為我剛剛發現一支潛力股
It is perhaps the best thing I've seen in the last six months.
大概能算我半年來見過最棒的一支
If you have 60 seconds,
我想跟你聊聊
I'd like to share the idea with you. You got a minute?
只要60秒  1分鐘好嗎
Actually, I'm really very...
我其實現在...
The name of the company, Aerotyne International.
公司名叫艾洛泰因國際
It is a cutting edge high-tech firm out of the Midwest
這是中西部一家尖端高科技公司
awaiting imminent patent approval
艾洛泰因 IND.
on the next generation of radar detectors
雷達探測器的專利許可
that have both huge military
現在這種雷達探測器的
and civilian applications now.
軍用和民用價值都非常高
Right now, John,
就是現在  約翰
the stock trades over-the-counter at 10 cents a share.
直接交易股價10美分一股
And by the way, John, our analysts indicate
還有  約翰  我們的分析師
it could go a heck of a lot higher than that.
認為這支股票日后能漲上天
Your profit on a mere $6,000 investment
你只要投資6000塊
would be upwards of $60,000!
就能賺到6萬塊的收益
Jesus! That's my mortgage, man.
老天  我住房按揭就6萬
Exactly. You could pay off your mortgage.
沒錯  你就能還清按揭了
This stock will pay off my house?
這股票能幫我還清房貸
John, one thing I can promise you,
約翰  就算股市這個樣子
even in this market,
我也能向你保證一件事
is that I never ask my clients
那就是我從不讓客戶
to judge me on my winners.
關注我賭對的股
I ask them to judge me on my losers
我讓他們看我賭輸的股票
because I have so few.
因為我賭輸的太少了
And in the case of Aerotyne,
至于艾洛泰因
based on every technical factor out there, John,
基于目前所有的技術因素  約翰
we are looking at a grand slam home run.
這絕對是滿貫全壘打
Okay, let's do it. I'll do four grand.
行  投吧  我投4000塊
$4,000? That'd be 40,000 shares, John.
4000美金  那就是4萬股  約翰
Let me lock in that trade right now
我現在就去下單
and get back to you with my secretary
然后讓我秘書聯系你
with an exact confirmation. Sound good, John?
確認信息  可以嗎  約翰
- Yeah, sounds good. - Great.
-行  很好  -好極了
Hey, John.
約翰
Thank you for your vote of confidence.
感謝您的信任
And welcome to the Investor's Center.
歡迎加入投資者中心
Yeah, thanks a lot, man.
非常感謝  老兄
Bye-bye.
再見
How'd you fucking do that?
你他媽怎么做到的
Just like that, I made two grand.
我就這樣賺了2000塊
The other guys looked at me
其他人都目瞪口呆地看著我
like I'd just discovered fire.
好像我剛發現了如何取火
Great! Even better!
好  那更好了
I was selling garbage to garbage men
我把垃圾股賣給垃圾人
and making cash hand over fist.
自己賺了個盆滿缽滿
The only problem you're gonna have
你將來只有一個問題
is that you didn't buy more.
就是當初買太少了
- So I was selling them shit. - Way to go.
-我賣給別人的都是垃圾  -加油
But the way I looked at it,
但在我看來
their money was better off in my pocket.
他們的錢在我口袋里更好
I knew how to spend it better.
我更懂得怎么花錢
Excuse me. Is that your car in the lot?
不好意思  停車場里那輛車是你的嗎
Yeah.
是
- It's a nice ride. - Thanks, man.
-真漂亮啊  -謝了
Donnie Azoff.
我叫唐尼·亞速
Hey. I'm Jordan Belfort.
我叫喬丹·貝爾福
- Nice to meet you. - How you doing?
-幸會  -你好
You know, actually, I see that car around.
我常看到那輛車
- I see it around a lot. - Oh, yeah, where?
-經常看到  -是嗎  在哪看到的
I think we live in the same building.
我們好像住同一棟樓
- No shit? - Yeah, yeah.
-真的假的  -真的
- Twelfth floor? - Yeah. What floor are you on?
-你住12樓吧  -是啊  你住幾樓
Fourth floor.
4樓
- I have two little kids. Ugly wife. - Right.
-我有兩個孩子  老婆很丑  -這樣啊
What do you do, bro?
你做什么的  兄弟
What do you mean, what do I do?
什么叫  我做什么的
For work, what do you do?
工作  你做什么工作的
I'm a stockbroker.
我是股票經紀人
- Stockbroker? - Yeah.
-股票經紀人  -對
Children's furniture.
我賣兒童家具的
Oh, good for you.
不錯啊
It's all right.
還行吧
You make a lot of money?
你賺錢多嗎
Yeah, I do all right for myself.
我自己覺得還不錯吧
I'm trying to put it together.
我就想理理清楚
You got your fucking nice car,
你開輛這么炫酷的車
we live in the same building. I just...
還跟我住同一棟樓里
I'm not understanding... How much money do you make?
我有點想不通  你賺多少
I don't know. $70,000 last month.
不好說  上個月賺了七萬
Get the fuck...
你他媽
Get the fuck out of here.
你他媽別逗了
No, I'm serious.
我認真的
Yeah, no, I'm serious, too.
我也是認真的
Seriously, how much money do you make?
說真的  你到底賺多少
I told you. $70,000.
我說了  七萬
Well, technically, $72,000.
確切來說應該是七萬二
Last month. Something like that.
上個月差不多就這么多吧
You made 72 grand in one month?
你一個月賺七萬二嗎
Yeah.
是的
I'll tell you what.
我跟你說
You show me a pay stub for $72,000 on it,
你把寫著七萬二的工資單拿給我看
I quit my job right now and I work for you.
我立馬辭職跟你混
Hey, Paulie, what's up?
保利  你好啊
No, yeah, yeah. No, everything's fine.
不  沒事  都挺好的
Hey, listen, I quit.
我要辭職
And he did quit his job.
他真的辭職了
Which I thought was a little weird.
我覺得有點怪
I mean, I just met this fucking guy.
我他媽才遇見這家伙
Don't fucking tell Susan. It's none of her business.
別他媽告訴蘇珊  跟她沒關系
There were other things about him, too.
這人還不止這一件事奇怪
Like his phosphorescent white teeth.
比如他白得發光的牙齒
Wife! I gotta fucking deal with your wife?
你老婆  我他媽還管你老婆
The fact that he wore horn rims with clear lenses
他用角制鏡架透明鏡片
just to look more WASP-y.
就為了看著更像上層階級
And then, there were these rumors.
還有那些流言
I heard some stupid shit. I don't know.
我聽到一些愚蠢的流言  怎么說呢
Fuck, I didn't even want to bring it up. It's just...
我操  我都不想提的  就是...
- It's stupid. - Shit with me?
-蠢透了  -有關我的流言
You know, people say shit. I don't even know.
人們就喜歡說三道四  我都不知道
I don't even listen to it half the time.
半數時間我都不會去聽
What are they saying?
他們說什么呢
Shit about you and your cousin or something like that.
說你和你表妹的傳言
I don't even listen to it.
我才不去聽呢
Bro, it's not like that.
老兄  不是他們說的那樣
It's not like that.
不是的
Like you married your cousin or some stupid shit. No?
說你娶了你表妹什么的  沒有嗎
Yeah, my wife. Yeah.
是  我老婆
My wife is my cousin, or whatever.
我老婆是我表妹
But it's not like what you think, or whatever, you know.
但不是你以為的那樣
Is she like a first cousin, or is she...
她是你的嫡表妹嗎  還是...
Yeah, no, she's, you know...
對  不是  她是...
Her... Her father
她爸
is the brother of my mom.
是我媽的弟弟
It's not like, what... You know.
不是那樣的
Look, we grew up together.
我們一起長大
And she grew up hot, you know. She fucking grew up hot.
她出落得很性感  真他媽性感
And all my friends were trying to fuck her, you know.
我朋友都想上她
And I'm not gonna let someone...
我可不會讓別人
You know, one of these assholes fuck my cousin,
讓這些傻逼上我表妹
so, you know, I used the cousin thing as like an in with her.
我就用表哥的身份接近她
I'm not gonna let someone else fuck my cousin.
我可不會讓別人上我表妹
You know, if anyone's gonna fuck my cousin,
要有人上我表妹
it's gonna be me, out of respect. You know?
那也得是我  出于尊重
No, I get it. Yeah.
我明白
I mean, you're not afraid of like the whole kid thing, right?
你不怕生孩子出事嗎
- What? Having kids with her? - Yeah.
-什么  跟她生孩子嗎  -是的
No. We have two kids.
不怕  我們有兩個孩子了
And they're... I mean...
他們...
I don't want to get personal, but they're okay?
這不是人身攻擊  不過他們沒事嗎
No, they're not retarded or anything like that.
沒有  他們不是弱智之類的
But there's a big chance, right, if...
但很有可能吧...
Yeah, there's like a 60%, you know,
是啊  大概60%
60% to 65% chance the kid's gonna be fucking retarded or whatever.
60%到65%的機會孩子會是弱智
That'd scare the shit out of me, buddy.
我他媽嚇尿了  老兄
Look, man, a lot of having a kid, or whatever, takes risk,
不管操的是不是表妹
whether you're fucking cousins or not.
生孩子都有風險
What if something like that happened?
如果你的孩子真是弱智怎么辦
Basically, you know, if the kid was retarded,
基本上  孩子要真是弱智
I would, you know, drive it up to the country
我就開車到荒郊野外
and just, like, you know, open the door and say,
打開車門然后說
"You're free now." You know, like, "Run free."
"你自由了"  "自由奔跑吧"之類的
You know?
你懂的吧
You're completely fucking with me.
你他媽逗我玩呢
That's horrible. You're not gonna...
那太可怕了  你才不會...
You look like you've... No.
你的樣子好像...不會
We would take it to, like, an institution or somewhere
我們會帶孩子去特殊機構什么的
that's handled to, like, you know, raise the kid or whatever.
或是專門負責撫養孩子的地方
You know what? If you're happy, God bless you, buddy.
如果你很開心  那上帝保佑你
No, I'm not fucking happy. No one who's married is fucking happy.
不  我他媽哪里開心了
No one who's married is fucking happy.
誰他媽結婚了還會開心啊
Well, I'm sorry to hear that, buddy.
聽你這么說很遺憾  兄弟
Listen, I'm really, you know...
我真的...
I'm really appreciative for this fucking job.
我真的很感謝你給我這份工作
I'm really enjoying it.
我真的很喜歡
I'm really happy with what you're doing.
我很滿意你現在的表現
Actually, I got you a little present.
我給你準備了一份禮物
- You got me a present? - I got you something.
-你給我準備了禮物  -一點小心意
Oh, fuck. You're sweet.
媽的  你真好
Yeah. It's in the back though.
不過在酒吧后面
- What do you mean? - You gotta go out back.
-什么意思  -你得去后面
Like it's wrapped up or something?
是禮物包起來了嗎
It's wrapped up. Yeah.
對  包起來了
- I don't get it. - Neither do I.
-我不明白  -我也不明白
Let's fucking go. Come on.
快他媽走吧  走吧
Your turn.
到你了
I'm not fucking doing this. You're out of your fucking mind.
我才不吸  你他媽瘋了吧
- Smoke this shit, bro. - No.
-抽點這玩意兒  -不要
No one's fucking here, bro.
這兒媽逼又沒別人
Get the fuck...
你他媽...
Fucking smoke crack with me, bro.
你他媽跟我一起吸可卡因吧  老兄
I'm not fucking doing it.
老子不干
Smoke crack. Smoke some fucking crack with me, bro.
吸吧  跟我一起吸可卡因吧
- One hit. One hit. That's it. - Okay.
-就一口  就這樣  -好
Fucking nut job.
真他媽瘋了
Let's go run, huh?
我們跑步去吧
We gotta get out of here, buddy.
我們不能憋在這兒  老兄
We gotta get out of here. Let's go fucking run.
我們得走了  跑步去吧
Let's run like we're fucking lions and tigers and bears!
像獅子老虎黑熊一樣奔跑吧
Let's run! Let's fucking run!
跑起來  快他媽跑起來
Let's fucking run! Go!
他媽的快跑  快啊
Go, go, go, go!
跑跑跑
You've reached Frank's Best Auto Body.
這里是弗蘭克汽車維修
We're closed right now.
我們現在不營業
So please leave us a message.
請留言
Hello. My name is Jordan Belfort.
你好  我叫喬丹·貝爾福
My partner and I are very interested in renting out your garage.
我和搭檔想租用你的汽修廠
Donnie and I were going out on our own.
我和唐尼辭職單干了
And the first thing we needed was brokers.
首先我們需要的就是經紀人
Guys with sales experience.
有銷售經驗的人
So I recruited some of my hometown boys.
所以我招募了幾個老鄉
Sea Otter, who sold meat and weed.
西·奧特  賣肉和大麻的
Chester, who sold tires and weed.
切斯特  賣輪胎和大麻的
And Robbie, who sold anything he could get his hands on.
還有羅比  能弄到什么就賣什么
Mostly weed.
基本都是大麻
Can you bring me some ketchup? Okay?
能給我拿點番茄醬來嗎
This is Brad.
這是布拉德
And Brad's the guy I really wanted.
我真想要的就是布拉德
But he didn't go along with us.
但他不愿意加入我們
He was already making so much money selling Quaaludes,
他賣安眠酮已經賺飛了
he'd become the Quaalude king of Bayside.
算是貝賽地區的安眠酮小王子
Getting any pussy with that thing or what?
你這玩意兒操上逼了沒
Yeah, man, of course.
當然  伙計
Bring some of them chicks around here sometime, huh?
有空也帶幾個妞兒來我這轉轉
Let 'em watch.
讓她們瞧瞧
Let 'em watch. Know what I mean?
讓她們見識見識  懂我意思嗎
Hey, Zip! You tell your sister I was asking about her.
小老二  代我向你姐姐問好
Why don't you bring me a pair of her panties
下次來我這的時候
next time you come through.
帶條她的內褲吧
Yeah, man. She said she don't want to talk to you anymore, man.
伙計  她說這輩子也不想見你了
Get the fuck out of here.
你他媽滾吧
Hey, Ma, we got chicken or what?
媽  今兒有雞肉沒
Ma!
媽
You listening? It's easier than you think.
聽見沒  比你們想象的還容易
Every person you're on the phone with,
每個接你電話的人
they want to get rich and they want to get rich quickly.
都做著一夜暴富的夢
They all want something for nothing.
都想空手套白狼
There was this one time
我有次
that I was selling pot to this Amish dude.
把口鍋賣給門諾會教徒了
You know those guys who got like the beard
就是那種留著鬢須
with like no mustache or some bullshit?
但嘴唇上不留胡子的
Well, he says that he only wants to make furniture.
他就說他這輩子只想做家具
- I don't understand. - What's that got to do with anything?
-沒懂你意思  -這和我們說的有什么關系
What the fuck are you talking about?
你他媽扯哪兒去了
I'm not putting words in your mouth or nothing,
不是我逼你說什么
but you just said that everybody wants to get rich.
但你剛說每人都想一夜暴富
Holy fuck, you did just say that.
我操  你剛確實說了
What the fuck are you talking about?
你們他媽扯哪兒去了
Yeah, like Buddhists. They don't give a shit about money.
對啊  佛教徒也是  他們才不在乎錢
They're wrapped in sheets. They're not buying shit.
他們只穿僧袍  也沒什么花銷
I'm not talking about Buddhists or Amish.
我又不是說佛教徒或門諾教徒
I'm talking about normal people, working-class, everyday people.
我是說普通人  工薪階級  平凡群眾
Everyone wants to get rich. Am I crazy?
人人都想賺大錢  我說錯了嗎
There's no such thing as an Amish Buddhist.
那種超凡脫俗的人根本不存在
- I'm pretty fucking sure. - There could be.
-我敢保證  -真的有
Can we get some ketchup, please?
能來點番茄醬嗎  謝謝
Do you guys not want to make money?
難道你們這幫人也不想掙錢嗎
I want to make some money.
我想掙大錢啊
I want to make some fucking money, okay.
我他媽當然想掙錢
I can sell anything.
我什么都能賣
Shit, I can sell ludes to a convent full of nuns,
我都能把安眠酮賣給修道院的修女
and get them so horny they'd be fucking each other.
讓她們淫水泛濫高潮迭起
That's the attitude. You can sell anything?
要的就是這個態度  沒你賣不掉的東西是嗎
Sell me this fucking pen right here.
來把這支筆賣給我
You can sell anything. Sell that. Go ahead.
你不是什么都能賣嗎  試試這個  來
Sell me the pen.
把這支筆賣給我
Can I finish eating first? I haven't eaten today.
等我吃完行嗎  一天沒吃飯了
Brad, show them how it's done. Boom.
布拉德  教教他們該怎么做
Sell me that pen. Watch. Go on.
把這支筆賣給我  都看好了  開始
You want me to sell this fucking pen?
你要我把這破筆賣給你
That's my boy right there. Can fucking sell anything.
這才是我哥們兒  什么都能賣
Why don't you do me a favor.
幫我個忙
Write your name down on that napkin for me.
把你名字寫那張餐巾紙上
I don't have a pen.
可我沒有筆呀
Exactly. Supply and demand, my friend.
賣給你了  這叫供需關系  伙計
- Holy shit. - See what I'm saying?
-簡直了  -我說什么來著
He's creating urgency.
他知道制造需求
Get them to want to buy the stock.
讓他們心甘情愿去買股票
Convince them it's something they need, you know what I mean?
讓他們相信這是不可或缺的  明白嗎
And that's the thing.
關鍵就在這
All nuns are lesbians.
修女全是同性戀
What the fuck are you talking about, Otter?
你他媽又扯到哪兒去了  海獺
Think about it. They can't keep a dude
想想看  在修道院釣不到凱子
so they're gonna start fucking chicks.
只好玩女人嘍
Four fucking times, Kimmie! Four times.
我喊了四遍了  幾米  第四遍了
He's not with us.
他沒跟上我們的思路
Now she runs.
她終于拿來了
But look. I knew these guys weren't like Harvard MBAs.
這幫人是沒念過哈佛工商管理碩士什么的
Robbie Feinberg, the pinhead,
羅比·范伯格  外號笨蛋
took five years to finish high school.
用了5年才高中畢業
Alden Kupferberg, the Sea Otter, didn't even graduate.
奧爾登·古佛博格  外號海獺  高中都沒念完
Chester Ming, the depraved Chinaman,
切斯特·明  外號頹廢華人
thought jujitsu was in Israel.
一直以為柔道是以色列人發明的
Smartest of the bunch was Nicky Koskoff.
當中最聰明的要屬尼基·克斯考夫
He actually went to law school.
他還真上過法學院
I called him Rugrat because of his piece of shit hairpiece.
我叫他魯格拉特因為他那頂傻逼假發
Still, give them to me young, hungry and stupid,
就算來的是一群年輕  饑渴的蠢貨
and in no time, I'll make them rich.
要不了多久我都能讓他們發財
Oh, my God.
我的天
Jordan, that...
喬丹  這
You like it, baby?
喜歡嗎  寶貝
Oh, my God, that's beautiful.
天哪  太漂亮了
They're not the biggest stones in the world,
這不是世界上最大的鉆石
but I promise they're really high quality.
但我保證這都是上等貨
It's beautiful.
很漂亮
They're so beautiful.
真的很漂亮
Oh, boy.
天哪
What?
怎么了
I know that look. What is it? Go ahead.
我見過你這副表情  怎么了  說吧
I don't know, it's... You know...
不知道  就是
These stocks... These companies...
這些股票  這些公司
They're like crappy companies.
都是一些不入流的公司啊
- Well, yeah. - Okay.
-沒錯  -是吧
Yeah, they're terrible.
沒錯  它們都糟透了
Don't worry about it. I told you,
別擔心  不是告訴過你嗎
what I'm doing is completely legal.
我做的都是合法生意
Yeah, I know.
我知道
But they're not gonna make anyone money though, right?
但那些投資人其實掙不到錢  對嗎
Well, sometimes they do, sometimes they don't.
時有時無吧
You know how it goes.
投資本來就是這樣的
Wouldn't you feel better if you sold that stuff to rich people
那把這種股票賣給
who can, like, afford to lose all that money?
不在乎這點小錢的富人不會更好嗎
Of course.
當然
But rich people don't buy penny stocks.
但有錢人是不會買仙股的
They just don't.
事實就這樣
Why not?
為什么
Because they're too smart, that's why not.
因為他們都混成精了
I mean, what person with a college education
只要是讀過大學的人
would trust this bunch of jerk-offs?
有誰會相信這群混混呢
Hang up the phone. Tell him you'll call him back.
把電話掛了  說一會打回去
I got five fucking grand on the phone right now!
我他媽這正談著5000塊的生意呢
But what if they didn't sound like a bunch of jerk-offs?
不過要是他們聽起來不像混混呢
What if I could teach them how to sell to people with money?
如果我教會他們怎么向有錢人推銷呢
Real money.
真正的有錢人
So I decided to reinvent the company.
所以我決定重新打造整個公司
Gentlemen, welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
先生們  歡迎來到斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
You schnooks will now be targeting the wealthiest 1% of Americans.
你們現在的目標是拿下美國那1%的首富
We're talking about whales here.
要撈就要撈大魚
Moby fucking Dicks.
就他媽《白鯨記》里那種
And with this script, which is now your new harpoon,
這份推銷詞  就是你們的魚叉
I'm gonna teach each and every one of you
我將教會你們每一個人
to be Captain fucking Ahab.
如何成為他媽的亞哈船長
Get it? Huh?
懂了嗎
Captain who?
什么船長
Captain Ahab. From the fucking...
亞哈船長  就他媽的是
The book, motherfucker. From the book.
那本書里來的  你這蠢貨  書里的
Turn your fucking brain on.
動動你的腦子
- Fuck you. - Jesus fuck, Robbie.
-去你媽的  -我操  羅比
Listen to me. We're a new company with a new name.
聽我說  我們這家新公司有說法的
A company that our clients can believe in.
一家讓客戶放心的公司
A company that our clients can trust.
一家讓客戶信任的公司
A firm whose roots are so deeply embedded into Wall Street
一家在華爾街根基深厚的公司
that our very founders sailed over on the Mayflower
當年的創始人乘著五月花號破浪而來
and chiseled the name Stratton Oakmont
將斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特這個名字
right into Plymouth fucking Rock!
鐫刻在普里茅斯的堅巖上
You got it?
明白了嗎
What we're gonna do is this.
我們的具體計劃是
First we pitch 'em Disney, ATT, IBM,
我們先推銷像迪斯尼  ATT  IBM
blue chip stocks exclusively.
這種藍籌熱門股
Companies these people know.
他們熟知的這種大公司
Once we've suckered them in, we unload the dog shit.
等他們放松警惕  我們就開始賣狗屎
The pink sheets, the penny stocks, where we make the money.
粉單和仙股才是我們的聚寶盆
50% commission, baby.
我們從中抽五成呢  乖乖
Now the key to making money in a situation like this
用這種策略盈利的關鍵在于
is to position yourself now before the settlement.
一定要先下手為強
Because by the time you read about it in The Wall Street Journal,
等《華爾街日報》都報道了再行動
it's already too late.
就為時已晚了
Then you wait.
然后你要做的就是等待
You wait.
耐心等待
And whoever speaks first loses.
誰先開口誰傻逼
Sorry...
抱歉
I appreciate the call.
感謝您來電告知我
I really have to give this some thought
我得考慮考慮
and talk to my wife about it.
再和我太太商量一下
Can I call you back?
我想好了再給您答復可以嗎
They don't know, right? They gotta think about it,
他們在猶豫  對吧  他們得考慮考慮
they gotta talk to their fucking wives,
得他媽問老婆
or the fucking Tooth Fairy.
或者去問他媽的牙仙什么的
Point is, it doesn't matter what the fuck they say.
但那些都不是關鍵
The only real objection that they have
唯一讓他們不敢砸錢的原因就是
is that they don't trust you guys.
他們并不相信你們這幫人
And why should they trust you? I mean, look at you.
他們憑什么相信你們  看看你們自己
You're a bunch of fucking sleazy salesmen, right?
就一幫沒文化的推銷員  對吧
So, what do you say?
那你們該怎么辦呢
You mean to tell me that if I put you in at Union Carbide at seven
要是我能讓你7美元買進聯合碳化物
and took you out at 32.
再32美元賣出
Texas Instruments at 11 and took you out at 47.
11美元買入德州儀器  47美元賣出
U.S. Steel at 16, took you out at 41.
16美元買入美國鋼鐵公司  41美元賣出
You wouldn't be saying to me right now,
你現在肯定跟我說
"Chester, pick me up a few thousand shares of Disney!"
切斯特  快幫我給迪斯尼投幾千股吧
"On the spot, right now. Come on."
立刻  現在  趕快買
Honestly, Kevin? Honestly? Seriously?
說真的  凱文  說真的  不是嗎
I don't know you.
我都不認識你
You cold-called me. You're a total stranger.
你我陌不相識  你就給我電話陌生拜訪
I am in complete agreement with you.
我表示完全同意
You don't know me, I don't know you.
我們互不相識
Let me introduce myself to you. My name is Alden Kupferberg.
請允許我做個自我介紹  我叫奧爾登·古佛博格
- Robbie Feinberg. - Chester Ming.
-我叫羅比·范伯格  -我叫切斯特·明
I'm Senior Vice President at Stratton Oakmont,
我現在是斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的高級副總裁
and I plan on being one of the...
我計劃在明年內成為
top brokers in my firm next year.
我公司頂尖的股票經紀人之一
And I'm not gonna get there by being wrong, Stanley.
我要邁錯一步可就沒戲了  斯坦利
I do wanna say that you sound like a...
我不得不說  你聽起來像是個
You sound like a pretty sincere guy.
你像是個實誠人
It's not gonna make you rich and it's not gonna make you poor.
這投資不會讓你一夜暴富或赤貧
But what this trade will do is serve as...
但這次交易絕對會成為
a benchmark for future business, Kevin.
未來交易的標桿  凱文
You feel comfortable with me now, Scotty?
現在說話舒服多了吧  斯科蒂
And then you'll know for sure
然后你就能確信了
that you finally found a broker on Wall Street
自己終于在華爾街找了個能信賴的
that you can trust,
股票經紀人
and who can consistently make you money.
而且還能保證你穩賺不賠
Sound fair enough?
聽起來不錯吧
You know what... Yeah.
我猜  是吧
I gotta say, I'm pretty impressed.
你的確讓我印象深刻
What are you thinking?
你具體怎么打算的
Kevin.
凱文
You give me one shot here
給我一個機會
on a blue chip stock like Kodak,
幫你投個柯達這樣的藍籌股
and believe me, Kevin,
相信我  凱文
the only problem you're gonna have
之后你唯一會頭疼的問題
is that you didn't buy more.
就是后悔當初沒多買點
Sound fair enough?
聽起來不錯吧
Shit. My...
該死  我
My wife might divorce me, but...
我老婆沒準會踹了我  不過
Yeah, let's do it.
成  來吧
Excellent choice, Kevin.
明智的選擇  凱文
How much do you want to go for this time?
這次你打算投多少錢
Let's do five... $5,000.
那就5...5000美元吧
Can we try 8,000, Kevin?
多投點  8000怎么樣  凱文
All right. Let's do 10.
好吧  干脆投一萬塊
- Ten. - You want to do that?
-一萬美元  -你覺得可行嗎
Excellent choice!
不能再明智了
Kevin, let me lock in that trade right now,
凱文  我先去下單
and get back to you in a few minutes
幾分鐘之后再給你回電
with an exact confirmation, Kevin.
進行確認  凱文
And welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
歡迎加入斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特
Thanks, man. I'm gonna have a beer.
謝了  伙計  我得去喝一杯
This is fun.
這還挺有趣的
Take it easy, Kev.
放輕松  凱文
Hey, thanks, Jordan. Thanks a...
謝了  喬丹  十分...
Fuck that motherfucker!
滾他媽的蛋吧
That's what I'm talking about!
這還差不多
What a fucking idiot.
真他媽是個傻逼
The one thing I know about in this world is airlines.
這世上我唯一了如指掌的就是航空行業了
And Cuchon Airlines is the future of airlines.
酷尚航空絕對是航空領域的未來之星
Get in now or...
趕緊下手  不然...
- I'm Nicky Koskoff. - Chester Ming.
-我叫尼基·克斯考夫  -我叫切斯特·明
and I'm a Senior Vice President with Stratton Oakmont.
我是斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的高級副總裁
Judy, I am so, so, so sorry for your loss.
朱迪  這真是太不幸了
When did he pass?
他什么時候去世的
Just say I'm wrong, right.
就算我預計錯了  好吧
And the stock goes down a couple points...
股票跌幾個點
And it makes you, in the words of my grandfather,
用我我祖父的話說  愿他的靈魂安息
God rest his soul, "A shit ton of money."
這絕對能讓你賺上一坨錢
It's like getting in on fucking sunlight
這就像還沒太陽的時候
before there was fucking sunlight. You understand?
就投資給陽光  懂嗎
Can we do 8,000 shares?
買8000股怎么樣
Okay, 25,000.
好的  兩萬五千股
That's a very intelligent decision.
您的決定太明智了
I'm gonna transfer you to my sales associate.
我將把電話轉接給我的銷售助理
Rhonda!
朗達
- Rhonda! - I'm gonna put you through to Andrea.
-朗達  -我現在把電話轉給安德烈
Has anybody fucking seen Rhonda?
媽的有人看到朗達了嗎
Everybody have a good week?
大家這周都過得不錯吧
Yeah!
好
The end of the month.
月末結算
$28.7 million in gross commissions,
公司傭金凈盈利2870萬美元
all from pink sheet stock, boys!
全是粉單市場賺來的  伙計們
And to celebrate with our weekly act of debauchery,
為了給本周的縱情聲色助興
I have offered our lovely sales assistant,
我愿給我們可愛的銷售助理
Danielle Harrison, here,
丹尼爾·哈里森小姐
$10,000 to shave her fucking head!
一萬美元  給她剃個禿瓢
Yeah, you want this?
你們想看嗎
Let's scalp her! Scalp her!
剃光頭  剃光頭
Let the scalping begin!
開始狂歡吧
Scalp! Scalp! Scalp!
光頭  光頭  光頭
FYI, boys, Danielle has promised to
還有  各位  丹尼爾已經答應
use this $10,000 for breast implants!
會用這一萬美元去隆胸了
She's already got C cups, but now she wants fucking double D's!
她現在是C罩杯  不過就快變他媽D杯了
Is this a great fucking company or what?
還他媽有哪兒比我們公司更棒
Is this the greatest company in the world?
是不是世上最棒的公司
Donnie!
唐尼
Blow the roof off this motherfucker!
今天要他媽爽爆這個鬼地方
Champagne?
還有香檳
Send in the stripees!
派姑娘們進來
Mine!
我的
Word about us spread throughout Wall Street.
整條華爾街都充斥著有關我們的傳聞
Even the places I didn't want it to.
甚至傳到了我不愿傳到的地方
It wasn't long before Forbes magazine,
沒過多久華爾街報社中的佼佼者
the flagship of Wall Street, called to do a profile on me.
《福布斯》雜志社邀請我做個人專訪了
Let me ask you, how do you see the future for Stratton Oakmont?
請問你認為斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的未來會怎樣
One word?
一個詞形容嗎
Diversification.
多樣化經營
Sounds good. Thank you so much. I have more than enough.
挺好  十分感謝  我已經收獲頗豐
- I appreciate your time. - Fantastic.
-感謝您百忙中抽出時間  -很好
Can we get a quick picture?
能給我們拍張照嗎
A total fucking hatchet job.
簡直就他媽是惡意詆毀
This conniving little twat! Look at this!
這幫陰險的小雜種  讀讀這個
"The Wolf of Wall Street" They call me. Look.
他們稱我為"華爾街之狼"
Your hair looks good.
你發型不錯
"Jordan Belfort, sounding like a kind of twisted Robin Hood"
喬丹·貝爾福就像個變態羅賓漢一樣
"who takes from the rich and gives to himself,"
從富人處搶錢然后和一幫
"and his merry little band of brokers."
經紀人狐朋狗友分贓
- Read that. Read it. - Listen.
-讀讀  讀讀  -聽著
There is no such thing as bad publicity, sweetheart.
所有媒體炒作都是好事  親愛的
Read the article, babe.
你讀下這篇  寶貝
Jordan, you look great! You're in a huge magazine.
喬丹  你看著棒極了  你上了大雜志
Big fucking deal I look great.
看著棒極了管屁用
Mr. Belfort! Can you look at my resume, please?
貝爾福  請看看我的簡歷
Excuse me, excuse me, sir!
抱歉  抱歉  先生
Calm the fuck down!
都他媽消停點兒
What the hell's all this?
這他媽怎么回事
It's the Forbes article.
都怪《福布斯》那篇報道
They all want to work for you now.
現在他們都想為你工作了
Hey! What did I say?
我怎么跟你說的
I'm just trying to be nice.
我只是想禮貌點
Hey, you want a job, you talk to me!
想工作  先找我
- Mr. Belfort! - Give me one minute.
-貝爾福先生  -給我一分鐘就好
Forbes made me a superstar.
《福布斯》把我炒成了超級巨星
Every day, dozens of money-crazed kids
每天有無數做著發財夢的年輕人
beat a path to my door.
踏破門檻來找我
If we hired 'em, they dropped straight out of college overnight
一旦應聘成功  他們立馬就從大學退學
and spent whatever allowance they had
從生活費里硬摳出一筆錢
on a new suit from our Stratton tailor.
買一套斯特拉頓定制裁縫的西裝
Are you fucking serious right now?
你們他媽是逗我玩嗎
I mean, we were literally putting clothes on these kids' backs.
喬丹·貝爾福不再賣肉 改銷高風險股票
And here comes this jerk-off sniffing around.
然后就被這個混蛋給盯上了
But, you know, every time someone rises up in this world,
不過這世上每次有人蒸蒸日上時
there's always gonna be some asshole trying to drag him down.
總會有些傻逼想把他們拉下馬
Within months, we doubled in size,
數月內  我們的規模就翻了番
moved to even bigger offices.
遷進了更大的辦公室
It was a madhouse.
公司整個就是一瘋人院
A greed-fest,
各種貪欲的狂歡
with equal parts cocaine, testosterone, and body fluids.
被可卡因  睪丸酮和體液均分
It got so bad, I had to declare the office a fuck-free zone
鬧得越來越嚴重以至于我得規定
between the hours of 9:00 and 7:00.
早9點到晚7點不準在辦公室操逼
But I'm telling you, even that didn't help.
但我告訴你  這都沒用
Actually, the madness started on our very first day,
其實我們進駐頭一天就這么瘋了
when one of our brokers, Ben Jenner,
我們的一個經紀人  本·詹納
christened the elevator by getting a blowjob
讓一個銷售助理給他口交
from a sales assistant.
給電梯破了處
Her name was Pam, and to her credit,
她叫帕姆  我得承認
she did have this amazing technique,
她的確技術超群
with this wild twist and jerk motion.
會那種瘋狂地套弄
About a month later,
過了差不多一個月
Donnie and I decided to double-team her
唐尼和我決定趁周六下午
on a Saturday afternoon while our wives were out
我倆妻子去買圣誕禮服時
shopping for Christmas dresses.
和她來個二夾一
Eventually, Ben married her,
后來本娶了她
which was pretty amazing
我們都覺得挺神奇的
considering she blew every single guy in the office.
因為她給辦公室所有男的都吹過簫
Then he got depressed and killed himself three years later.
本后來因為抑郁3年后自殺了
Anyway, I hired my dad, Max, to maintain order as the Enforcer.
我雇了我爸麥克斯做執行官來維持秩序
Stratton's very own Gestapo.
斯特拉頓自己的蓋世太保
We called him Mad Max because of his hair-trigger temper,
我們叫他瘋狂麥克斯因為他的急脾氣
which could be set off by
簡直一觸即發
something as innocuous as a ringing telephone.
連電話鈴這點小事都能惹到他
Who the fuck has the goddamn gall
誰這么厚顏無恥
to call this house on a Tuesday night?
周二晚上給我家打電話
God damn it!
真該死
You're gonna miss it!
你要錯過片頭了
Please, tell me something I don't know.
拜托說點新鮮的
I wait all week for the fucking Equalizer
我等一星期就為了看《均衡》
and they have to fucking... Hello.
他們就非得這時候... 你好
But as soon as he picked up the phone...
但一接起電話
Gene. How are you, Gene?
吉尼  最近怎么樣  吉尼
... he'd affect this weird British accent.
他就開始用很奇怪的英國腔說話
Right-o, Gene, that'd be great.
好的  吉尼  那太好了
Cheerio.
回見
It was absolutely bizarre.
特別的奇怪
The fucking halfwit!
這該死的白癡
- He'd hang up... - You missed it!
-等他掛了電話  -你錯過片頭了
... and then he's Mad Max all over again.
就又變回瘋狂麥克斯了
Damn it!
該死
All right, tell me what happened. What happened?
告訴我剛講什么了  怎么了
Well, he discovered it was the mother's sister.
他發現是他姑姑
Who's he? Who? Tell me who...
他是誰  告訴我是誰
The main guy. You know who the main...
主角啊  你知道主角...
The main guy...
主角
It was his mother's sister. She showed up dead.
是他姑姑  他發現她死了
Of course, Mad Max didn't have to know
當然我們在斯特拉做的事情
everything we were doing at Stratton.
不用都讓瘋狂麥克斯知道
And then there's a big target and we...
弄一個大的靶子  我們...
They get launched at the target. They stick.
把他們扔向靶子  然后就粘上了
There's a bull's-eye and the bull's-eye's a dollar sign.
靶心里畫個美元符號
Whoever gets closer to the dollar sign
扔得離靶心最近的
gets the most points.
得分最高
I'm gonna throw the shit out of this little fucking thing.
等著我把那小崩豆扔傻了
So if it gets hurt, what happens?
要是他受傷了怎么辦
'Cause we're gonna get fucking nuts.
到時我們肯定很瘋狂
I don't think he's gonna get hurt. They're like...
我覺得我們傷不到他們  他們可...
They got like superhuman strength.
他們都結實得跟超人一樣
I think he's gonna be fine.
我覺得他不會有事的
You can't look him right in the eyes.
你別瞪著他眼睛看就行
You can't look him in the eye?
別瞪著他眼睛看
That's a fact. I saw it on PBS.
認真的  我看PBS臺說的
They get confused and their wires get crossed.
他們會被你看毛然后發瘋的
You gotta look at their chin.
你得看著他們的下巴
Like it looks like I'm looking at you
看著像是我在看你
but I'm looking at your chin.
但其實我在看你下巴
I feel like you're addressing me right now,
我感覺你在跟我說話
but you're not, are you?
但你沒在跟我說話吧
They're like the Mona Lisa. They find eye contact,
他們就像蒙娜麗莎一樣  不管你站哪里
like, wherever you are standing in the room.
他們都能直視你
And they lock in.
然后就鎖定了
No, but there is a limit to what we can do with them?
但我們還是有個限度的對吧
We're allowed to throw shit at 'em.
可以向他們身上扔東西
We're allowed to throw food? Bananas.
我們可以扔吃的嗎  香蕉
Any food. Correct.
隨便什么吃的  沒錯
But, for example, what I wouldn't do is
但舉個例子  我就不大會
maybe like tell him to pull his cock out
讓他把雞巴掏出來
and like get some of the girls to, you know,
然后找幾個妹子
fondle him and shit like that.
玩他什么的
That would be... That's unacceptable?
那也...不能這么干嗎
Let's keep that in our back pocket.
這招我們先留著
This guy is more about throwing at the dartboard.
這人比較適合往靶子上扔
Correct. Yes, yes, yes.
對  對  沒錯
The thing is, this is their gift, okay.
他們就適合干這個使
They're built to be thrown like a lawn dart.
天生就適合被拿來當飛鏢扔
They're top heavy like a lawn dart.
跟飛鏢一樣頭重腳輕
So they're built for accuracy.
就是為了讓你能投準的
Oh, my God. Can we bowl with this guy?
天哪  我們能把他滾著玩么
That's his fucking brother, Rob.
那是他兄弟  羅比
His brother's the bowling ball.
羅比才是保齡球
The brother, you put a skateboard on him,
給他身上綁個滑板
you strap him to a skateboard,
把他綁在滑板上
you toss him down an alley at some pins.
然后順著過道往瓶子上扔
- No shit. That's interesting. - Swear to fucking God.
-這想法不錯  -絕對的
- Can we get that guy? - Yeah, we'll get that guy, too.
-這個我們也要吧  -沒錯我們倆都要
But it says here this guy will show his cock. Yeah.
但這上面說他兄弟同意露陰
- Instead of growing up. Yeah. - He will?
-他倒是不長高  -他同意嗎
They are very ornery by the way,
但他們挺易怒的
so you gotta be very careful with these little guys.
所以跟這些小不點得悠著點
Safety first.
安全第一
Safety is first, all right?
安全第一  好吧
I want somebody with a fucking tranquilizer gun
在旁邊安排一個人拿著麻醉槍
ready to knock this fucker out.
出事兒了就擊暈他
- Do we want to get like a... - Mace. Taser guns.
-我們要不要弄個...-梅斯催淚  高壓槍
A pellet gun maybe?
小氣槍怎么樣
No, a pellet gun is gonna hurt him.
不行  小氣槍會傷到他的
I just want him out. Knocked out cold.
我只想弄暈他  暈死就行
But I say we stick with the loophole. Right? Okay?
要我說我們還是認準法律漏洞
If we don't consider him a human,
要是我們不把他到人看
we just consider it an act, I think we're in the clear.
就單純的行為來講  我們就沒事
Like The Flying Wallendas.
就像飛天瓦倫達馬戲團
You know, a lot of those guys died but they never sued anybody.
死了不少人也沒人告他們
The important thing you guys gotta keep in mind
重要的是你們得記住
is that these things gossip.
他們互相會八卦的
They get together and they gossip.
聚在一起就八卦
- That's a good point. - And the last thing
-這點好  -我們最不希望看到的
that we need is them getting together and saying,
就是他們聚到一起然后說
"Oh, they made fun of us."
他們嘲笑我們了
Like, it's gonna make Stratton look bad.
那會抹黑斯特拉頓的
That's why I love you. You think of shit like that.
我就愛你這點  能想到這些破事
When they come in, we treat it just like one of us. Okay?
等他們來了  就把他們當自己人  好嗎
One of us. Gooble gobble, one of us.
自己人  咕咕咕咕  自己人
We accept them, one of us!
接納他們  自己人
Gooble gobble, one of us.
咕咕咕咕  自己人
Jordan! Your Dad's coming.
喬丹  你爸來了
Something about the American Express bill.
好像是運通卡賬單的事
Can you get him out of here?
你能別讓他來嗎
Yeah. Lick my twat.
能  你舔蛋去吧
No, I'm serious!
沒  我認真的
Fuck. Guys, act like we're working.
該死  各位  假裝我們在工作
You got any fucking stock forms?
你他媽有股票單嗎
He's coming, he's coming.
他來了  他來了
Make some shit up.
隨便編點什么
I think if we short Pfizer...
我覺得要是我們把輝瑞制藥...
$430,000 in one month, Jordy, huh?
一個月43萬嗎  喬丹
Four hundred and fucking
你他媽的一個月
30,000 fucking dollars in one fucking month!
居然他媽的花43萬嗎
Good morning. They're business expenses. Relax.
早上好  那都是商務花費  淡定點
- Business expenses? - Yes.
-商務花費嗎  -是
- Jordy, look what you got here. - What?
-喬丹  你看你這都是什么  -什么
Look at this. $26,000 for one fucking dinner!
看這個  兩萬六美金一頓晚飯
Okay. No, no. This could be explained.
不  這我能解釋
Dad, we had clients. The Pfizer clients.
爸  我們有客戶的  輝瑞制藥的客戶
Right. The porterhouse from Argentina.
沒錯  阿根廷的上等腰肉牛排
Expensive champagne and... We had to buy champagne.
還得買上等的香檳  都很貴的
And you ordered all the fucking sides.
然后你還點了一堆狗屁配菜
- Tell him about the sides. - I ordered sides, so...
-你自己跟他說  -我點了配菜  所以
Sides? $26,000 worth of sides?
還配菜  26萬塊的配菜嗎
What are these sides? They cure cancer?
你這配菜治癌癥的嗎
The sides did cure cancer. That's the problem.
問題是配菜的確治癌癥
That's why they were expensive.
所以才這么貴
- Shut the fuck up. - I'm serious.
-你他媽閉嘴吧  -我認真的
- Stop. - And EJ Entertainment?
-夠了  -還有EJ娛樂
What the fuck is EJ Entertainment?
EJ娛樂是他媽什么東西
Well, that's...
這個是
Yeah, Jordy, what's EJ Entertainment?
是啊  喬丹  EJ娛樂是什么
How do I describe this?
這怎么形容呢
Jord, what is that?
喬丹  是什么
- It's a fucking prostitution ring, Jordy! - I know.
-這他媽是賣淫團伙  喬丹  -我知道
- That's what it is! - That is what it is.
-是賣淫團伙知道嗎  -的確是賣淫團伙
Isn't that the perfect description for it?
你看這么形容合適不
That is what it is. But none of these were charged to me.
的確是這樣  但這都不是我干的
This is all of them.
這都是他們干的
- Oh, that was all us? - It wasn't me though.
-是嗎  都是我們干的  -反正不是我
Fucking explain this shit to him!
快他媽給他解釋清楚
These are all of your fucking charges right here!
這他媽都是你花的錢
The IRS, they allow for T&A. It's fine.
聯邦稅務部允許旅行女樂花費的  沒事
T&E!
旅行娛樂
Yeah. I said T&E.
是  我說的就是
- No, no. You said T&A. - No, I didn't.
-不是  你說的旅行女樂  -我沒說
Yeah, you did.
你說了
- When did I say that? - You said T&A.
-我什么時候說了  -你說的旅行女樂
T&E!
那叫旅行娛樂
I know you're upset about the dinner,
我知道你對那頓飯不滿意
and that makes sense because
你有道理生氣
we did spend too much money.
因為我們的確花太多了
But I said T&E.
但我說的就是旅行娛樂
Don't tell me what you said. I heard what you said.
別跟我說你說了什么  我都聽見了
- Dad. He said T&A. - He did?
-爸  他說的是旅行娛樂  -是嗎
Absolutely, no question.
絕對的  毫無疑問
I'm trying to...
我是要...
I'm getting this close!
我就差一點
- Dad, relax. - I'm getting this close.
-爸  別急  -我就差這么一點
That's what I'm saying. I want you to open up more, Max.
我就是這意思  我想讓你敞開心扉  麥克斯
He's gonna fucking kill you.
你等著他哪天殺了你
Why do you hold it in? Why do you...
你干嘛憋著  你干嘛都憋著
Max, why do you hold it in?
麥克斯  你干嘛非都憋著
That's it. Get the fuck out of here!
夠了  你他媽給我滾出去
- No, no, no! - Asshole, get out of here.
-別  別別  -滾蛋  出去
What kind of hooker takes credit cards?
嫖什么妓女還能刷信用卡
A rich one.
有錢的
At Stratton, there were three kinds of hookers.
斯特拉頓會雇三種妓女
The Blue Chips, top of the line, model material.
藍籌股  頂尖好手  當模特的料子
They cost between $300 and $500
得花300到400美金
and you had to wear a condom unless you gave them a hefty tip,
你要是不想帶套就得多給小費
which, of course, I always did.
當然我每次都給
Then came the NASDAQs, who were pretty, not great.
然后就是納斯達克股  漂亮但活一般
They cost between 200 and 300 bucks.
大概200到300塊錢
Finally, there were the Pink Sheets. Skanks.
最后就是粉單股的渣子了
They cost about 100 or less.
大概不到100塊
If you didn't wear a condom,
要是你不戴套的話
you'd have to get a penicillin shot the next day
第二天就得去打青霉素了
and pray your dick didn't fall off.
還得祈禱自己的老二別爛了
Not that we didn't fuck them, too.
倒不是說這種我們就不干了
Believe me, we did.
相信我  我們都干了
It's that slipped disc thing again.
我又腰椎間盤突出了
I know what it is. You know, too much...
我知道你怎么回事  凈那啥了
...with EJ Entertainment.
就跟EJ娛樂
Pops.
爹
How are things at home?
家里怎么樣
Well, not the best.
不是很好
She just doesn't... You know what I'm saying?
她就是有點...你懂吧
It's like the smell...
好像氣味啊
There's a smell, there's an attraction thing.
有種氣味  吸引力什么的
After a while it kind of fades away a little bit.
過段時間就越來越淡了
Yeah, well. It's supposed to fade away.
本來就該越來越淡的
- Supposed to? - That's marriage. You know...
-本來就  -婚姻就這樣  知道嗎
Your mother and I, we've been married a long, long time.
我和你媽結婚很長時間了
What do you think? We're...
你難道覺得我們倆
We're jumping into bed every two minutes?
每兩分鐘就得上個床嗎
- It doesn't work that way. - I love her to death.
-那可不行  -我很愛她
I want to stay married, Dad, but...
爸  我不想離婚  但是
It's crazy out there.
現在世道太瘋狂了
Some of these girls... You should see them.
有些個姑娘  你真該見識見識
Oh, my God!
老天
They're fucking...
簡直是
The things they're doing now, Pops.
爹  她們現在的活兒
I mean... I mean, it's on a whole other level.
絕對是更新換代了
- Really? - And they're all shaved, too.
-是嗎  -下邊還都剃光了
- Get out of here! - All shaven.
-去你的  -全跟白虎似的
- Are you kidding me? - Yeah.
-你就逗我吧  -沒逗你
- Bald as a china doll. - No bush?
-跟瓷娃娃一樣干凈  -沒毛嗎
- No bush. - Oh, my God!
-沒毛  -老天
All of a sudden, one week,
突然之間  就一周
nobody had anything down there anymore.
所有人下邊就都干凈了
It's a new world.
新世界了
They're bald from the eyebrows down.
從眉毛往下就沒毛了
Nothing. Not a stitch. It's like lasers.
一根毛沒有  想激光除過一樣
Wow. A new world.
真是新世界了
I was born too... too early.
我真是生早了
I've never been a fan of the bush, to be honest.
其實我從來不喜歡陰毛
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的嗎  -是
I don't mind it.
無所謂
Dad.
爸
I don't want you stressing out about any of this.
我不想讓你為這些操心
How can I not get stressed out?
我怎么可能不操心
Look at the knuckleheads you got working for you.
看你都找些什么蠢貨給你工作
I know they're knuckleheads
我知道他們是傻瓜
but I need them to want to live like me, you get it?
但我得讓他們羨慕我的生活  懂嗎
To live like me.
想過得像我一樣
Jordy.
喬丹
One of these days, the chickens are gonna come home to roost.
你這么折騰早晚遭報應
You're looking at me like I'm crazy.
你覺得我瘋了嗎
Crazy? This is obscene.
瘋了  你這叫傷風敗俗
It was obscene.
的確傷風敗俗
In the normal world.
在現實世界中的確如此
But who the fuck wanted to live there?
但誰愿意活在現實中
Go party your fucking cocks off!
一起狂歡到屌炸天吧
We are about to become fucking legends
我們將成為華爾街的
on Wall Street!
傳奇
We got plans up here that's gonna take this company
我們的規劃將帶領公司
into the fucking stratosphere!
一路沖上平流層
Wolfie! Wolfie!
狼仔  狼仔
Fuck Merrill Lynch. Fuck them.
去他媽的梅林銀行  管他呢
Why should they be taking
憑什么總讓他們
all our fucking money all the fucking time?
賺走我們的錢
This way we become the underwriters.
這樣我們就是證券承銷商了
It was our next big move.
我們下一步棋
Finding companies to take public. IPOs.
就是找公司幫他們做首次公開募股
It was the only way these Wall Street pricks
這有這樣  那些華爾街的小崽子們
would ever stop thinking of us as some shitkicker bucket shop.
才能不把我們當做野雞證券交易所
We got Arncliffe International.
我們還有阿克利夫國際
See, we were a little different.
我們做事比較不尋常
We liked to get as fucked up as possible
我們談正事的時候
during our business powwows
喜歡嗑藥并喝得酩酊大醉
in order to stimulate our free-flowing ideas,
這樣才能才思泉涌
which is why we were popping these ludes like they were M&M's.
所以我們吃安眠酮就像吃巧克力豆一樣
Steve Madden.
史蒂夫·麥登
We own the fucking companies...
那家公司歸我們了
We own the companies...
絕對歸我們了
Don't know what a lude is? I'll tell you.
不知道安眠酮是什么  我告訴你
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
等等  等等
Looks like those ludes
貌似安眠酮
are working their magic on Donnie right now.
正在唐尼身上顯神跡呢
The Quaalude,
鎮定安眠酮
or lude, as it is commonly referred to,
一般叫作安眠酮
was first synthesized in 1951 by an Indian doctor,
于1951年由一位印度醫生首次合成
that's dots, not feathers,
是點紅點的印度人  不是印第安人
as a sedative, and was prescribed to
當時被當做鎮定催眠藥開給
stressed-out housewives with sleep disorders.
壓力大的家庭婦女緩解睡眠障礙的
But pretty soon someone figured out
但很快就有人發現
that if you resisted the urge to sleep for just 15 minutes,
服藥后只要忍住15分鐘不睡
you got a pretty kick-ass high from it.
就能爽翻天了
Didn't take long for people to start abusing ludes, of course.
當然沒過多久大家就開始濫用安眠酮了
And in 1982, the U.S. Government Schedule 1'd them.
1982年美國和全世界都把安眠酮
Along with the rest of the world.
列為了一級管控藥物
Which meant there was only a finite amount of these things left.
所以說安眠酮數量有限越吃越少
No shit, you can't even buy 'em anymore.
認真的  買都買不到
You people are all shit out of luck.
你們都慘了
What are you saying? What is it?
你要說什么
Steve Madden.
史蒂夫·麥登
Steve.
史蒂夫
You remember those ads?
你記得那些廣告嗎
Those giant-headed girls with the bug eyes
那些有鼓眼泡的大頭姑娘
wearing those big clunky shoes?
穿著笨重的高跟鞋
My friend from school, Steve Madden.
上學時是我朋友  史蒂夫·麥登
His friend from school, Steve Madden.
上學時是他朋友  史蒂夫·麥登
Steve Madden was the name in women's shoes at the moment.
史蒂夫·麥登是當下炙手可熱的女鞋品牌
And all of Wall Street was begging to take his company public.
整條華爾街的人都想幫他上市
Go ahead, go ahead, what is it?
來啊  你要說什么
Except, guess who grew up with him?
但你猜他跟誰是發小
- Women's shoes. - Women's shoes.
-女鞋  -女鞋
My very own Vice President.
正是我的副主管
Women's shoes!
女鞋
Diamond Donnie Azoff.
鉆石唐尼·亞速
- Steve Madden. - Steve.
-史蒂夫·麥登  -史蒂夫
Steve.
史蒂夫
Hey, JB, JB, JB, JB.
喬·貝  喬·貝
You gotta come check this fucking chick out.
過來瞧瞧這個妞
Look at this. Look.
快看
I would fuck that girl if she was my sister.
她要是我妹我一定要了她
I would let that girl give me fucking AIDS.
她就是有艾滋病我都愿意
You want to see the Wolf handle this?
看看狼哥如何搞定她吧
She's hot.
她好正
Cristy.
克里斯蒂
Jordan, this is my friend Naomi.
喬丹  這是我的朋友內奧米
- Hi. Nice to meet you. - Naomi.
-你好  -內奧米
Naomi, nice to meet you.
內奧米  你好
You got an awesome place here.
你家真棒
I've don't think I've ever been in a house this big before.
這么大的房子我還從來沒見過
- Oh, really? - Yeah.
-是嗎  -是
Beautiful beach out there.
外面有漂亮的沙灘
Blair Hollingsworth.
布萊爾·霍林斯沃思
Hi, Blair. Nice to meet you.
布萊爾  你好
- Your name's Blair, right? - Yeah.
-你叫布萊爾對吧  -是
You like to Jet Ski?
你喜歡摩托艇嗎
I've never done it before.
我沒開過
You've never Jet Ski'd in your life?
你從沒開過摩托艇嗎
No, I've never Jet Ski'd.
是  從沒開過
You've never been on a Jet Ski?
你從沒坐過摩托艇嗎
How many times are you gonna ask her?
你要問她多少次
She's never been on a Jet Ski.
她沒坐過摩托艇
I don't know. Might ask her a couple more times.
不知道  也許再問幾次吧
Okay. Sure.
好吧
Hi. I'm Hildy. Nice to meet you.
我是希爾迪  很高興認識你
Jordan, Teresa needs your help.
喬丹  泰瑞莎讓你去幫忙
Yeah, I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
我待會兒過去
Just tell her I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
跟她說下我待會過去
Why don't you tell your wife that?
你干嘛不自己和你老婆說
I might do that, but I'm having
我想去  但我現在
- a conversation right now. - What am I, your secretary?
-在跟別人說話  -你當我是你秘書嗎
You know what, I think we should get going.
我覺得我們該走了
Wait, wait. Where you guys going?
等等  你們去哪
We gotta go. We got two other parties to go to.
我們必須走了  還要趕兩場派對
- We can stay for a drink. - Yeah, stay for a drink.
-我們可以在這喝一杯  -喝一杯吧
No. We got two other parties we're supposed to get to.
不了  我們還要趕兩場派對
But we can stay for a drink...
但我們可以在這喝一杯
She's
她真是
perfect.
美爆了
- You like champagne? - I do.
-你想喝香檳嗎  -可以
She's perfect.
她美爆了
Donnie, what the fuck are you doing?
唐尼  你他媽在干嘛
You piece of...
你個渣...
You're gonna have to excuse my friend. He gets...
請你不要介意  他有點...
Get the fuck out!
快滾
Jordan, you gotta fuck her, bro. She's so hot!
喬丹  你一定要操她  她太正了
Yeah, Donnie!
加油  唐尼
Let him fucking finish, Hildy.
讓他擼完  希爾迪
That's fucking rude.
這樣太他媽暴力了
Have some fucking manners.
淑女點好嗎
So, Bay Ridge, that's near Staten Island, right?
灣脊區  在史坦頓島附近  對吧
Brooklyn, across the Verrazano Bridge.
在布魯克林  穿過韋拉札諾海峽大橋
Saturday Night Fever territory.
《周末夜狂熱》的地盤
That's right. Guinea Gulch.
沒錯  幾內亞峽谷
We call the Verrazano Bridge the Guinea Gangplank.
我們把韋拉札諾海峽大橋叫做幾內亞跳板
Right.
是
So I presume you're Italian?
我猜你是意大利人吧
On my dad's side.
我爸爸是
I'm also Dutch, German, English.
我還有荷蘭  德國  英格蘭血統
I'm a mutt.
我是混血兒
Yeah. You're a mutt.
混血
Yeah, I still have family over there though, in London.
我在倫敦還有親戚
My Aunt Emma. She's the best.
艾瑪姑姑  她最好了
Very British, you know. She's a classy lady.
有種英國范兒  特別優雅
That explains it then.
這就說的通了
Explains what?
說通什么
It explains you. I mean, you're a duchess, right?
你啊  你是女公爵對吧
The Duchess of Bay Ridge.
灣脊區的女公爵
Excuse me.
不好意思
Could I get a straw, please?
請給我一根吸管
Thank you.
謝謝
So I was a little surprised you asked Cristy for my number.
真沒想到你會向克里斯蒂要我的電話
Why is that?
為什么驚訝
Aren't you married?
你是有家室的人了吧
Well... Yeah, but what?
是  所以呢
Married people can't have friends?
有家室就不能有朋友啦
We're gonna be friends?
我們要當朋友啊?
Yeah. You don't want to be my friend?
當然  你不想跟我做朋友嗎
We're not gonna be friends.
我們可不會是單純朋友
And at night I work on my designs.
晚上我會做一些服裝設計
I have an entire line of lingerie.
各種女性內衣
You know, camisoles, bustiers, panties.
女用背心  束身胸衣  三角褲
She designs women's panties, too?
她居然還設計三角褲
Oh, my God!
天哪
Come on, Jordan, think of a way to get up to her apartment.
喬丹  快想個上去的借口
You wanna come up for some tea or something?
你想上去喝點茶什么的嗎
Tea? Yeah.
茶?  好啊
- Like hot tea? - Yeah.
-熱茶嗎  -是
Oh, yeah. That sounds nice. Yeah.
行啊  聽上去不錯
Tea. Fuck, yeah, I wanted to come up for tea.
茶  我太他媽想上去喝茶了
Like Darjeeling or rose hip, something nice like that?
有大吉嶺茶或洛神花茶之類的嗎
Sure.
有
This is Rocky.
這是洛基
Oh, who's this? Say hi, Rocky.
看看這是誰  問聲好  洛基
Hi, sweetheart.
你好  小家伙
Okay.
特別好
Why don't you light a fire or something and I'll be right out.
你能點一下火嗎  我馬上就出來
- Yeah. Fire, here? - Sure.
-火  在這嗎  -是
I like your painting here. It's...
畫挺好看的
God, help me. How do I fuck this girl?
神啊幫幫我  我怎么才能上這姑娘
You all right?
你沒事吧
Yeah, yeah. Just trying to light the fire here.
沒事  只是在點火
That's it. That's it, you're leaving.
打住  打住  你該走了
Don't get involved. Go home to your wife.
別亂來  回家找老婆去
As you can probably guess,
你也想的到
I fucked her goddamn brains out...
我把她操翻天了...
Jesus Lord!
天啊
For 11 seconds.
總共11秒
Did you just come?
你剛剛射了嗎
Oh, yeah, I just came.
是啊  我射了
Did you? Did you come?
你呢  你高潮了嗎
- No. - No?
-沒  -沒有嗎
Okay.
好吧
I'm still hard so just give me a sec.
我還硬著  給我點時間
Sure.
好
Come on, baby, come on.
快起來  寶貝  快起來
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
來了  來了
Oh, God!
天啊
Fuck off, Rocky! Bad dog.
滾開  洛基  壞小狗
You have a biscuit or something like that?
你有餅干之類的東西嗎
It's okay.
別管它
- Just keep going. - Rocky, go play.
-繼續  -洛基  一邊玩去
Go play, Rocky. Go, go, go, go.
邊兒去  洛基  走開  走開
You're crazy.
你真是瘋了
I couldn't get enough.
我無法自拔
I mean, her pussy was like heroin to me.
她的陰道就像海洛因
And it wasn't just about the sex, either.
其實也不只是因為性
Naomi and I got along. I mean, we...
內奧米和我特別合拍  我們
We had similar interests and shit.
我們有相同的興趣
Choo-choo train.
小火車
I think I can. I think I can. I think I can. I think I can.
我可以  我可以  我可以  我可以
Yeah, yeah. Let's toke it all on there, huh?
全放在這吸如何
Oh, shit!
爽
You!
你
Get out of the fucking car!
從車里滾出來
Jesus Christ.
天啊
Son of a bitch! Oh, fuck!
死混蛋  操
Relax, sweetheart. Relax.
冷靜  親愛的  冷靜
- Son of a fucking bitch! - Okay, okay... Geez!
-死混蛋  -好了  好了  天啊
Okay, babe, stop!
寶貝  住手
Please.
求你了
Bitch!
混蛋
- What are you doing... - That whore from the party?
-你干嘛呀  -派對上的那個婊子嗎
Jesus Christ!
天啊
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你他媽怎么了
I thought you were at the fucking beach!
我以為你在他媽的海灘
I didn't know you were here!
我不知道你在這
That's where you've fucking been?
你一直都在忙這個嗎
With that fucking whore from the party?
忙那個派對婊子
I thought you were at the beach house.
我以為你在海濱別墅
How could you do this to me?
你怎么可以這樣對我
Sweetie, come on...
親愛的  別這樣
Who the fuck are you, Jordan?
你成什么樣了  喬丹
You're like a completely different fucking person!
完全變了一個人
I made a mistake. I don't know what to tell you,
我錯了  我不知道該怎么跟你說
babe. I...
寶貝  我
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
- I'm sorry. - Is that who... is that what you want?
-對不起  -你就喜歡她那樣的嗎
Do you love her?
你愛她嗎
Answer me.
回答我
I felt horrible.
我很愧疚
Three days later, I filed for a divorce
3天后我簽了離婚協議
and moved Naomi into the apartment.
并且讓內奧米搬進了公寓
Say what you will, but the Duchess did have style.
隨你怎么說  但女公爵確實有她的一套
She brought in a decorator, feng shui'd the whole place.
她帶了一個裝璜師  看了看房子的風水
She even hired a gay butler.
她還雇了個男同管家
This guy was smart, sophisticated, professional.
聰明  老練  職業
Really, really great.
非常非常棒
Is that jasmine?
是茉莉花嗎
Yes, sir. I tried to stump you this evening. Very good.
是  我還以為能難住你  你太厲害了
Very good. Great nose.
太厲害了  您鼻子很好
Except for that one time.
除了有一次
Oh, my God!
天啊
Oh, hey.
你好
Is it wednesday already?
已經周三了嗎
Oh, don't stop.
別停
What the fuck!
真的假的啊
That is fucked up!
這下完蛋了
He must have thought we were still
他一定以為我們
at the Hamptons this weekend, you know.
這周還要呆在漢普頓斯
Where were they doing it, sweetheart? In the bedroom?
他們在哪兒做的  親愛的  臥室里嗎
They were everywhere.
他們在哪里都做了
There were two guys over there on the table.
有兩個在那邊桌子上
There were more over here.
這邊還有更多
There were four right here.
有四個就在這里做的
Are you fucking serious? Right there?
你他媽不是逗我吧  就在這里嗎
Why didn't you tell me? Sweet.
你怎么不早說  寶貝
Oh, baby, it gets worse.
寶貝  這還不是最糟的
After they left, I checked the apartment.
他們走了以后  我檢查了下屋子
Right. What?
然后呢
What is it, babe? What?
什么問題  寶貝
Where's my money?
我的錢在哪
I don't know where your money...
我不知道您的錢在哪
Where is my fucking money? Where is it?
我的錢他媽的在哪  在哪
I don't know where your money is, Mr. Belfort.
我不知道錢在哪  貝爾福先生
- I didn't do anything. - If you don't get...
-我什么都沒做  -如果你不說
He's lying through his fucking teeth.
他說的全他媽是假話
Let's start from the beginning.
我們從頭開始
Let's start from the beginning, all right?
我們從頭開始好吧
You invited some friends over, right?
你叫了一些朋友來對吧
One thing led to another. Things got out of hand.
莫名其妙的局勢就失控了
We understand that, we do.
這我們可以理解
We do blow all the time. We're fucking degenerates ourselves.
我們也經常犯渾  生活墮落得一塌糊涂
Look at us, right?
瞧瞧我們
But money was stolen from my apartment.
但有人從我的公寓里偷了錢
Right from my sock drawer. All right?
就從我放襪子的抽屜里
Like I said, I don't know where your money is.
我說過了  我不知道您的錢在哪
Just start from the beginning. Who came over?
我們從頭開始  都有誰來
It was just a normal day.
那天和平時一樣
I knew you were coming home the next day.
我知道你們下一天才回來
So everything would be fine. It'd be cleaned up.
所以不會有問題  我都會清理干凈
I got a little high at breakfast.
早餐時我磕了點藥
So I got a little happy. I had some eggs,
所以我有點小興奮  我吃了些雞蛋
I had a little bit of ice cream.
還吃了點冰淇淋
And then I said, "Who do I know that likes ice cream?"
然后我想  我有哪個朋友喜歡冰淇淋
It's my friend, Rudy. So I called Rudy.
魯迪喜歡  所以我叫了魯迪
- Who's Rudy? - Yeah, who's Rudy?
-誰是魯迪  -誰是魯迪
- You know who Rudy is. Come on. - Me? I don't...
-你知道誰是魯迪  -我  我不
- You know... - Who the fuck is Rudy?
-你認識  -魯迪他媽的是誰
I don't know anyone named Rudy.
我不認識叫魯迪的
Last month. The Lollipop Club.
上個月  在棒棒糖俱樂部
You know who Rudy was. Dancing...
你認識魯迪的  他就在那兒跳舞
You know who Rudy is?
你認識魯迪嗎
I don't fucking know any...
我他媽根本不認識什么
What do you mean?
你想說什么
So he went to The Lollipop Club?
他去了棒棒糖俱樂部嗎
Oh, he was at The Lollipop Club for sure.
沒錯  他就在棒棒糖俱樂部
On the stage, grinding with everybody.
在臺上  和其他人一起跳
I got fucked up. I like to dance.
我喝多了  我喜歡跳舞
I don't know. Maybe I met him, maybe I didn't.
我不知道  也許我見過他  也許沒有
I meet a lot of fucking people.
我他媽的見過很多人
- What are you saying? - $50,000 was stolen
-你說什么  -有他媽五萬美金
from my fucking sock drawer!
從我抽屜里被偷走了
All my girlfriend's jewelry is gone.
我女朋友所有的首飾都沒了
- Where the fuck is it? - Rudy. What the fuck?
-東西他媽在哪  -魯迪  什么玩意
Did your fucking little faggot friend Rudy take my shit?
是不是你的基友魯迪拿了我的東西
Did he? Answer me!
是不是他  回答我
Okay. Now I get it. Now I get why I'm...
我知道了  現在我知道為什么了
This is a gay thing.
就因為我是同性戀
See, all of you...
你們都
You think this is 'cause you're a fag?
你覺得我們找你是因為你是基佬
My cousin's a fucking faggot.
我表弟也他媽的是基佬
And I go on vacation with him and his boyfriend.
我還跟他和他男友一起去度假呢
I love fags.
我喜歡基佬
You were in charge, right?
這件事責任在你  知道不
I will not be stolen from. You get that?
沒人能偷我的東西  懂嗎
I fucking like gay people. I don't like you.
我喜歡同性戀  但我不喜歡你
He should've hired a fucking
他應該雇一個他媽的
Mexican like I have in my fucking house.
墨西哥人  像我家一樣
Shit! What the fuck...
操  我操
Talk, you fuck, talk!
說話  混蛋  說話啊
I'm gonna drop you, you faggot!
我要把你扔下去  你個死基佬
Where is it?
錢在哪
Chester and Toby, they went all yakuza on Nicholas.
切斯特和托比對尼古拉斯有些殘暴
You know, they got crazy.
他們玩嗨了
I don't know!
我不知道
I had to call the cops
我不得不叫警察來
just to keep them from killing the poor guy.
以免他們把那個可憐的家伙殺了
I gave them each 1,000
我給了他們每人1000塊
bucks and told them what Nicholas had done.
告訴他們尼古拉斯做的好事
Then they kicked his ass.
結果他們也狠揍了他一頓
Thanks again, Officer.
謝謝  警官
It's not like I cared about the 50 grand anyway.
其實我不怎么在乎那五萬
I was making that much almost every day
我幾乎每天都能掙那么多
through one rathole or another.
從隨便哪個老鼠倉里
Now a rathole is a friend, like Brad here,
老鼠倉就是朋友開的戶  比如布拉德
who held stock in his name for me.
他以他的名義幫我持有股票
Who are you supposed to be, huh? Jack Nickle-Jew?
你是誰  猶太人版杰克·尼克勞斯嗎
I'd drive the price up then
我把價格抬上去后
he'd sell and kick most of the profits back to...
他把股票賣掉  然后把大部分利潤還給
You guessed it, me.
沒錯  給我
All cash. None of it's on the books.
都是現金  都不在賬上
A big no-no, of course, in the eyes of the law.
當然是違法的
Enter our new securities attorney, Manny Riskin.
我們有了新的證券律師  曼尼·瑞絲金
700 bucks an hour to be the voice of doom.
我們付他每小時700元聽他的恐嚇
Listen to me. You piss up the SEC's leg,
聽著  你要是招惹了證監會
you end up with your tits in a wringer.
一定會吃不了兜著走
Do not worry about it. I have the SEC under control.
不過別擔心  證監會的我已經打點好了
What the fuck are these imbeciles doing?
這些傻逼們在干嘛
What are you doing? Hey!
你們在搞什么玩意兒
We got the SEC in here.
證監會的人來了
The Securities and Exchange Commission
證券交易委員會
sent two lawyers down to review our files.
派了兩名律師來查我們的文件
So I set them up in our conference room
我把他們安排在了會議室
and I had it bugged
放了竊聽器
and the air conditioning turned up so high
把空調開到最猛
that it felt like Antarctica in there.
讓里面冷得像南極一樣
Is it always this cold in here?
這一直都這么冷嗎
I don't know.
不知道
Then, while they were looking
當他們在那里
for a smoking gun in that room...
尋找我的罪證時
Arncliffe International is on fire.
阿克利夫國際現在很火
I was gonna fire off a bazooka in here,
我正在這里大張旗鼓
offering up our latest IPO.
為我們的最近的IPO做準備
An IPO is an initial public offering.
IPO的意思是首次公開募股
It's the first time a stock
是指一家企業首次
is offered for sale to the general population.
將股票向公眾出售
Now, as the firm taking the company public,
作為負責上市的機構
we set the initial sales price
我們來制定發行價
then sold those shares right back to our friends. The...
再把股票賣回給我們的朋友  那些
Look.
好吧
I know you're not following what I'm saying anyway, right?
我知道你壓根不懂我在說什么
That's okay. That doesn't matter.
沒關系  無所謂
The real question is this.
關鍵在于
"Was all this legal?"
這合法嗎
Absolutely fucking not.
必須他媽的不合法
But we were making more money than we knew what to do with.
但我們能賺到多得不知道怎么花的錢
And what do you do when you're making
在錢多得不知道怎么花的時候
more money than you know what to do with?
你要怎么花呢
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Will you marry me?
你愿意嫁給我嗎
Oh, my God.
天啊
Is that a yes?
你是答應了嗎
Are you sure?
你確定嗎
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure.
是的  是的  我確定
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
-你愿意嗎  -愿意
I held my bachelor party
我在拉斯維加斯的
at the Mirage in Las Vegas.
米拉奇辦了單身派對
The flight there alone was a bacchanal.
從飛機上就開始縱酒狂歡了
One last blowout for the gods before I settled down for good.
成家前的最后放縱
A hundred Strattonites,
上百名斯特拉頓人
50 hookers,
50個妓女
plus 50 more waiting once we landed.
落地了還有50個
Oh, and the drugs.
當然也少不了毒品
I mean, I tell you, our plane
這么說吧  我們飛機
was like a pharmacy with wings.
就像是插上翅膀的藥房
All told, the weekend cost me two million bucks,
這個周末一共花了我兩百萬美金
including the cost of refurbishing the entire 28th floor.
包括翻修整個28樓的費用
Kiss the bride.
親吻新娘
But the wedding was something out of a fairy tale.
但婚禮像童話般美好
With Naomi, my Duchess,
內奧米是我的公爵夫人
me, her handsome Duke,
而我就是她帥氣的公爵
and The Bahamas Ocean Club, our castle.
巴哈馬海洋俱樂部  則是我們的城堡
Of course, after the bachelor party, me, the Duke,
當然  在單身派對后  我這個公爵
needed a few penicillin shots so he could
得打點青霉素
safely consummate the marriage.
才能安全地洞房
Hey! Barry Kleinman, filming the wedding.
我是巴瑞·克萊門  正在拍攝婚禮現場
A few words for your son?
對你兒子說點什么吧
Jordan. Remember what I told you.
喬丹  牢記我的話
It involves your penis and her vagina.
關于你的陰莖和她的陰道的
And you know, you know what you can do, Jordy.
你懂的  你知道自己能做什么  喬迪
Oh, my God!
天啊
Aunt Emma?
艾瑪姑姑
I can't believe you came!
真不敢相信您能來
Jordan! Jordan! Look who came!
喬丹  喬丹  看看誰來了
It's Aunt Emma.
是艾瑪姑姑
Aunt Emma.
艾瑪姑姑
- Oh, Jordan, dear, how lovely. - Hey, how you doing?
-喬丹  你真可愛  -你好嗎
It's a pleasure to finally meet you in person.
真榮幸見到您
Into the donuts, I see.
吃了不少甜甜圈吧
Oh, I... I...
我   我
Well...
這個
I lived through the '60s, my dear.
我經歷過60年代  親愛的
Enjoy the day.
好好享受吧
She surprised me. I didn't even know.
真是個驚喜  我都不知道
Just one more step. Are you ready?
再走幾步  準備好
- Where are we going? - Keep your eyes closed.
-這是去哪  -別偷看
One, two, three!
一  二  三
What is this?
這是什么
- It's your wedding present. - What?
-你的新婚禮物  -什么
It's your wedding present, sweetheart.
是你的新婚禮物  親愛的
What?
什么
- Are you serious? - I'm serious.
-你開玩笑吧  -是真的
A fucking yacht?
一艘游艇
For millionaires whose ships have come in,
游艇正在富翁中流行
pricey pleasure boats are for the most fun afloat.
豪華舒適的游艇才能帶來頂級享受
It's no coincidence that its 150 feet of green hull
150英尺長的綠色船體
is the color of cash. Anchors aweigh!
正是鈔票的顏色  起航
Oh, my God! Baby!
天啊  親愛的
- I think you like it? - You're crazy.
-我覺得你會喜歡的  -太瘋狂了
- You like it? - Yes!
-喜歡嗎  -喜歡
For three weeks,
接下來三周
we sailed the Naomi through the Caribbean,
我們乘著內奧米號穿過加勒比海
eventually taking her home to Long Island,
最后抵達位于長島的家
where we bought a house.
我們在那買了棟房子
Seven acres on the Gold Coast of Long Island.
長島黃金海岸  七英畝的地盤
The most expensive real estate in the world.
世界上最昂貴的地產
With maids, cooks, landscapers, you name it.
仆人  廚師  園藝師  應有盡有
We even had two guards who worked in shifts.
甚至還有兩個輪班的保鏢
Both named Rocco.
都叫羅科
It was heaven on earth.
簡直是天上人間
Wake up, you piece of shit!
起來  你這個混蛋
Who's Venice?
威尼斯是誰
Who?
誰
Who? Who?
誰  誰
"Who?" What are you, a fucking owl?
還問誰  別裝傻了
Who is she?
她是誰
Some little hooker you were fucking last night?
昨晚睡的婊子嗎
What the fuck are you talking about? No.
你他媽說什么呢  沒有
No way, baby, no!
不可能  寶貝  沒有
You were calling her name in your sleep!
你夢里還喊她名字呢
Are you out of your fucking mind? I don't...
你他媽瘋了吧  我沒有
I don't even know who Venice is.
我都不知道威尼斯是誰
What the fuck does that even mean? Venice.
威尼斯是啥意思
That's the stupidest shit I've ever heard in my fucking life!
這是我這輩子聽過的最扯蛋的事了
Venice...
威尼斯
Venice, baby, where are you?
威尼斯  親愛的  你在哪
Where'd you go?
你去哪了
Oh, baby. Oh, you're gonna play rough, huh?
親愛的  你要玩狠的是吧
- Oh, Jesus Christ! - You like that?
-天啊  -你喜歡嗎
I like it. I like it.
我喜歡  我喜歡
Wolfie, Wolfie, Wolfie, Wolfie.
小狼  小狼  小狼  小狼
Wolfie?
小狼?
Yeah, it's my safe word, baby. It's my safe word.
是我的安全詞  是我的安全詞
I don't give a fuck about your safe word!
我他媽才不管你的安全詞呢
- Come on! - Shut the fuck up!
-拜托  -你他媽閉嘴
Shut up, you little bitch!
閉嘴  小賤貨
You're a fucking dirty little birdy!
你真是個下流的妞
That's right.
對了
That's right! I forgot.
對了  我忘了
I forgot, baby.
我都忘了  寶貝
Donnie and I were investing in a condominium complex in Venice.
唐尼和我在威尼斯投資了個酒店公寓
That's why all this confusion.
所以你誤會了
Oh, you're investing in Italy?
你還去意大利投資了
Not Italy. California.
不是意大利  是加州
- Oh, California? - Yeah.
-是嗎  加州  -對
You're a lying piece of shit!
鬼話連篇的混蛋
Duchess, baby, come on.
公爵夫人  親愛的
Don't you fucking "Duchess" Me.
你他媽別叫我夫人
Don't you "Duchess" Me!
別叫我夫人
Do you really think that I don't know what you're up to?
你以為我不知道你的小伎倆
- You're a father now, Jordan. - Yeah.
-你是有孩子的人了  喬丹  -是啊
- You're a father now. - I know...
-你該像個父親樣  -我知道
And you're still acting like an infant!
可你做事還那么幼稚
God damn it!
去你媽的
Baby, you know, you got real anger issues.
寶貝  你得管管你的臭脾氣了
Who is the one who flew in here
是誰凌晨三點了
at 3 in the morning on their stupid helicopter
才開著傻逼直升機回來
and woke up Skylar? That was you!
還吵醒了斯凱拉  是你
Oh, Skylar! Oh, fucking bullshit!
吵醒了斯凱拉  簡直是屁話
Does it even matter to you that I just had that driving range
你有注意過我剛給高爾夫場
sodded with Bermuda grass, Jordan,
鋪了百慕大草嗎  喬丹
- and now you fucking wrecked it! - Oh, my God... Bermuda grass.
-全都被你毀了  -天啊  百慕大草
No, you didn't research the whole thing
你連看都不看
and deal with the fucking golf course people!
也從來不和高爾夫球場的人打交道
Oh, my God,
天啊
you had to deal with the golf course people, too!
你還得和球場的人打交道
What a Greek tragedy, honey! Oh, my God!
真是悲劇啊  親愛的  天啊
You probably had to pay them in cash with your hands!
你是不是還得親手付他們現金啊
What a fucking burden.
辛苦你了
And actually do some work
除了整天刷我的信用卡之外
besides swiping my fucking credit card all day, huh?
還得做這么辛苦的事  是吧
Because I can't keep track of your professions, honey.
我都跟不上你的職業變化了  親愛的
'Cause last month you were a wine connoisseur.
上個月你還是紅酒鑒定家
Now you're an aspiring landscape architect!
現在又成了高雅的景觀設計師
- Let me get that right... No! - Fuck you!
-這么說吧...別  -去你媽的
Don't fucking dare throw that fucking water at me.
你敢把水潑來試試
Don't you fucking dare.
你敢潑
All right, honey?
冷靜  親愛的
Now will you just...
你能不能...
We could talk this out, all right?
我們談談吧  好嗎
We just use our words. You know?
動口不動手  知道嗎
Communicate.
交流
Okay?
行嗎
Come on, sweetheart.
來吧  親愛的
Talk to me. Talk to me.
說說話  談談
Stop flexing your muscles, Jordan.
別再秀肌肉了  喬丹
You look like a fucking imbecile.
看著跟腦殘一樣
Babe, come on.
寶貝  別這樣
You should feel happy you got a husband
你丈夫身材這么好
who's in such great shape like this, huh?
你該高興啊
Come here.
過來
Come on, give me a kiss.
過來  親親我
You look so beautiful right now.
你看起來美極了
- Come on. - Kiss you?
-來吧  -親你?
- You look so beautiful... - Kiss you?
-你好美啊  -親你?
Yeah, give me one...
是啊  就親一下
Fuck you!
操
Ah, yes, my morning ritual.
沒錯  早晨的慣例
First I'd get up and fight with Naomi
起床先跟內奧米
about whatever it is I did the night before.
就前一晚的什么傻事吵架
Next was a steam so I could sweat out
然后蒸個桑拿
the drugs still in my system.
排掉留在身體里的毒品
Then I'd assess the damage.
然后評估一下損失
Drown out my eyeballs.
滴眼藥水
Take my "Back pills" To get the day started,
吃點"背痛藥"  開始這一天
then seek to make up with Naomi.
然后想法兒跟內奧米和好
Good morning, Daddy.
早上好  爸比
Where's my kiss?
給人家的親親呢
Hey, sweetheart.
小甜心
Does Daddy get a kiss from both of his little girls, huh?
爸比可以跟兩個甜心都親親嗎
Oh, no.
不行
No, Daddy doesn't even get to touch Mommy
爸比不能碰媽咪
for a very, very,
很久很久
very long time.
都不能碰
Daddy's really sorry about what he said in the other room.
爸比對剛才的話非常抱歉
He didn't mean any of it.
那都是氣話
Daddy shouldn't waste his time.
爸比不用浪費口舌
And from now on,
從現在起
it's gonna be nothing but short,
媽咪在家只會穿
short skirts around the house.
超短的小裙子了
And you know something else, Daddy?
你知道嗎  爸比
Mommy is just so sick and tired of wearing panties.
媽咪好討厭穿小內褲啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-是嗎  -是的
In fact,
其實
she's decided to throw them
她已經把內褲
all away.
都丟掉了
So take a good look, Daddy.
看好了  爸比
You're gonna be seeing an awful lot of this around the house.
以后在家會經常看到哦
Oh, baby...
寶貝
Yeah, Mommy.
是嗎  媽咪
- Yeah... - But no touching.
-是啊  -但不許碰
Oh, gosh.
老天啊
What's wrong, Daddy?
怎么了  爸比
Baby.
寶貝
God!
天啊
Look at this shit.
你快看
Okay. Mommy likes to play games with Daddy.
好吧  媽咪想和爸比玩游戲
Mommy, have you ever noticed anything odd about Mr.
媽咪  你有注意過那只
Mr. Fuzzy Bear over there?
毛毛熊有點奇怪嗎
His eyes seem to be a little bit odd, don't they?
他的眼睛有點奇怪  是吧
Yeah, there's something a little bit different about his eyes.
是啊  眼睛有點奇怪
Yes! I think it's true. Say "Hi," Mommy.
沒錯  是的  打個招呼  媽咪
Say "Hi" To Rocco and Rocco.
跟羅科和羅科打個招呼
Say "Hi." Hi, fellas.
打招呼  伙計們你們好
See that, huh?
都看到了嗎
Of all the fucking days,
這么多天來
she chooses today to give me blue balls!
她偏偏挑今天來挑逗我
I mean, today was the biggest day in Stratton's history,
今天可是斯特拉頓史上最重要的一天
and I needed to be thinking straight.
我得理清頭緒
Hey, Jordan!
喬丹
- Welcome. - Steve here yet?
-歡迎  -史蒂夫來了嗎
This was the day that we launched the Steve Madden IPO.
今天我們要為史蒂夫·麥登首次公開籌股
Troops are all here, everyone's all rallied, excited.
人都齊了  大家都歡欣鼓舞著呢
Everything had to run tight.
一切都要按部就班
It had to be perfect.
不容有差
What the fuck is that kid doing?
那熊孩子在做什么
What's he doing?
他在干嘛
The biggest IPO in this firm's history.
公司史上規模最大的公開募股
What the fuck is he doing?
他你媽的在做什么
Is he... Is he wearing a bow tie?
他戴的是領結嗎
Hi.
你好
How're you doing?
感覺怎么樣
Good.
很好
You cleaning the fish bowl?
你擦魚缸呢
I just... I had a minute and...
我恰好有空
You had a minute.
你有空
And today you needed to clean the fish bowl? Today?
非得在今天擦魚缸嗎  今天
I had finished my paperwork and I had a couple of minutes.
我已經做完工作了  有點空閑時間
Okay. Nice to meet you.
好吧  很高興見到你
On new issue day?
非得在發行日
On cocksucking, motherfucking new issue day?
非他媽的在發行日嗎
This is what you do?
你就干這個
Hey, everybody, listen up!
大家聽著
This is what happens when
發行日這天還玩寵物
you fuck with your pets on new issue day!
就是這個下場
Take your little bow tie, get your shit,
戴著你的小領結
and get the fuck out of my office! You understand?
收攤子走人  聽懂了嗎
Get the fuck out!
滾蛋
Everybody on point!
各就各位
We are here to make money. Everybody on point.
你們是來這賺錢的  各就各位
A real wolf pit, which is exactly how I liked it.
這兒就是個狼窩  而我愛的也正是這點
Jordan, look what I caught in the lobby.
喬丹  看看我在大廳遇到誰了
I caught a genius.
遇到個天才
Enter Steve Madden.
那就是史蒂夫·麥登
The great American cobbler.
偉大的美國鞋匠
Red-hot ladies footwear impresario.
炙手可熱的女鞋制造者
And thanks to Donnie,
多虧了唐尼
we were taking his company public.
我們才能幫他的公司上市
Stratton Oakmont was crawling out of the primordial ooze.
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特爬出原始的泥濘
Pond scum no more.
再也不是井底之蛙了
That's why they gotta see your face.
所以得讓他們見見你
You get them fired up so
你要鼓舞士氣
they push the shit out of this stock. Okay?
大家才能拼命賣股票  好嗎
And not only that, Donnie and I secretly owned
不僅如此  唐尼和我
85% of Steve Madden Shoes,
秘密持有史蒂夫·麥登鞋業85%的股份
which legally speaking was a big no-no,
這是法律絕對不允許的
but we'd get filthy fucking rich if our troops got behind it.
但我們打算著狠狠撈上一筆
Our job was to get them worked up.
我們要鼓舞士氣
But not too worked up.
但也不能太士氣高漲了
Hello. If...
大家好
For those of you who don't know me...
如果有不認識我的
My name's Steve Madden.
我叫史蒂夫·麥登
Yeah, we know who you are.
我們知道你是誰
Your name is on the box.
盒子上都印著你的名字呢
Get the shoes. Show them the shoes.
拿鞋子  給他們看看鞋子
- Show them the shoes. - Okay. Yeah.
-給他們看看鞋子  -好
Anyway, you know, this shoe is pretty cool.
這鞋子很酷的
This is the Mary Lou,
叫瑪麗璐
which is really the shoe that put me on the map.
我的成名作
Without it, I wouldn't be here.
如果沒有它  我就不會站在這
It's a fat girls' shoe!
這是給胖妞穿的
Believe it or not... Believe it or not though,
不管你信不信
the Mary Lou is actually the
瑪麗璐實際上和瑪麗珍同款
same as the Mary Jane, but it's black leather.
只不過是黑色皮質的
Fight back! Come on! Where you at? Where you at?
反擊  是誰扔的  是誰扔的
All right!
好了
Let's give it up for Steve Madden and his awesome Mary Lou!
掌聲送給史蒂夫·麥登和他超贊的瑪麗璐
Hold that up. Hold that up. Hold that up proud!
舉起來  舉起來  自豪地舉起來
Give him a round of applause!
掌聲獻上
You guys got that out of your systems, huh?
發泄完了嗎
You having a good afternoon or what?
下午過得怎么樣
I wanna take a moment and tell you why Steve here is so
我要花點時間  告訴你們
absolutely off the fucking wall.
為什么說史蒂夫與眾不同
It's because this man is a creative genius.
因為他是個創作天才
This ability, this gift that Steve has,
史蒂夫的能力和天賦
it goes beyond just spotting the hottest shoe trends.
不是緊跟女鞋時尚潮流
Steve's power is that he creates trends.
而是他  能引領潮流
You understand?
懂嗎
Artists like Steve come along once every decade.
史蒂夫這樣的藝術家十年難遇
I'm talking Giorgio Armani, Gianni Versace,
就像喬治· 阿瑪尼  詹尼·范思哲
Coco Chanel,
可可·香奈兒
Yves Saint Laurent.
伊夫圣羅蘭
Steve, come over here for a second.
史蒂夫  過來一下
I don't think you all realize
你們可能沒有意識到
that Steve Madden
史蒂夫·麥登
is the hottest person in the women's shoe industry,
是女鞋界最炙手可熱的人物
with orders going through the roof
北美的每一家百貨商場
at every department store in North America right now.
他的訂單都多到滿天飛
We have him here in our office!
我們竟有幸邀請他來辦公室
We should thank our fucking lucky stars this man is here!
謝天謝地  他來了
We should be on our hands and knees right now,
我們應該五體投地
getting ready to suck this guy off!
給他跪舔
Like this! Okay?
像這樣  知道嗎
I wanna suck you off, Steve!
我要跪舔你的雞雞  史蒂夫
Everyone's gonna suck you off!
大家都想給你跪舔
This is our golden ticket
這就是我們進入
to the fucking chocolate factory right here!
巧克力工廠的金獎券
And I wanna meet
我要的是
Willy fucking Wonka, okay?
威利·旺卡那樣的魔法人物
I wanna be with the fucking Oompa Loompas like this!
要像奧柏倫柏人那樣瘋狂一次
All right, get off this fucking stage! Get out of here.
好了  下去吧  下去
All right, I want all of you to focus for a second.
大家都聽好了
See those little black boxes?
看到那些小黑盒子了嗎
They're called telephones.
那叫電話
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret about these telephones.
告訴你們一個關于電話的小秘密
They're not gonna dial themselves. Okay?
它們不會自己撥號  知道嗎
Without you, they're just worthless hunks of plastic.
沒有你們  它們只是快沒用的塑料
Like a loaded M16
就像上膛的M16
without a trained Marine to pull the trigger.
卻沒有扣動扳機的士兵
And in the case of the telephone,
而這些電話存在的意義
it's up to each and every one of you,
就取決于在座的各位
my highly-trained Strattonites.
我訓練有素的斯特拉頓人
My killers!
我的殺手們
My killers, who will not take no for an answer!
殺手們  不能接受否定的答案
My fucking warriors,
我的戰士們
who will not hang up the phone
決不輕易掛斷電話
until their client either buys
直到客戶被拿下
or fucking dies!
或者他媽死球
Let me tell you something.
讓我來告訴你們一件事
There is no nobility in poverty.
沒錢是裝不了貴公子的
I have been a rich man
我可能成為一個富人
and I have been a poor man.
也可能成為一個窮人
And I choose rich every fucking time.
我每次都他媽選擇當富人
Because at least as a rich man,
因為作為一個富人
when I have to face my problems,
當我要面對什么問題時
I show up in the back of a limo,
我起碼可以坐在加長豪車后座出場
wearing a $2,000 suit
穿著一身兩千美元的西服
and a $40,000 gold fucking watch!
帶著四萬美元他媽一塊的金表
Duke it out! Hit him!
打一架  揍他
Get the fuck off me!
從我身上他媽滾下來
And if anyone here thinks I'm superficial or materialistic,
假如這兒有任何人覺得我膚淺或者物質
go get a job at fucking McDonald's,
那你去他媽的麥當勞找份工作吧
'cause that's where you fucking belong!
因為那里才是你他媽該去的地方
But before you depart this room full of winners,
但在你離開這間滿是勝者的房間之前
I want you to take a good look at the person next to you. Go on.
我希望你能好好看看你身邊的人  看吧
Because sometime in the not-so-distant future,
因為在不遠的將來
you're gonna be pulling up to
你會開著一輛破破爛爛的福特斑馬
a red light in your beat-up old fucking Pinto,
在紅燈前停下
and that person's gonna be pulling up right alongside you
而那個人會開著一輛嶄新的保時捷
in their brand new Porsche
停在你旁邊
with their beautiful wife by their side,
身旁還坐著他們漂亮的
who's got big voluptuous tits.
有一對大奶子的妻子
And who're you gonna be sitting next to?
而你身邊會坐著誰呢
Some disgusting wildebeest with three days of razor-stubble,
某頭惡心的角馬  滿嘴唇毛
in a sleeveless muumuu,
穿著件無袖長袍
crammed in next to you
擠進你身邊
in a carload full of groceries from the fucking Price Club!
帶著一滿車從他媽折扣批發超市買的雜物
That's who you're gonna be sitting next to!
那就是將來坐在你身邊的人
So you listen to me and you listen well.
所以你們聽我說  而且聽仔細了
Are you behind on your credit card bills?
你是不是還有信用卡賬單沒付清
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
很好  拿起你們的電話然后開始撥號吧
Is your landlord ready to evict you?
你的房東是不是準備趕你出門了
Does your girlfriend think you're a fucking worthless loser?
你女朋友是否覺得你他媽就是個屌絲
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
很好  拿起你們的電話然后開始撥號吧
I want you to deal with your problems by becoming rich!
我希望你們能賺夠錢去解決這些問題
All you have to do today is pick up that phone
你們今天唯一需要做的就是拿起那臺電話
and speak the words that I have taught you.
然后說出我教你們說的話
And I will make you richer
然后我就能讓你們變得
than the most powerful
比美利堅他媽合眾國
CEO in the United States of fucking America!
大部分有權有勢的CEO都富有
Yeah!
好
Fuck, yeah!
他媽的棒極了
I want you to go out there
我希望你們上場
and I want you to ram
然后把史蒂夫·麥登的股票
Steve Madden stock down your clients' throats
塞進你客戶的喉嚨
until they fucking choke on it!
直到他們噎住為止
Till they choke on it and they buy 100,000 shares!
直到他們噎死而且買了十萬股為止
That's what I want.
那就是我想要的
Yeah! Fuck, yeah.
好  太他媽好了
You be ferocious!
你們要夠兇殘
- You be relentless! - Yeah!
-你們要夠無情  -好
You be telephone fucking terrorists!
你們要當他媽的電話恐怖分子
Now let's knock this motherfucker out of the park!
現在  讓我們把這操蛋的東西踢出去吧
At 1:00 p.m.,
下午一點
we opened the stock for sale at $4.50 a share.
我們以每股四塊五美元的價格開市
By 1:03, it was over $18.
到一點零三分  股價就超過了十八美元
Even the big Wall Street firms were buying.
就連華爾街上的大投行也在買
Of the two million shares offered for sale,
出售的兩百萬股里面
a million belonged to me, held in phony accounts by my ratholes.
有一百萬是從我的老鼠倉帳戶流出來的
Now once the price hit the high teens...
一旦價格到了高位
You know what? Who gives a shit?
你知道的  誰他媽在乎別的
As always, the point is this.
重點向來都是這個
$22 million in three fucking hours!
三小時就他媽兩千兩百萬了
Can you believe this shit?
你能相信嗎
I fucking love this, baby!
我他媽愛死這個了  寶貝兒
It's amazing!
這簡直太棒了
Jordan!
喬丹
Barry Kleinman's on the phone
巴瑞·克萊門打電話找你
- from Future Video. - Who?
-未來影視的  -誰
I don't know. He shot at your wedding.
我不知道  他給你婚禮攝過像
He says it's urgent.
他是有急事
Urgent? Who the fuck is Barry Kleinman?
急事  巴瑞·克萊門是哪根蔥
Oh, my God, you wanna marry me?
天吶  你想嫁給我嗎
You're in love with me?
你愛上我了嗎
Yeah. Go fuck your cousin!
是啊是啊  去操你表妹吧
Hey, Barry, what's up?
巴瑞  有事嗎
Listen, I got this subpoena.
聽著  我收到了一張傳票
Subpoena? What the fuck are you talking about?
傳票  你他媽在說什么呢
Yeah, the FBI,
是的  是聯邦調查局的人
they want a copy of your wedding video.
他們想要一份你婚禮錄像的拷貝
The fucking FBI?
他媽的聯邦調查局
- You fucking kidding me? - Listen to me.
-你他媽逗我呢吧  -聽著
His name is Denham.
他叫德納姆
He's an agent with the New York office.
他是調查局紐約辦事處的一個探員
What's his problem?
他想干什么
Gordon GekkoHe's a Boy Scout.
他就像個童子軍
He thinks you're fucking Gordon Gekko.
他覺得你他媽是戈登·蓋柯
What does he want with my wedding video?
他想要我的婚禮錄像做什么
It's like an invasion of my privacy.
這是對我隱私的一種侵犯
You know what I'm saying? It's like...
你懂我在說什么嗎  這就像...
It's intrusive, you know.
這很具有侵略性  你懂
He's got pictures of your whole inner fucking circle.
他有你整個核心集團的照片
Pictures, names of the people.
照片  以及那些人的名字
You know what he's trying to do?
你知道他想干什么嗎
Exactly what he's doing. Look at yourself.
就是他正在干的事  看看你自己
He's trying to rattle you,
他試圖把你嘮叨死
he's trying to rattle your old lady,
他試圖把你老婆嘮叨死
so she nags you
然后她就會朝你叨叨個不停
until you become a fucking witness.
直到你他媽出庭作證為止
He wants me to rat on myself?
他想我自我檢舉揭發
He wants me to give information about my...
他想我透露我自己的信息
Listen. The good fucking news is,
聽著  他媽的好消息是
you know I know everybody downtown,
你知道我認識市里的每個人
I call up the Justice Department, the DEA,
我可以打電話給司法部  給緝毒局
nobody even knows you fucking exist,
甚至不會有人知道你他媽的存在
so calm down!
所以說放松點
They don't know I exist?
他們不知道我的存在
- No. - That's good.
-不知道  -那很好
But you...
但你...
You know who he is, right?
你知道他是誰  是吧
- Yeah. - So, if I just wanted to get some more information,
-沒錯  -所以假如我想要問點消息
just find out what he knows,
就看看他知道了多少東西
you could go to his house, right?
你能去他家吧  是嗎
Tap his phones a little bit, bug him.
竊聽一下他的電話  安點竊聽器
You could get some information...
你能搞到點消息...
You don't fuck with these guys like that.
你不能這樣搞這些人
You don't fuck with them like that.
你不能這樣搞他們
What are you, nuts or something?
你怎么回事  是瘋了還是怎樣
This is what you fucking do.
這就是你他媽要干的事情
What do I pay you for?
不然我付錢給你是干什么的
I have a fucking P.I. License, you know?
我是有他媽的偵探執照的  知道嗎
I make a living at this.
我是靠這個吃飯的
I'm not a cop anymore.
我不再是一名警察了
They'll take my fucking license away from me, all right?
他們會他媽的把我的執照奪走  明白嗎
Okay.
好吧
Okay, if I can't do that, can I just...
好吧  要是這樣不行  能不能...
Can I give the guy a call?
我能給這家伙打個電話嗎
- Why? Is that... - Jordan. Jordan.
-怎么了  這是  -喬丹  喬丹
Do me a favor?
行行好
The only one who calls this guy
唯一一個能給這家伙打電話的
is your fucking lawyer.
就是你他媽的律師
I can't call him, right?
我不能打給他  是吧
- It's against the rules? - I told you,
-這違反了規定嗎  -我告訴你
whatever the fuck you say to him,
不管你他媽對他說了什么
he's gonna use against you. Don't you understand?
他都會用來對付你  你難道不明白嗎
He's smart, you're dumb.
他很聰明  你很蠢
Fucking bullshit.
放他媽的屁
Are we fucking talking tonight,
我們今晚是他媽的要好好談談
or are you gonna get schwacked?
還是你打算嗑到暈
The last time you took these fucking pills,
上次你嗑這些該死的藥時
you put your head in the fucking macaroni.
你把你的頭伸進了他媽的通心粉里
I had to pick it up.
得我去把你抬起來
All right.
好吧
Okay, I won't call him.
好吧  我不會打給他的
Hey, fellas! Come on board. The plank's right around there.
伙計們  上船來  踏板就在那邊
Welcome!
歡迎
What a nice day.
真是美好的一天啊
Hey.
你好
Welcome aboard.
歡迎登船
Jordan. Welcome aboard the Naomi.
我是喬丹  歡迎登上內奧米號
Pleasure to meet you.
很高興見到你
Agent Denham. This is Agent Hughes.
德納姆探員  這位是休斯探員
Hi, how are you?
你好啊
Let me introduce you. This is Nicole,
讓我來給你們介紹一下  這位是尼克爾
Heidi. Come on. Don't be shy.
這位是海蒂  來吧  別害羞
What are you guys all shy for? Don't be scared.
你倆害羞個什么勁啊  別怕
These are friends of Stratton.
她們是斯特拉頓的朋友
- It's a pleasure. - Hello.
-很高興見到你們  -你好
Your message said that you wanted to speak privately.
你信息上說你想單獨談談
Right. I do want to speak privately.
沒錯  我是想單獨談談
Give us a minute, huh, ladies?
給我們點時間唄  女士們
Let me know if I can get you anything.
要我幫你們拿什么東西盡管開口
We'd be happy to help.
我們很樂意幫忙的
You guys hungry?
你們餓不餓
Want something to eat?
想吃點什么嗎
Got some pasta, shrimp, lobster.
這兒有意面  對蝦  龍蝦
I got whiskey.
我還有威士忌
Any kind of booze you want.
你們想喝什么酒我這兒都有
You know what? The Bureau doesn't allow us to drink while we're at sea.
局里不允許我們"出海"的時候喝酒
Duh! Of course.
哈  當然啦
Ever been on one of these before?
你以前來過這種地方嗎
A boat?
你指船上嗎
I learned how to sail when I was six.
我六歲就學會開船了
No shit. Is that right? Really?
你沒開玩笑吧  是嗎  真的嗎
I mean on one like this, though?
我的意思是像這樣的
I mean I had the whole front extended
我的意思是我把前面整個加長
in order to fit the chopper up there.
專門用來停直升機
See that?
看見那個了嗎
Anyway, this is for you.
不管怎樣  這是給你的
It's a complete list of every person that was at my wedding.
這是參加我婚禮的人的完整名單
I understand you wanted the whole wedding video.
我理解你想要整個婚禮錄像
Figured this would help expedite the whole process, right?
我猜這個能幫你加快進程  對吧
- There you go. - Look, my point is that
-確實如此  -聽著  我的重點是
I know you're investigating Stratton.
我知道你在調查斯特拉頓
But for the life of me, I can't figure out why.
但我想我一輩子也想不通是為什么
I know we're a little unorthodox,
我知道我們是有點不正統
we're a little loud in the way we do things.
我們做事有點大張旗鼓
But you gotta understand,
但是你得理解
we're the new guys on the block, you know,
我們是新入行的  你懂
we're trying to make a name for ourselves.
我們在努力讓自己名揚萬里
But I want you to understand, we don't do anything illegal.
但我希望你明白  我們不做違法的事
Whatsoever.
無論如何也不做
I mean, you could talk to the SEC.
你可以去找證監會的人
They were at my office 15 times over the last six months.
他們過去六個月來我辦公室拜訪了十五次
I mean, I got... I got nothing to hide.
我是說  我沒...我沒什么要隱瞞的
Well, you know the SEC is a civil regulatory agency.
你知道證監會只是個民事管理機構
We pursue criminal activities.
而我們查的是犯罪活動
Exactly! You go after real criminals,
正是這樣  你要查的是真正的犯罪
which makes me wonder what the hell you're investigating me for?
這讓我很好奇你們為什么會調查我
I mean, honestly...
我是說  說實話...
what is it that you think that we did or do?
你覺得我們做過什么或者在做什么嗎
I don't get it.
我不明白
Well, I...
我...
Look, Jordan, I can't discuss an ongoing investigation.
喬丹  我不能討論正在進行的調查
No, I get that. No, I understand.
沒事  我明白  沒事的  我理解
With that said...
雖然這么說
this case got dumped on my desk...
其實這案子是被扔在我桌上的
- Did it? - You know, by a higher-up
-是這樣嗎  -你懂的  高層
who needs to make a show
那些想要作秀的人
of looking into the new company on the block,
得借著追查一家新公司為由
- with all the press and everything. - New loud guys.
-拉上一堆媒體之類的  -新上位那些
And then I end up being the schmuck who does the looking.
然后我就變成了來做調查的蠢貨
Exactly.
就是這樣
It's just, you know... it bothers me.
只是  你懂的...這東西很煩
We're the new guy.
我們是新人
We're the one that's banging on Wall Street's door.
我們是去敲華爾街的門的人
I mean, you should...
我的意思是  你應該...
You should see what's going on at the bigger firms.
你應該去查查那些大投行在干什么
I mean, I know all the information.
我說  我知道所有的內幕
It's true! Goldman, Lehman Brothers, Merrill...
是真的  高盛  雷曼兄弟  美林
Collateralized debt obligations?
擔保債務憑證
This Internet stock bullshit?
還有什么互聯網概念股
I mean, it's a fucking travesty.
簡直就是他媽的放屁
I could take you step-by-step
我能手把手地告訴你
through what exactly is occurring.
他們每一步都在做什么
All you have to do is ask.
你只需要開口問
I'm available.
我隨時恭候
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
我就等你這句話了
I don't see why a little sitdown like this
我不明白像這樣的談話
can't be profitable for the both of us.
怎么就不能對我們雙方都有利了
It should. Right?
本來就應該這樣  是吧
It should profit the both of us.
這本來就該對我們雙方都有利
- It should. - Look.
-是應該這樣  -聽著
I'm gonna give you my personal line.
我會給你我的私人號碼
Five days a week, you just call me, feel free.
工作日里隨時可以打電話給我
- I'll do that. - Great.
-我會的  -棒極了
Are you sure you guys don't want something to drink?
你們確定不喝點什么
You're not hungry? Nothing?
你們不餓嗎  什么也不要
- Nothing? No? - Oh, no.
-什么都不要嗎  不要嗎  -不用了
Let me ask you,
讓我問你幾個問題
and if you don't wanna get too personal,
假如你不想透露太多個人信息
just tell me to shut up at any time.
你可以隨時叫我閉嘴
Did you try to get your broker's license at one time?
你是不是曾經考慮過弄個經紀人執照
Did I hear that right?
我不知道自己有沒有聽錯
Were you trying to take a stab at Wall Street?
你是不是也曾想來華爾街分一杯羹
- No? - Who you been talking to?
-沒有嗎  -你和誰談過話
Who the fuck you been talking to?
你他媽和誰談過了
Well, you're investigating me. I hear things.
你在調查我  我也聽了你的事跡
You know what I mean?
你懂我意思吧
You ever think about what would've happened
你有沒有想過假如你堅持下去了
if you would have stayed the course?
會發生什么
You know what? When I'm riding home on the subway
你知道嗎  每當我搭地鐵回家
and my balls are fucking sweating,
蛋蛋都他媽汗濕了
I'm wearing the same suit three days in a row...
一套西服連續穿了三天...
Yeah, you bet I do.
沒錯  我當然想過
I've thought about it before. Who wouldn't, right?
我以前就想過這個  誰不想呢  是吧
Right, who fucking wouldn't?
沒錯  誰他媽會不想呢
What do you get...
你是怎么...
Another personal question, no need to answer...
又是一個私人為題  你不用回答
No, that's all right, Jordan.
沒事  沒關系的  喬丹
What do you pull in? 50, 60K? Something like that?
你能賺多少啊  五六萬之類的
A year? In the ballpark?
一年嗎  大約
Well, I...
我...
Let's put it this way.
這樣說吧
You get a free handgun when you sign up for the Bureau.
局里至少能給你一把免費的槍
No, but it fucking pisses me off. You know what I mean?
這他媽讓我很生氣啊  你懂我意思嗎
You think about the people that built this country,
你想想  那些建設了這個國家的人
hardworking people like you.
像你一樣勤勤懇懇的人
Firefighters, teachers, FBI agents.
消防員  老師  聯邦探員
End of the day,
結果到最后
you guys get fucking skinned alive financially.
你們這群人在經濟上被生吞活剝了
It fucking makes me angry.
這他媽讓我太生氣了
Now the one thing about Wall Street and this market is,
如今  關于華爾街和這個市場
for me, I feel
在我看來  我覺得
it's good to give back. You know, there's...
能回饋社會是好事  你知道  有些
There are situations where I can
有些情況下我能
make those situations better for people. You know?
讓這些人處境好點  明白嗎
You know what I mean.
你懂我意思的
Opportunity
機遇
is everything.
就是一切
Exactly.
太對了
Take for example, I got this one kid, right?
舉個例子  有這么個小孩  是吧
Went to school for environmental science, something like that.
去學校學環境科學之類的
He was bogged down by student loans.
但卻被學生貸款困住了
Turns out, his mother needed triple bypass surgery.
然后他媽又要做三重心臟搭橋手術
- Jesus. - Right. Horrible situation.
-天吶  -沒錯  很慘
Sure.
是啊
But we got him into the market
但是我們在正確的時候
at the right time and chose the right stock.
拉他入市  再選一只正確的股票
We gave him the right guidance.
我們給予他正確的指導
Boom! Overnight, changed his entire life.
轟  一夜之間  就改變了他整個人生
Got to put his mother into the best hospital in New York City.
他媽被送進了紐約最好的醫院
It didn't work out for her,
但還是沒用
granted, she passed away, unfortunately.
假設  她還是去世了  很不幸
But we gave him that opportunity.
但我們至少給了他那個機會
You know what I'm saying?
你懂我在說什么嗎
It's just about setting up the right team,
這取決于建立一個好團隊
and then overnight your life can change.
然后一夜之間你的人生將得以改變
What does... What does an intern...
一個實習生能...能...
What does an intern make in a deal like that?
一個實習生做這樣一單能賺多少
Well, in that situation,
在那種情況下
in that particular trade, and it was one trade,
在那筆特定的交易里  就那一筆
north of half a million dollars.
五十多萬美元吧
And I'd do that for anybody, you know,
而且我會為任何人做這件事  明白嗎
anybody that needs the proper guidance.
任何需要適當的指導的人
Can you say that again, just the way you said it?
能再說一遍嗎  就把剛剛說的再說一遍
Just the same way.
一模一樣的
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不懂你在說什么
Oh, come on! You know what I'm talking about.
算了吧  你當然懂我在說什么
I think what Jordan just did is he...
我覺得剛剛喬丹在干的事是...
- If I'm not mistaken... - No.
-假如我沒弄錯的話...  -不是
...you just tried to bribe a federal officer.
你剛剛在試圖賄賂一個聯邦官員
No, technically I didn't bribe anybody.
沒有  理論上我沒有賄賂任何人
No, no, that's not the conversation I heard, Jordan.
不不  我聽到的可不是這樣的  喬丹
No, no, according to the U.S. criminal code,
不不  根據美國刑法
there needs to be an exact
賄賂必須有個
dollar figure for the exchange of services.
確切的金額
That would not hold up in a court of law.
那個在法庭上站不住腳的
Nah, it's not how I heard it.
不不  我聽見的可不是這么回事
No, no, no, that's the truth.
不不不  事實就是如此
But I want to tell you this.
但我想告訴你這個
Yeah.
你說
The same gentleman that told me
那個告訴我你曾經試過
that you tried to get your broker's license
考經紀人執照的人
also told me that you are a straight arrow.
也和我說過你是個規矩正直的人
He ran a security check on me.
他把我仔細調查了一番
Well...
這個嘛...
Yeah, when you sail on a boat
沒錯  假如你駕著一艘
fit for a Bond villain,
像是邦德電影里反派開的船
sometimes you need to play the part. Right?
那有時你就得扮扮"惡人"   是吧
I think it's time you both get the fuck off my boat.
我覺得你倆是時候滾下我的船了
What do you say?
你說什么
You know, Jordan, I'll tell you something.
你知道嗎  喬丹  我告訴你一件事
Most of the Wall Street jackasses that I bust,
大部分我逮捕的華爾街混蛋
they're to the manor born.
他們都是天生如此
- Is that right? - Yeah.
-是嗎  -沒錯
Their fathers are douchebags,
他們老爹是混蛋
just like their fathers before them.
老爹的老爹也是
But you...
但你不一樣
You, Jordan, you got this way all on your own.
喬丹  你全是自己打拼出來的
Did I?
是嗎
- Good for you, little man. - Little man?
-佩服佩服  小伙子  -小伙子
Good for you.
真心佩服
Me, the little man?
你居然叫我小伙子
And let me tell you something.
而且我跟你說
Let me tell you something else.
我跟你說點別的
Honestly, I'm not bullshitting here,
老實說  我沒跟你開玩笑啊
this is one of the nicest boats
這艘船可說是我登上過的
- that I've ever been on, I gotta tell you. - I bet it is.
-最好的船了  真心話  -我看也是
And you know what I was just thinking, too?
你知道我還怎么想的嗎
The fucking hero that I'm gonna be back at the office
如果哪天局里派人封了這艘船
when the Bureau seizes this fucking boat.
那我他媽肯定就是大英雄
Because, I mean, fuckety-fuck-fuck, Jordan,
你他媽說是不是這樣  喬丹
look at this thing!
瞧瞧這艘船
It's beautiful!
多漂亮
And you got the beautiful girls there. It's wonderful.
而且你船上還有美妞兒  多好
All right, get the fuck off my boat.
挺好  快他媽給我滾
I'm sure we'll be seeing each other
我想我們很快就會
- real soon. - I'm sure.
-再見面的  -我同意
Good luck on that subway
祝你們坐破地鐵
ride home to your miserable, ugly fucking wives.
回家干你們臭婆娘的路上一路順風
I'm gonna have Heidi lick
我則要讓海蒂
some caviar off my balls in the meantime.
就著魚子醬舔我的蛋
Hey, you guys want to take some lobsters for your ride home?
你兩個想不想帶些龍蝦回家
Fucking miserable pricks, I know you can't afford them!
一群混蛋  諒你們也吃不起
Fucking cheap fucks.
一群賤貨
Fucking miserable pricks.
混蛋
Hey, fellas! Look what I found in my pocket! Look!
兩位  看看我掏兜的時候找著了啥
A year's salary right here.
把你們一年的工資都掏出來了
You know what I call them? Fun coupons!
你知道我管這叫什么嗎  優惠券
See that!
看見了嗎
They're fun coupons!
我都嫌多的優惠券
Switzerland? What the fuck is in Switzerland?
瑞士  瑞士有什么好逛的
Swiss fucking banks, that's what.
當然是去逛瑞士銀行
It was ass-covering time. I had to hide my money.
現在得遮遮丑  我必須得把錢藏起來
Enter Rugrat.
因特·魯格拉特
He knew this Swiss banker from law school.
他是在法學院里認識這個瑞士銀行家的
That's for European pussy!
這是干歐洲娘們用的
But he was in Geneva.
但他人在日內瓦
And there was no way I was gonna make that flight sober.
所以這趟長途飛機  我肯定要嗨著過去
So I knew if I took my drugs right,
我知道我只需適當的藥量
I could sleep through the entire flight.
就能睡完整個旅程
But I had to take them just right.
但必須要按時按量
At 4:00 P.M., I popped a few more ludes,
下午四點整  我又吃了幾片
which started kicking in by the time
這樣等我開完銷售會議
I finished my sales meeting.
藥勁正好上來
My tingle phase.
這是手腳刺癢階段
By dinner, I popped a few more
到晚餐時  我再吃幾片
on top of some cocktails and a Valium or two.
就著幾杯雞尾酒和一兩片安定
My slur phase.
這是口齒不清階段
By 8:30, I took a few more ludes
到八點半  我再多吃幾片
and pretty much lost all my motor skills.
這時我差不多就走不動道了
This was the drool phase.
這是口水橫流階段
By 10:00, I didn't know who or what the fuck I was.
到十點  我就完全不知道我是誰了
The amnesia phase.
這是記憶喪失階段
We boarded the plane just before midnight.
我們在午夜之前登機
Wow! Look at you!
媽呀  瞧瞧
- You're beautiful. - Excuse me, sir.
-好個美人兒  -請別這樣  先生
His sleeping pills just kicked in. He's all right.
他安眠藥的藥勁上來了  他沒事的
May I see your boarding passes, sir?
能出示一下登機牌嗎  先生
We have the boarding passes.
我們當然有登機牌
Jesus Christ, I wanna fuck her.
向老天發誓  我真想干她
Hey! Fucking relax.
干嘛呢  輕點
Oh, my God! You got your hand on my fucking cock!
老天  快把你的爪子從我的老二上拿開
Cut it out.
別鬧了
He's got his hand on my dick again.
你看他還到處亂摸
I'm just trying to buckle you up.
我這是給你系安全帶
You got your hand on his dick?
你摸著他老二了嗎
You gotta stop doing that in public places.
大庭廣眾的可控制著點啊
Oh, my God. Take it off!
我的天  放手
Take it off!
快放手
I heard there's a treasure map under here.
我聽說你頭發里有藏寶圖呢
Stop!
住手
- Excuse me, sir. - I know, miss.
-抱歉  先生  -我知道  女士
Please sit down.
請您坐下
- Watch it. - Go back to your seat, please.
-管好他  -請做回您的座位去
- What are you upset about? - Please go back to your seat.
-你不高興個什么勁啊  -請您坐回去
I will have to call the captain.
否則我要通知機長了
Please, sir, please, sir. Sit down.
先生  請您坐回去
Please sit down!
坐回去
- I'm going! Stop. - Okay, sorry.
-我這就去  別說了  -抱歉
We apologize. We're gonna go to sleep.
我們抱歉  我們這就睡覺去
Question. I wanna ask you a question.
提問  我要求提問
Fasten your seat belt, sir.
系好您的安全帶  先生
We cannot take off if you haven't fastened
您不系好安全帶我們就
- your seat belt. - I'm really horny, too.
-沒法起飛  -我真想爽一發啊
Sit down. Fasten it.
坐好  系上安全帶
- Right. Okay, I'll sit down... - I will do it for you.
-那好  我這就坐  -我來給您系
- What? - I'll do it for you.
-說啥  -我幫您系
You gotta speak English.
說人話啊  姑娘
We don't understand this language you're speaking.
您這異域風情的口音我們聽不懂
I will help him with his seat belt.
我要幫他系上安全帶
- You gotta put it on right. - Sit back. Sit back, sir.
-你得讓他坐正  -坐好  坐好先生
- There you go. - All right. I'll just lean back...
-這就對了  -我只要倚著就行啦
Bitte, Hilfe!
快來幫忙
- Hilfe! - Hilfe!
-來幫忙  -來幫忙喲
Jesus Christ!
可惡
Fuck!
該死
Donnie...
唐尼
Donnie, this isn't funny. You gotta untie me, buddy.
唐尼  這不好玩  快給我解開
I can't untie you.
不行啊
The captain tied you up. He almost fucking tasered you.
機長綁的你  再不然他就要用電棍了
Why?
為什么
it's not you, sweetheart, don't beat yourself up.
不怪你  親愛的  別怪你自己
Easy, easy. He's fine. He's just a nervous flyer.
別緊張  他沒事  他只是怕坐飛機
You were screaming at people.
你沖別人大喊大叫
Oh, fuck off.
不是吧
You were on the floor rolling around and shit.
你在地板上滿地打滾
Oh, Jesus.
我的天
You called the captain the N-word.
你管機長叫什么奴
I called the captain the N-word?
我這么叫他了嗎
- Yeah, he was very upset. - Really?
-他非常不高興  -是嗎
- Luckily we're in first class. - Jesus.
-還好我們在頭等艙  -我的天
Jesus Christ, I think you have a fucking drug problem.
我說你是不是嗑藥上癮了
Where are the ludes? Where are the ludes?
藥在哪  到底在哪
They're up my ass. Don't worry about it.
我藏得好好的  別緊張
- I got it. - Okay.
-都弄好了  -那就好
Thank God.
那就好
Jesus Christ, what are we
我的天  等我們
gonna do when we get to Switzerland, buddy?
到了瑞士可怎么辦啊  哥們
This is bad.
大事不妙了
Fucking things are against my chest. I can't breathe.
這破玩意兒綁這么緊  我喘不過氣來了
Come on, do something to calm me down. Please.
幫幫忙  撫慰撫慰我  求你了
Okay, shut the fuck up. Shut the fuck up.
好好  你先閉嘴  先閉嘴
Okay.
好吧
- That's good. - Go to sleep.
-真舒服  -睡吧睡吧
Rub it harder, buddy.
使點勁  哥們
You're all right.
你是好寶貝
We all love you. Shut the fuck up!
我們都愛你  閉上嘴
Mr. Belfort, you're free to go.
貝爾福先生  你可以走了
Really?
真的嗎
- Hey, Donnie. - Yeah?
-跟你說  唐尼  -咋了
When we get out there, try not to act like yourself.
等我們到了那邊  你注意點你自己
Okay? Let's make Geneva an asshole-free Donnie zone, all right?
到了日內瓦就別混犯渾了  可以嗎
What are you fucking coming at me for?
你沖著我來干什么
Hey, listen. The only reason you're sitting in this limo
聽著  你現在坐在加長豪車而不是
and not in a Swiss jail is because of my friend. Okay?
瑞士監獄里必須感謝我朋友  懂嗎
Hilfe!
幫個忙
- We're here. We're here. - Everyone calm down.
-到了到了  -大家伙穩著點
Jordan Belfort!
喬丹·貝爾福
At last.
您終于來了
Nicholas has told me so much about you.
我從尼古拉斯那聽到了您的許多壯舉
Jordan, Jean Jacques Saurel.
喬丹  這位是簡·雅克·索雷爾
- Pleasure to make your acquaintance. - Nice to meet you.
-很高興認識您  -幸會幸會
It's a joke.
您說笑了
You'll understand when you're in the fucking seat.
你只要坐一坐就知道是什么感覺了
You need a bigger couch. For guests.
你需要大點的沙發  待客用的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I don't understand. I'm sorry.
哈哈  哈哈  我還是沒懂  抱歉
I'm curious about your bank secrecy laws here.
我對你們國家的銀行保密法很感興趣
Wait. Yes. Excusez-moi, Jordan.
等下  那個  抱歉喬丹
Swiss custom requires 10 minutes of...
瑞士人待客總是得先來十分鐘
Blah, blah, blah.
這個那個的
- Chit chat. - Yeah, chit chat, thank you.
-閑聊  -對就是閑聊  多謝
...before business can be discussed.
然后再談正事
Yeah.
是吧
Of course.
那好
Let's get down to it. What would you like to know?
那咱們就說正事  您想了解些什么
Under what circumstances would you be obligated
在什么情況下  你們有義務
to cooperate with an FBI
和聯邦調查局
or a U.S. Justice Department investigation, for example?
或者美國司法部之類的部門合作
Ca depend.
看情況
Ca depend?
還得看情況
Oui.
沒錯
Ca depend on what, exactly?
具體看什么情況
Whether America plans to invade Switzerland
看美國人接下來幾個月會不會
in the coming months.
占領瑞士
Shall I check if tanks are rolling down the Rue de la Croy?
要不要我去看看十字架上有沒有跑坦克
- Yes. Rue de la Croix. - Croix. Croix.
-那是十字街  -對對  十字街
Not Croy. Not Rue de la Croy. It's Croix.
是街不是架  還"十字架"  是街啦
See, this is what he used to do back in law school. Check me.
我們在法學院常玩這個來著  不信你看
- Champagne. Champagne. - Yeah.
-是香檳還是香崩  -沒錯
Yeah, yeah. French fries, pommes frites.
沒錯  還有炸薯條和炸洋芋
- And that kind of stuff. - That's funny.
-總之這類的  -逗出鳥來了
What I'm asking, you Swiss dick,
我問的是  你這瑞士廢柴
is are you going to fuck me over?
你會不會事后坑我
I understand perfectly, you American shit.
我當然聽明白了  你個美國白癡
The only way the Banque Real de Geneve
外國司法部門能夠獲得
would cooperate with a foreign legal body
日內瓦銀行合作的唯一情況
is if the crime being pursued is also a crime in Switzerland.
就是他們指控的罪名在瑞士也同樣違法
But there are very few Swiss laws which apply to your practices.
但只有很少的瑞士法律涉及您從事的業務
From a financial standpoint,
從金融角度講
you are now in heaven.
您現在身處天堂了
See, I told you he was fantastic, right?
我就說他很厲害吧
If the U.S. Justice
如果美國司法部
Department sent us a subpoena, it would become
發傳票給我們  我們會只當它
papier toilette.
是廁紙
We would wipe our ass with it.
擦屁股用的
Unless, of course, it was an investigation
當然  除非他們是要調查
into stock fraud,
股票詐騙
which is a crime here in Switzerland, if I'm correct.
我沒記錯的話  這在你們瑞士也是犯罪
Then there would have to be cooperation on your part,
這樣的話你們將有義務與他們合作
- if I'm not mistaken. - Yes.
-如果我沒說錯的話  -當然
Yes, we would.
當然會合作
Assuming the account is under your name.
如果賬戶是在你名下的話
If it were another name,
但如果不是你的名字
a friend's, camarade...
是你的朋友  令親之類的
Cousin?
表親嗎
Cousin, absolute.
表親  肯定也行
- Relative? - Yeah.
-你是說親戚  -沒錯
Was that yodeling I just heard
你剛才那是哼小調
or did you just say what I thought you said?
還是我所理解的那個意思
Yes. Yes.
就是那個意思
He's telling me to use a fucking rathole.
他這是在建議我建個老鼠倉
But a U.S. rathole would never get
但一只美國老鼠絕對沒法
into Switzerland with all that money.
把那么多錢弄到瑞士來
What I needed was a rathole with a European passport.
我還得找個有歐洲護照的老鼠
Jordan.
喬丹
Hey. How's my favorite aunt, huh?
你好啊  我最親愛的姨媽
Welcome. Was the traffic terrible?
歡迎  路上沒堵車吧
Oh, no, not at all.
沒有  當然沒有
Jordan, come in.
喬丹  快進來
Thank God Aunt Emma didn't need too much convincing.
還好說服艾瑪姨媽沒費多少勁
Turned out the British weren't too different from the Swiss.
看來英國人跟瑞士人差別也沒那么大嘛
Money talks and bullshit takes the bus.
只要錢跟上  一切就迎刃而解了
How do you say "Rathole" In British?
英式英語里"老鼠倉"怎么說
If you get into any trouble whatsoever,
一旦你碰上任何麻煩
I'll come forth immediately. I'll say that I duped you.
我就會馬上站出來  承認是我騙了你
That I promise.
我保證
Risk is what keeps us young, isn't it, darling?
冒險尤其能讓人倍感青春  是吧親愛的
Sometimes I wonder
有時我禁不住想
if you let money get the best of you, my love.
你是不是讓錢給拿住了  親愛的
Among other substances.
以致忽視了其他種種
It's that obvious, huh?
這么明顯啊
It's chilly, darling, and you're sweating bullets.
天氣一點都不熱  但你卻直冒汗
What can I say? I'm...
我該怎么說呢
I'm a drug addict.
我是個癮君子
I really am.
癮頭非常大
Cocaine, pills,
白粉  搖頭丸
whatever it is, I'll fucking do it.
這個那個  我都嗑
Now that's the truth.
這是實情
I mean...
我是說
I'm a sex addict, too.
我還有性癮
Well, there are worse things to be addicted to than sex.
這世上肯定還有比性癮更危險的事
Jesus, why am I telling you all this? Why am I...
天啊  我跟你說這些干什么  我干嘛
I'm sorry.
真抱歉
Because I'm very easy to talk to.
因為我是個很好說話的人
You are. You are easy to talk to.
還真是  你的確很好說話
I suppose it's...
在我看來
Just my job, you know.
這是我的責任
All these people dependent on me.
有這么多人依仗著我
Tens of millions of dollars at stake, you know.
事關數以千萬計的美金  你懂的
Sometimes I feel like I...
但有時我又覺得
I've bitten off more than I can chew, you know.
我有點貪多嚼不爛了
You're a man with large appetites.
但你的胃口很大
Yeah.
是啊
Is she fucking hitting on me?
這姐們是在挑逗我嗎
Yeah, I am.
還真是這樣
I suppose I put that on myself though, right?
看來是我自作自受了哈
My decision.
我自己的決定
It's just hard to...
有時候很難
Hard to learn to control the anxiety sometimes, you know?
很難控制內心的焦慮  你懂嗎
You know, to...
就是那個
learn to relax and let go and...
試著放松  放下心事
to release the tension.
去釋放壓力嗎
She is hitting on me.
她還真在挑逗我
Holy shit!
我的天啊
Yeah, to release the tension.
沒錯  釋放壓力
I suppose we...
看來我們都得
We all just need to learn...
都得試著做到
learn to do what comes naturally in life, you know?
順其自然  對吧
Is he fucking hitting on me?
這哥們他媽是不是在挑逗我
Stability, dear.
穩住  親愛的
Family.
我們是親戚
You take care of my niece, my love.
你照顧好我的侄女  親愛的
I'll take care of everything over here.
這邊放心交給我
Deal.
成交
Come on! There you go.
爽  真他媽爽
We had, literally, a fuckload of money.
我們貨真價實地干了千金一炮
Aunt Emma could never carry all this by herself.
艾瑪自己可運不了這么多錢
So I thought to myself, who else has a European passport?
我就琢磨  還有誰有歐洲護照
Brad, you're making this too fucking tight!
布拉德  你捆得太緊了
Now Brad, as a successful drug dealer,
而布拉德作為一個成功的藥販子
spent his winters in the south of France,
每年冬天都要在法國南部度假
which is where he met his wife, Chantalle,
在那里他遇見了他的妻子  仙黛爾
a stripper of Slovenian origin
她本是斯洛文尼亞的脫衣舞女
born, in of all places,
正好就出生在
Switzerland.
瑞士
Well, this is fucked.
這根本就成不了
No shit.
成了才怪
Like, this will take her like 50 trips.
她怎么著得跑50趟吧
I know.
我知道
Let me ask you something?
不如這么著吧
What about her family? Right?
她不是還有家人嗎
I mean, they all got Swiss passports, right.
他們人人都有瑞士護照
She's got parents, she's got a brother, right?
她有父母  有兄弟  是不是
The brother's got a wife. That's five fucking people.
他兄弟還有個老婆  這就是五個人了
Six, seven trips, boom, right?
頂多六七趟  是吧
They're all fucking Swiss nitwits like her.
他們跟她一樣都是瑞士的蠢貨
- They'll do it. - We could do that.
-他們會同意的  -沒準能行
At least I have a family, you crooked-nose fuck!
至少我還有家人  你個大鼻子蠢貨
Hey, don't forget about my money.
別忘了我的錢
I'm sorry, what's that?
抱歉你說啥
Yeah, I forgot to tell you. He's got some...
我忘了提了  他也有
- He's got some money. - My money.
-也有些錢要運  -我的錢
I got a couple of mil coming in like a week.
我一周之內要進個幾百萬的
When it gets in, I'll give you a call, you come pick it up.
錢進賬 我給你電話  你來取
You give me a call?
你還給我打電話
When it gets here,
等錢來了
I'll give you a call and you'll come pick it up.
我給你打電話  你來取
Well, we don't fucking work for you, man!
我們又不給你干活  老兄
Sweetheart, you have my money taped to your tits.
親愛的  你奶子上貼的全是我們的錢
Okay? Technically, you do work for me.
明白嗎  說白了  你就是給我干活的
Hey, Jordan, we're gonna need to talk.
喬丹  我得跟你談談
If I fucking do this, I'm telling you right now,
我他媽不干這個  我跟你明說了吧
I ain't going to him, okay.
我才不會去找他
- I'm not a fucking shvartze. - I got it.
-我又不是給他跑腿的  -我懂
I don't do fucking pickups, all right?
我不干上門取件的事  明白嗎
- I got it. - Well, listen to me.
-我明白  -你聽好了
We meet someplace that I fucking say.
我說在哪碰頭就在哪
And you tell that fucking piece of shit,
然后你告訴那個死胖子
- he comes correct. - I will.
-過時不候  -我會說的
He comes in all fucking loopy and fucked up, I swear to God
他敢闖一丁點亂子  我發誓
I'll mash that douchebag's teeth in.
我把丫的牙打回牙床子里去
You're gonna mash whose fucking teeth in?
你他媽要打誰的牙床子
Whose fucking teeth are you gonna mash in?
咱倆玩玩看誰打誰的牙床子
I put the money on that fucking table! Not you!
你那破桌子上堆的是我的錢  不是你的
I'm the reason we have this whole fucking deal!
要不是老子  你他媽能有今天
- He's got a gun, you fucking idiot! - Fuck his gun!
-他有槍  白癡  -操他媽的槍
I put that money in there!
那堆錢是我的
You know what? You're a fucking pill dealer.
你他媽逼就是個藥販子
I got five more just like you, bro.
像你這種人我一撈一大把
Keep talking, you fucking piece of shit!
繼續說啊  你他媽的狗雜種
You know what else? You dress like shit!
你他媽逼穿得也像坨屎
So fuck you!
操死你丫的
- Fucking motherfucker! - Oh! Jesus!
-王八操的  -老天
How about that, faggot? Who's a faggot?
爽不爽  你個操屁眼的  看誰是基佬
You okay? Hey, pal.
你還好吧  兄弟
The next day, Aunt Emma flew to Geneva.
第二天  艾瑪姑媽飛去了日內瓦
Two million in cash in her carry-on,
帶了兩百萬美元現金
which in the big picture was a drop in the Swiss bucket.
對瑞士那邊來說可是九牛一毛
'Cause the following month,
因為在接下來的一個月里
over the course of six round trips,
往返歐洲六趟
Chantalle's family and
仙黛爾的親戚朋友
friends smuggled in over 20 million in cash
毫無閃失地將兩千萬美元現金
without even a hiccup.
偷運進了瑞士
- And I have some more. - Really?
-這還有呢  -是嗎
- Here. - Oh, thank you.
-給你  -噢  謝謝
And here.
還有
- Welcome. - Welcome?
-歡迎光臨  -歡迎光臨
Yeah, like four bags of it.
一共四大包
Are you Swiss-Slovakian or Swiss-Slovenian?
斯洛伐克瑞士還是斯洛文尼亞瑞士
- Slovenian. - Slovenian?
-斯洛文尼亞  -斯洛文尼亞
Who cares. You're blonde.
管它呢  反正你是金發美女
Oh, stop.
討厭啦
Shit.
我操
Just put the fucking car in park,
你就不能把車停好嗎
you dumb fucking idiot!
你個傻逼
I can't close this briefcase.
這個箱子怎么合不上
One fucking day.
有一天
One fucking day, you couldn't keep it together?
你能不能別嗑藥  哪怕一天
I'm fucked up, Brad.
我磕嗨了  布拉德
- Gotta be fucking kidding me. - Fucked up.
-你他媽沒開玩笑吧  -真磕嗨了
- It's a joke. - It's a joke?
-我開玩笑的  -什么
- I'm sober. - Jesus fucking Christ!
-我好著呢  -我操
It's a fucking joke.
我他媽騙你呢
- Are you fucking stupid? - I'm not stupid.
-你他媽傻啊  -我不傻
You fucking drive in here like a fucking maniac,
你車開的歪七扭八的
you know the attention that that fucking draws?
引來多少注意你知道嗎
- I'm not stupid. I'm smart. - Smart?
-我不傻  我很聰明  -聰明
- I make million-dollar deals. - That right.
-我一單生意就幾百萬  -沒錯
With smart important people, unlike you.
還是和聰明的重要人物做的  不像你
People who don't sucker-punch people when they're scared. Okay?
他們不會因為怕了就動手打人  明白嗎
- I'm scared, huh? - And by the way,
-你是說我怕了  -順便還有
I haven't gotten an apology yet for that.
你還沒給我一個道歉呢
You want an apology, okay.
你想要我道歉  是吧
I check my fucking messages every day
我每天下班后
- when I come home from work. - Did you?
-都他媽要查下收件箱  -是嗎
- My answering machine. Zero. - Didn't get one, huh?
-還有答錄機  都是空的  -沒有嗎
I got a blinking light,
我還設置了閃光提醒
because I don't have shit from you.
因為你屁都沒跟我吭一聲
You know what, you got a big fucking mouth, okay?
你這張欠扇的嘴
I got my wife checking the messages
我叫我老婆隨時候著
every 45 minutes calling the office, saying,
每45分鐘給我辦公室打個電話  問我
"Has Brad apologized yet?"
"布拉德道歉了嗎"
"Is there an apology message on the machine?"
"答錄機上有留言嗎"
I don't have jack shit. You know what?
我又不是傻的  你知道嗎
That's not how you treat people.
你不能這樣對別人
You got a big fucking mouth, you know.
你這張嘴太欠扇了
I'm gonna give you a fucking pass. Just give me the case.
我不和你計較了  趕緊把包給我
You're gonna give me a pass?
你還不和我計較
Look, it's a figure of fucking speech.
少廢話了行嗎
Oh, my gosh. The Emperor of Fucksville
我的天  操蛋村的村長
came down from Fucksville to give me a pass!
從操蛋村下山來不和我計較了
From Fucksville, huh?
操蛋村是吧
Hey, what are the citizens of Fucksville doing today
那操蛋村的村長今天不在
when their Emperor's gone?
操蛋村村民都干嘛呢
Is it mayhem?
在暴亂嗎
Are people looting and raping?
到處打砸搶燒  強奸婦女嗎
What are all the little fuckheads doing while you're here?
你下山來了那些傻逼都干什么呢
Go fuck yourself! Give me the bag.
操你媽的  把包給我
You back the fuck up.
你他媽站遠點
I'll cause the biggest
你再過來
fucking scene that I've ever caused in my life
我都不知道我今天要干出什么
if you come at me again.
驚天動地的大事了
- You know what? - Just fucking keep it down.
-你知道嗎  -你他媽小聲點
I got...
我覺得
I don't wanna be out of line or anything,
我不是故意要躲著你
but I think you like, like me. Like you...
但我覺得你好像喜歡我
Like when you come at me...
就像你剛靠近我時...
What's the matter with you? What the fuck is...
你今天怎么了  你他媽...
...and you look at me. I swear I just noticed it.
...你的眼神  我發誓我真的看到了
You have like a fucking, like...
你他媽好像...
Like a twinkle. You have like a twinkle.
眨了下眼  你剛才眨了下眼
Are you trying to kiss me, bro?
你是想親我嗎  老兄
Jesus fucking Christ.
我了個操
- What's with you? - I have a... I don't know.
-你怎么了  -我有點  我不知道
- It's not a homophobic thing. - All right...
-也不是我恐同  -好吧
You're just not the one for me, pal.
只是你不是我喜歡的那一型
You know what I mean? It's not...
明白我意思嗎  我不是...
- It's not about that for me, you know. - I've heard enough.
-我不是那種人  -我聽夠了
Please, I'm begging, give me the fucking case.
當我求你  快點把箱子給我
- I'm gonna give you the case. - Give me the case.
-我把箱子給你  -快拿來吧
- You gotta do me one favor. - What's that?
-你要幫我個忙  -什么忙
You gotta take this case, you gotta drive straight home,
你要拿著箱子  直接開車回家
need you to open up the briefcase,
打開箱子
and you take out every single dollar.
拿出每一張鈔票
Don't leave one dollar inside the briefcase.
別留任何一張在箱子里
And once you have it all
當你把錢全拿出箱子
neatly organized outside the briefcase,
整齊擺好后
I need you to take it and I need you to shove it right up
你把它拿起來塞進
your wife's Latvian cunt, you understand?
你老婆的拉脫維亞逼里面  明白了嗎
- My fucking wife! - Chill! Chill, bro.
-你他媽敢罵我老婆  -淡定  兄弟
Fuck. You motherfucking piece of shit!
操你媽  你這個王八蛋
How about now?
現在快去吧
- Go, go! - Fuck!
-快去  快去  -操
Motherfuck! You're fucking dead!
龜孫子  你他媽死定了
Stop! Don't move! Don't move!
站住  不許動  不許動
Stop, or I will blow you the fuck away!
快站住  否則我他媽打爆你的頭
Drop the case! Put your hands in the air!
放下箱子  把手舉起來
Get down.
跪下
Get down on your knees! Get down on your knees!
跪下  跪下
Motherfucker!
我操你媽
Jordan, do I have a surprise for you!
喬丹  我有個驚喜給你
- What's that? - Twenty real Lemmons.
-什么驚喜  -20粒正宗檸檬片
Retired pharmacist's client of mine,
我認識的一個退休藥劑師
they've been in the safe for 15 years.
把它在保險箱放了15年了
Are you fucking kidding me? Lemmons?
你他媽逗我呢  檸檬片
They're gonna knock us on our fucking heads.
這能把咱們的腦袋都爽翻天
When it comes to Quaaludes, the Lemmon 714 was the Holy Grail.
檸檬714就是安眠藥中的戰斗機
- Can you believe it? - Oh, my God.
-你敢相信嗎  -我的老天
I thought they were like a myth.
我以為這只是一個神話
Three times as powerful as anything available today.
這藥比當今市面上的任何一種都要強三倍
Look at these babies.
看看這些寶貝
Boy, Donnie really knew how to celebrate.
唐尼真是懂得怎么慶祝啊
He said he was saving these for a special occasion.
他說這個要留在特別時機再用
Like a birthday, or being clap free,
比如過生日  擊掌慶祝時
or our money arriving safely in Switzerland.
亦或是咱的錢安全抵達瑞士
So that night,
于是當晚
I cleared my schedule and I rid my body
我撇開所有計劃并清除我體內
of anything that could fuck with my high.
任何會影響我爽的東西
It was celebration time.
這是歡慶時刻
Okay.
來吧
Start off with one, see how it goes?
先來一顆  看看怎么樣
My guy says all we'll need is one.
我的藥頭說只能吃一顆
Here you go.
給你
- Salud! - Cheers.
-干杯  -干杯
Maybe if I pull it again, it'll go down.
說不定我再拉一下就會下去了
Steve! Steve!
史蒂夫  史蒂夫
I gotta get out of here!
我要離開這兒
Carl, I think I got it figured out.
卡爾  我搞明白了
It must be one pull for up and two pulls for down.
這個肯定是拉一下朝上拉兩下朝下
Okay.
好吧
Do you feel anything?
有感覺嗎
No.
沒有
It's been 35 minutes.
都35分鐘了
Maybe we've built up a tolerance after all these years, huh?
可能我們磕了這么多年有耐藥性了
This is bullshit!
屁用沒有
My metabolism's pumping. I can't feel shit!
我的新陳代謝飛速運轉  啥感覺也沒有
They're old.
時間太長了
You think they lost their potency, huh?
是不是過期了
Check the bottle!
看下瓶子
January '81.
81年1月
They're fucking duds.
早他媽過期了
Fuck!
操
Let's take...
我們再...
Let's take two more each.
我們再來兩顆
- Jordan. - Yeah, baby.
-喬丹  -怎么了寶貝
What are you two retards doing?
你們倆傻逼干什么呢
We're working out, honey.
我們在健身  親愛的
Well, Bo Dietl's on the phone.
波·迪特爾來電話了
Okay.
知道了
- Okay? - Okay.
-知道了  -嗯
Hey, Bo, what's going on?
波  出什么事了
Jordan, listen to me clearly.
喬丹  仔細聽我說
I cannot talk to you on this phone, I have to talk to you.
我電話上不能和你說  我要和你談談
Get out of here. What's going on?
快出來  出什么事了
Listen to me! Leave the fucking house, Jordan,
聽我說  快他媽離開你家  喬丹
and then call me from a pay phone.
從公用電話上給我打
This is not a fucking joke, Jordan.
我他媽可沒開玩笑  喬丹
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
好好好
- Shit. - What'd he say?
-操  -他說什么
I don't know what the fuck's going on.
我也不知道出什么事了
- I gotta go! - Is everything okay, Jordan?
-我出去一下  -沒事吧  喬丹
The closest pay phone I could get to
離我家最近的公用電話
was at the Brookville Country Club.
在布魯克維爾鄉村俱樂部
It was a real WASP stronghold,
這是一家上流社會大本營
just a mile down the road from my house.
就在離我家一英里遠處
Hey, Bo, what's up, it's me. What's going on?
波  是我  出什么事了
I'm at a pay phone. What's going on?
我在公用電話了  什么事
Listen to me carefully.
仔細聽我說
Please. Your little friend there,
你的朋友
Brad, your little buddy, he's in jail.
布拉德  你的小兄弟  進監獄了
What the fuck's he in jail for?
他為什么進了監獄
- What'd he do? - I don't know what he did.
-他干什么了  -我不知道
My friends in Long Island told me
我長島的朋友告訴我
he got picked up in some fucking shopping mall.
他在一家商場門口被抓了
He got locked up by...
他被關進...
Wait, wait. Did you... Did you say a shopping mall?
等等  你說在商場
- Yeah. - He was with Donnie.
-對  -他和唐尼在一起
He was supposed to deliver some money,
他本來要去幫忙送錢
- then that fucking fat piece of shit... - Listen to me!
-被那死胖子搞砸了...  -聽我說
I gotta go fucking talk to him right now!
我他媽現在就要找他問問
Listen to me! Don't go! Listen to me.
聽我說  千萬別去  聽我的
That guy Denham, that FBI agent guy,
德納姆  那個FBI探員
somebody told me he's got your phones tapped.
有人告訴我他監聽了你的電話
Your office and your home.
還有你辦公室和你家的
Don't talk on the motherfucking phone!
再別他媽用這些電話了
Okay. Fuck! I got it. I got it. I got it.
好了  我操  知道了  知道了
Jordan.
喬丹
You didn't try to bribe this fucking FBI agent, did you?
你沒有要賄賂這個FBI探員吧
No, I didn't try to bribe an FBI agent.
我沒有賄賂他
You think I'm that fucking stupid? No.
我以為你是傻逼啊  沒有
What the fuck did you say? I can't understand you.
你他媽說的什么鳥語  我聽不懂
Say that again.
再說一遍
I said...
我說...
What the fuck are you saying?
你他媽說的什么亂七八糟的
Are you fucking high?
你磕嗨了嗎
Jordan, are you fucking high?
喬丹  你他媽磕嗨了嗎
Jordan, do me a favor, stay where you are.
喬丹  行行好  就呆那兒
Don't get behind the wheel of the car.
不要開車了
I'm gonna send Rocco over to pick you up.
我叫羅科過去接你
Jordan! Jordan!
喬丹  喬丹
After 15 years in storage,
放了15年
the Lemmons had developed a delayed fuse.
檸檬片產生了延遲效果
It took 90 minutes for these little fuckers to kick in.
90分鐘后這些天殺的藥丸才生效
But once they did...
可一旦生效
I mean, I had skipped the tingle phase
我直接跳過了刺痛狀態
and went straight to the drool phase.
進入了流口水狀態
Tell me where you are! Don't fucking drive...
告訴我你在哪  別他媽開...
These little bastards were so strong,
這些小東西藥性太猛了
I discovered a whole new phase.
我發掘了一種全新的感受
The cerebral palsy phase.
腦癱狀態
Come on, stand up!
加油  站起來
Okay, walking's out.
好吧  走路是沒戲了
All right, think, think. What else is there?
想想  再想想  還有什么辦法
Yes! I can crawl. I can crawl like Skylar!
有了  我可以爬  像斯凱拉那樣爬
Fuck! The kid makes it look so goddamn easy!
操  小孩爬起來那么容易
Think, you motherfucker, think!
想  操他丫的  再想想
Yes!
有了
I got it! I've got it!
想到了  想到了
I can roll! I can roll!
我可以滾  我可以滾
Jordan.
喬丹
Oh, Jesus. Where are you?
老天  你人呢
I'm at a country club!
我在鄉村俱樂部
What?
在哪
I don't know what the fuck you're saying.
我他媽聽不懂你說的什么
Look, you need to get home.
你趕緊回家來
Donnie is out of control! He's on the other line
唐尼已經失控了  他在另外一條線上
with some Swiss guy. I don't know...
和一瑞士男在打電話  我不認識
What?
什么
Get him off the phone!
別讓他打電話
I can't understand you!
我聽不懂你說什么
Get him
不要
off
讓他
the phone!
打電話
I don't know what the fuck you're saying, Jordan.
我他媽聽不懂你說的什么  喬丹
Can you just get home? Hurry!
你能回來嗎  快點
I was less than a mile from home.
我離家還不到一英里
I drove as slow as I fucking could.
我盡量慢慢開
I'd seen Jell-O move faster.
連果凍滑得都比我快
I was gonna give you two million.
我本來要再給你兩百萬
I's gonna be lates.
我要吃[遲]一些了
You ate two million?
你吃了兩百萬
Later.
遲
Get off the phone.
放下電話
Get off the fucking phone! Idiot!
放下那天殺的電話  傻逼
Get out of the way, asshole!
別擋路  蠢驢
You hate two million?
你恨兩百萬
No, you don't hate two million, Donnie.
你可不能恨兩百萬  唐尼
By some miracle, I made it home alive,
奇跡般地  我活著回到了家
not a scratch on me or the car.
我和車都沒有蹭到
Jordan?
喬丹
Jesus fucking Christ!
我了個大操
What did you take?
你吃什么了
What's wrong with you?
你有毛病啊你
Jor!
喬
It's fucking good, right?
爽歪歪了對吧
Fucked up!
閉嘴
Get off the phone!
放下電話
What the fuck, Jordan?
你搞什么  喬丹
Your daughter's in the house!
你女兒在家呢
I hope you know that!
你最好弄清楚
Your fucking daughter's in the house!
他媽的你女兒在家呢
Yeah, it's real fucking funny, Donnie.
太他媽好玩了  唐尼
Get off the phone!
放下電話
Jesus Christ, Jordan.
天啊  喬丹
The FBI!
有FBI
Hey!
嘿
I'm on phone!
我正打著呢
Get off the fucking phone!
你媽逼快放下電話
Come here! ...the phone.
快過來...  給我
Come on. We're gonna go upstairs, all right.
來  我們上樓去
I'm on the phone!
我正打著呢
On the phone!
正打著呢
I know what you did,
我知道你干的好事
you piece of shit!
你個王八操的
What? What?
什么  什么
Brad!
布拉德
You fucking cocksucker!
你個吸雞巴的
What did you do,
你都干了些什么好事
you piece of shit?
你個垃圾
Fuck you!
操你媽
I wanna fucking kill you!
我他媽宰了你
I got you!
抓住你了
What the fuck happened?
這他媽怎么回事
Oh, shit!
我操
Jordan? Jordan, are you all right?
喬丹  喬丹  你還好嗎
Donnie? Donnie?
唐尼  唐尼
Donnie?
唐尼
Jordan, he's not breathing.
喬丹  他上不來氣了
Oh, fuck, I don't know what to do.
哦操  我不知道該怎么辦
Jordan, I don't know what the fuck to do!
喬丹  我不知道該怎么辦
I can't help him! Oh, my God. Jordan.
我幫不了他了  我的天  喬丹
Oh, my God, I think he's choking, Jordan. Do something.
天吶  他嗆住了  喬丹  快來幫忙
- Oh, God. - Baby, I got you!
-天啊  -寶貝  我來了
He's not breathing, Jordan. You gotta do something!
他沒氣了  喬丹  你快來幫忙啊
Shit! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
操  天啊  我的天啊
I got you.
我來了
Step aside!
靠邊站
Oh, God!
老天啊
Move aside, baby.
靠邊站  寶貝
Come on! Come on!
快點  快點
Come on!
來啊
Jordan, he's not breathing. You gotta do something.
喬丹  他沒呼吸了  快想點辦法啊
Jordan, he's a father! He's got fucking kids!
喬丹  他還有家有孩子呢
- Do something! - Yeah?
-快想點辦法  -好
Rocco, you gotta get over here.
羅科  快過來
- Come on. - Call an ambulance!
-來啊  -快叫救護車
I don't fucking know!
我他媽也不知道
Just get over here! Call 911.
趕快過來報警
You all right? He's all right.
你還好吧  他沒事了
Mr. Belfort?
貝爾福先生
Get the fuck out of here. Fuck.
滾出去  滾
Sir, we need to ask you some questions.
先生  我們需要問你幾個問題
Are you fucking kidding me? Fuck you.
你他媽開玩笑吧  去你媽
Come on, get up.
來吧  站起來
Get the fuck out of my house.
滾出我的房子
- Let's go. - I've been here all night.
-走吧  -我整晚都在這兒
I been sitting here all night.
整晚都坐在這兒
What the fuck are you talking about?
你們他媽什么意思
- Where you taking him? - Where you taking me?
-你們帶他去哪兒  -你們帶我去哪兒
Where you taking him?
你們帶他去哪兒
You ain't got no warrant.
你們又沒有搜查證
Just come up in people's house like that!
怎么能隨便到別人家里來
Did you drive your car tonight, Mr. Belfort?
你今晚開過你的車嗎  貝爾福先生
Well?
怎么說呢
Maybe I hadn't made it home okay.
看來我并沒有安然無恙地到家
Get out of the fucking way!
快他媽讓開
Fuck!
我擦
Did you drive that car tonight?
你今晚開過這輛車嗎
- Yeah. - Yeah, right.
-有  -好的
I'm a family man!
我可是有家室的
Family man. Honey!
有家室的  親愛的
It was a miracle I wasn't killed,
我沒把自己撞死
or that I didn't kill anybody else.
或者撞死別人真是個奇跡
The cops took me in for questioning, but they couldn't charge me.
警察帶我去問了話  但他們沒法起訴我
They had no proof I was even behind the wheel.
他們沒法證明我開了車
Meanwhile,
與此同時
Brad did three months in jail for contempt,
布拉德因為蔑視法庭坐了三個月牢
because he wouldn't rat Donnie out.
因為他不肯供出唐尼
The result, I was scot-free.
結果就是  我安然無恙
But I had eyes on me like never before.
但我也受到了前所未有的監視
You're a lucky man, Jordan.
你真是走運  喬丹
You're lucky to be alive, let alone not in jail.
居然能活著  還不用坐牢
You know I don't believe in luck, right?
你知道我不相信運氣的  對吧
But it's time.
但是是時候了
Please, let me call the SEC and cut a deal
拜托讓我跟證監會談好條件
before your luck runs out.
在你運氣用光以前
Wave to Daddy.
跟爸爸揮揮手
Hey.
嗨
Hey, sweetie.
你好啊  甜心
What kind of terms would you be talking about if I...
都有什么條件  如果我...
I don't know.
這很難說
You plead guilty to a handful of securities violations,
你得坦白一些違反證券規則
stock manipulation, high-pressure sales tactics.
操縱股價  高壓銷售
Ticky-tack shit like that, you know.
都是這樣的小罪  你懂的
You pay a couple million dollars in fines,
你得付幾百萬的罰款
in exchange, the SEC fucks off till the end of time.
作為交換  證監會永遠不會再煩你
And Stratton?
那斯特拉頓呢
What happens to Stratton?
斯特拉頓會怎么樣
There's no way... I mean... You got to walk away. Right?
沒別的辦法...你必須收手  對吧
Let Donnie be in charge.
讓唐尼管事就行
Right. Donnie.
沒錯  唐尼
Now the FBI is another animal completely.
FBI可沒那么好對付
They'll still be pursuing you for criminal wrongdoing.
他們會繼續追查你的犯罪行為
However, with you stepping down voluntarily,
不過  只要你自愿離職
my guess is that your best friend Agent Denham
我猜你的好朋友德納姆探員
will be standing around with his dick in his hand.
也就無計可施了
Jordan.
喬丹
What do you have to think about?
你還有什么好考慮的
You beat them.
你打敗了他們
You won!
你贏了
God knows you never have to work again.
你一輩子都不用工作了
What're you gonna do? Spend the rest of your life in jail?
你還想怎么樣  在牢里度過余生嗎
- Is that what you want? - No.
-你想那樣嗎  -不想
- Of course not. - Okay.
-當然不想  -那不就得了
Okay! You got all the money in the world.
你已經掙了全世界的財富
You need everybody else's money?
難道還想把所有人的錢都掙光嗎
- Of course not, Pops. - Well?
-當然不是  爸  -所以啊
- You know, I built it. - I know you built it.
-可這是我一手創造的  -這我知道
You built it, so now preserve it.
你創造了這些  現在你得保住它們
You know,
你知道
five years ago, when I started Stratton Oakmont
五年前  當我和唐尼·亞速一起創立
with Donnie Azoff, I knew the day
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特的時候  我就知道
would eventually come where I'd have to be moving on.
總有一天我要離開這里
And it's truly with a heavy heart that I'm here to say that...
現在我非常沉重地宣布...
That that day is finally here.
那一天終于來了
I wanna... I want to thank you all for your...
我想...我想謝謝你們所有人
Your years of loyalty and admiration.
謝謝你們多年的忠誠與敬仰
But the point is this.
但重點是
Under Donnie's leadership,
在唐尼的領導下
along with Nicky Koskoff and Robbie Feinberg
再加上尼基·克斯考夫和羅比·范伯格
moving into key management positions,
加入領導層
this place really, is gonna be better than ever!
這里只會比原來更好
That I promise you. Okay?
我保證  好嗎
Give them a round of applause. Come on.
為他們鼓掌吧  來吧
This is Ellis Island here, people.
這里就是埃利斯島  各位
I don't care who you are, where you're from,
我不管你是誰  從哪里來
whether your relatives came over on the fucking Mayflower
不管你的祖先是坐他媽的五月花號
or on an inner tube from Haiti,
還是從海蒂坐輪胎漂過來的
this right here is the land of opportunity.
這里就是你的希望之地
Stratton Oakmont is America!
斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特就是美利堅
All of you know Kimmie Belzer, right?
你們都認識幾米·貝爾澤吧
Yes, we do.
是的
Fuck you.
去你的
Come on, Kimmie.
別這樣  幾米
What you probably didn't know is,
你們可能不知道的是
Kimmie was one of the first brokers here,
幾米是這里最早的經紀人之一
one of Stratton's original 20.
斯特拉頓最初的二十名員工之一
Now most of you met Kimmie,
你們大部分人認識的幾米
the beautiful sophisticated woman that she is today.
是現在這個美麗優雅的女性
A woman that wears $3,000 Armani suits.
穿著三千塊的阿瑪尼套裝
Who drives a brand-new Mercedes-Benz.
開著嶄新的奔馳
A woman who spends her winters in the Bahamas,
冬天在巴哈馬度假
and summers in the Hamptons!
夏天在漢普頓避暑
That's not the Kimmie that I met.
我遇到的幾米可不是這樣的
The Kimmie that I met didn't have two nickels to rub together.
我遇到的幾米身無分文
She was a single mom on the balls of her ass
她是個窮困潦倒的單親母親
with an eight-year-old son.
有個八歲的兒子
Okay? She was three months behind on her rent.
她已經欠了三個月的房租
And when she came to me and asked me for a job,
她來我這兒找工作的時候
she asked for a $5,000 advance,
只想要五千塊的預付工資
just so she could pay her son's tuition.
來付她兒子的學費
And what'd I do, Kimmie?
我是怎么做的  幾米
Go on, tell them.
告訴他們
You wrote me a check
你給我寫了一張
for $25,000.
兩萬五千塊的支票
That's right.
沒錯
Thank you.
謝謝你
And you know why that is?
你知道我為什么這么做嗎
It's because I believed in you.
因為我相信你
It's because I believed in you, Kimmie,
因為我相信你  幾米
just like I believe in each and every one of you here today.
就像我相信今天在場的每一位
- I fucking love you, Jordan! - I fucking love you.
-我他媽愛你  喬丹  -我他媽愛你
I fucking love you! I love you.
我他媽愛你  我愛你
I fucking love you, too! I fucking love you, too!
我他媽也愛你 我他媽也愛你
And I love all of you!
我愛你們所有人
And I love all of you from the bottom of my heart.
我從心底愛你們所有人
- I fucking love you, too. - I mean that.
-我他媽也愛你  -真心的
You are the shit. You are the fucking shit.
你最屌  你他媽最屌了
It's a shame, you know.
真是諷刺啊
For years, I've been telling
這么多年來  我一直告訴你們
you guys never to take no for an answer, right?
不要接受別人的拒絕  對吧
You know, to keep pushing, to never hang up the phone
繼續努力  不要掛下電話
until you get what you want.
知道你得到你想要的
Because you all deserve it.
因為那是你應得的
You know, this fucking deal that I'm about to sign,
而我就要簽的那個混蛋協議
barring me from the securities industry,
禁止我參與證券行業
barring me from Stratton,
禁止我進入斯特拉頓
my home.
我的家
What the fuck is that, you know?
這他媽算什么啊
I'll tell you what it is. It's...
我來告訴你它是什么  它是...
It's me taking no for an answer, you know.
是我接受別人的拒絕
It's them...
是他們...
It's them selling me, not the other way around.
他們說服了我  而不是反過來
It's me being a hypocrite is what it is.
是我變成了偽君子
So...
所以...
You know what?
你猜怎么著
I'm not leaving.
我不走了
I'm not fucking leaving!
我他媽不走了
You're not getting a fucking promotion!
你他媽升不了職啦
The show goes on!
演出繼續
This is my home!
這是我的家
They're gonna need a fucking wrecking ball
他們得拆了這地方
to take me out of here!
才能把我弄走
They're gonna need to send in the National Guard
讓他們派國民警衛隊來吧
or fucking SWAT team,
或者他媽的特警隊
'cause I ain't going nowhere!
因為我哪兒也不去
Fuck them!
去他們的
Jordy! Jordy!
喬迪  喬迪
Jordy! Get back here!
喬迪  回來
Hey!
喂
Give me that.
給我
What is this?
這算什么
Ramar of the Jungle, for Christ sake?
叢林大狂歡嗎  上帝啊
Paddy D, mazel tov, you Irishman.
帕迪  你走運了  愛爾蘭小子
Jordan Belfort just welched on his deal with the SEC.
喬丹·貝爾福撕毀了和證監會的協議
He is back in the ocean. Happy hunting.
可以繼續追查他了  狩獵愉快
It was our time to party big.
我們開始了盛大的狂歡
And just as Brad was released from jail, too.
正好布拉德也出獄了
I apologized, even offered to pay him for his time in the can.
我道歉  賠他入獄期間的損失
But he said no, that he was out.
但他拒絕了  說他不干了
He didn't want any part of us.
他不想再跟我們有瓜葛
Sad thing was,
可惜的是
two years later he was dead.
兩年后他就死了
Massive heart attack. Thirty-five.
死于心臟病  才35歲
Same age Mozart died.
和莫扎特去世的年齡一樣
Not that they have a hell of a lot in common, but...
他們倒也沒什么共同點  不過...
Anyway, I don't know why that came to mind.
算了  我也不知道怎么會想到這些的
Within days, subpoenas started flying.
沒過幾天  傳票就開始滿天飛
Notices to produce documents, depositions, you name it.
要求出示文件  做口供  應有盡有
Donnie couldn't drink water fast enough.
唐尼都給弄得缺水了
United States government wants to give me a subpoena?
美國政府要給我們傳票
Here's what we do with subpoenas at Stratton Oakmont!
咱們斯特拉頓·奧克蒙特就這么對付傳票
Fuck you, USA! Fuck you!
操你媽的美國  操你媽
Fuck you! Fuck you!
操你媽  操你媽
Fuck you!
操你媽
Jordan Belfort.
喬丹·貝爾福
Alden. That's a nice name.
奧爾登  這名字不錯
Thank you very much for that.
謝謝夸獎
- What kind of name is that? - That is my name.
-這算什么名字  -我的名字
I do not recall that.
我不記得
I do not recall that. Okay?
我不記得  好嗎
Mr. Ming, thank you for coming in today.
明先生  謝謝你能過來
Are you gonna finish the rest of that Danish?
這些點心你們還吃嗎
- Can I have that Danish? - No, no, go ahead.
-我能吃點心嗎  -當然  吃吧
They interrogated everybody.
他們審問了所有人
I got a low blood sugar, thyroid thing.
我血壓低  甲狀腺的問題
It went on for months.
審問持續了幾個月
It was a total fucking harassment.
簡直是在騷擾我們
Tell him to proceed with the questions.
讓他問問題吧
But not a single Strattonite cracked.
但沒有一個斯特拉頓人崩潰
Gladys Carrera?
格拉迪斯·卡雷拉呢
Doesn't ring a bell.
沒印象
Sorry, I have no recommendation of that.
抱歉  無可奉告
No.
沒有
No idea.
沒想法
I don't recall that transaction. You guys have any milk?
我不記得那筆轉賬了  你們有牛奶嗎
Absolutely not.
絕對沒有
Francis Sortigi you called so many times,
你給佛朗西斯·索特吉打了很多通電話
I just thought you might remember that.
我覺得你應該記得
Would you remember any of those?
你記得這些嗎
- I do not recall any of that. - This Abdul...
-我不記得  -這個阿杜卜勒...
I do not... No, I don't recall.
我不...不  我不記得
It was a long phone call.
那通電話打了很久
I just wondered if you have any memory of that.
我想知道你還有沒有印象
Okay. You know we've talked
好了  我們已經
to several of the employees at this firm,
跟這里的好幾名員工談過了
and nobody can recall anything about this Steve Madden IPO.
沒人記得史蒂夫·麥登首次公開募股的事
I think it's odd.
我覺得挺奇怪的
Do you recall Cartage Corporation?
你記得運輸公司嗎
You do recall it?
你記得嗎
No, I don't recall that at all.
不  我完全不記得
Excuse me. I have to ask. Is that your real hair?
抱歉  我想問你的頭發是真的嗎
Are you gonna say anything about that?
你想談這個嗎
Are you gonna comment on my hair?
要對我的頭發品頭論足嗎
Is that how we're doing... Is this personal questions?
我們是來談這些...談私人問題的嗎
I'm just wondering why you would wear something like that.
我只是好奇你的發型
Sorry. I don't recall that company.
抱歉  我不記得那家公司
Can I get you anything else, gentlemen?
還需要什么嗎  先生
Yes. Sweetheart, I have a rare condition
親愛的  我有一種罕見的病
which requires me to drink one of those every 15 minutes, please.
必須每15分鐘喝一杯  拜托了
We were specifically advised not to leave the country.
我們被明確告知不能出國
So, we took our wives to Italy.
所以我們帶著老婆去了意大利
We figured we were safer working from overseas
我們覺得在海外辦公會更安全
giving orders to Rugrat.
只要給魯格拉特下命令就好
Nobody could arrest us and nobody could prove
沒人能逮捕我們  也沒人能證明
I was still running Stratton from a yacht.
我在游艇上操控著斯特拉頓
Hey, Rugrat.
嘿  魯格拉特
Bonjour.
你好啊
You bald-headed eagle, how you doing?
你這禿頭鷹  還好嗎
Donnie, Donnie, listen!
唐尼  唐尼  聽著
We have a problem, okay.
我們有麻煩了
Your friend, Steve Madden, is unloading shares.
你的朋友史蒂夫·麥登正在拋售股份
What are you saying? Who told you that?
你說什么呢  誰告訴你的
- What's going on? - He's doing it, Donnie!
-怎么了  -是真的  唐尼
He said that Steve Madden's unloading shares.
他說史蒂夫·麥登在拋售股份
Who told you that? It's bullshit!
誰跟你說的  真是胡扯
Give me that goddamn phone.
快把電話給我
- What's going on? - Don't listen...
-怎么了  -別聽他的...
Jordan, look. I'm watching the screen
喬丹  聽著  我正盯著屏幕呢
and huge chunks of Steve Madden are being sold, okay.
有大量的史蒂夫·麥登股票被拋售
It's not coming from us, so it's gotta be Steve.
不是我們賣的  所以只能是史蒂夫
He's the only person with that many shares.
只有他有那么多股份
It's Donnie. Call me back, all right.
我是唐尼  打給我  好嗎
Donnie, your little friend is trying to fuck me, you know that.
唐尼  你的小朋友想害我  你知道嗎
Your little friend is trying to fuck me right in the ass.
你的小朋友想害死我
- Get him on the phone now! - We don't know anything yet.
-現在就給他打電話  -我們還不確定
Let's not jump to conclusions.
別急著下結論
Even though I owned 85%
盡管我掌握了百分之八十五的
of Steve-cocksucking- motherfucking-Madden Shoes,
史蒂夫·操蛋·混球·麥登鞋業的股份
the shares were in his fucking name.
但股權都是在他名下的
This motherfucker knew I was in trouble with the feds
這混蛋知道調查局在找我麻煩
and was trying to take advantage.
想要趁火打劫
Talk to me, man. How do you wanna play this?
說話啊  你準備怎么辦
I want you to get all our clients on the phone right now,
我要你現在就打給所有的客戶
and have them start selling Steve Madden.
讓他們開始賣史蒂夫·麥登的股票
We're gonna drive that fucking price down!
我們得把他媽的股價降下來
Do you hear me? Shut the fuck up!
聽到了嗎  你他媽閉嘴
This is your fucking friend from high school.
他是你的高中同學
If that little fucking prick thinks he can fuck with me,
要是那個小混球想弄我
we'll turn his company into a penny stock! You hear me?
我們就把他的公司弄成低價股  懂了嗎
- You got it? - Yes. I got it!
-聽到了嗎  -聽到了
Let's just not jump to
在了解情況之前
conclusions before we know what's going on.
先別急著下結論
Captain Ted!
泰德船長
Hang up your phones! Everybody, hey!
把電話掛了  所有人
Turn the boat around! We're going home!
掉頭  我們回家
Baby! Baby, what happened?
寶貝  寶貝  怎么了
I just...
我...
Sweetheart, what's going on?
親愛的  出什么事了
Aunt Emma...
艾瑪姑姑
Just wait.
等一下
I can't...
我不行
What's going on? Why you crying?
怎么了  你怎么哭了
- She's dead! - Who? Who's dead?
-她死了  -誰  誰死了
I just got a call from my cousin Betty.
我剛接到貝蒂表姐的電話
Yeah?
然后呢
Aunt Emma is dead.
艾瑪姑姑死了
- Are you fucking kidding me? - No.
-你他媽在開玩笑吧  -沒有
You're serious?
你認真的嗎
Oh, my God! Baby, that's...
天啊  寶貝  這真是...
Oh, fuck!
我操
Oh, sweetheart, that's just...
親愛的  真是...
Fucking heart attack!
去你妹的心臟病
Boom, snap, gone.
砰  啪  嗝屁
Shuffled off her mortal coil.
從此遠離塵世
And $20 million stuck in a Swiss bank account.
我的兩千萬困在瑞士的銀行賬戶里了
The last time I talked to her she was fine!
上次見到她  她還好好的呢
- She's not that old. - Oh, God! Baby, oh, God!
-她也沒那么老  -天啊  寶貝
That's so fucking terrible!
太他媽糟糕了
Oh, fuck!
我操
It is terrible.
真是糟糕
Your aunt was such an elegant, attractive woman.
你姨媽是個端莊美麗的女人
My condolences to you and your family.
請接收我對你和你家人的慰問
Yes. We're absolutely devastated.
是啊  我們都崩潰了
Thank you so much for your condolences.
謝謝你的慰問
Now where does that leave us in regard to her account exactly?
那她的賬戶要怎么處理
Does it go into probate or what?
是要被審查還是怎樣
Not to worry, Jordan. Not to worry.
這個你不需要擔心  喬丹
Your aunt, before she died,
你姑姑在死之前
signed a document naming you as her successor.
簽了份文件  任命你為繼承人
She did?
真的嗎
Fantastic! Well, that's good news!
太好了  這是個好消息
Well, not as of yet.
這個嘛  暫時還不是
What does that mean? Not as of yet?
什么叫做暫時還不是
I can't seem to hear you.
我聽不清你說什么
I must have bad reception. Are you speaking English?
這里的信號太差了  你在說英文嗎
- Very... Now. Fast. Very fast. - Fast?
-快  現在  快動身  -快
I have to get to Switzerland now?
我要現在就動身去瑞士嗎
Speak English! Fucking speak English!
說英語  給老子說英語
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey. Hey! Quiet, okay?
安靜點  讓我講完
Take your suit, take your dick, okay, and move your ass! Please.
帶上西裝  帶上小雞雞  給我滾過來
Okay. Move my ass! Yes!
好的  我立刻過去
I gotta say, these Swiss were some sneaky motherfuckers.
我得說  這些瑞士人真夠狡猾
Within minutes, he had me set up with a forger
就在幾分鐘內  他找到了一個
who could fake Aunt Emma's signature.
可以偽造艾瑪姑姑簽名的人
You American shit!
你個美國廢物
I just had to get there by tomorrow, or lose $20 million.
我必須明天前到那里  否則損失兩千萬
We're going to Monaco!
我們要去摩納哥
- Monaco? Now? - Yes, baby.
-摩納哥  現在嗎  -是的  寶貝
We're going to Monaco, so then we can go to Switzerland, okay?
我們先去摩納哥  然后去瑞士
- But her aunt just died. - I realize that.
-但是她的姑姑剛去世  -我知道
But I have business in Switzerland.
但我要去瑞士辦事
I need to go to Switzerland right now.
我必須現在就去瑞士
Bottom line. Sorry.
就這樣定了  抱歉
We gotta get to London.
我們要趕去倫敦
Why? Why?
為什么  為什么
The funeral!
要參加葬禮啊
Yeah, but, babe. Look, look...
寶貝  你聽我說
I loved your aunt more than anyone in the entire world.
我是這世上最愛你姑姑的人
I really did.
我真的很愛她
But she's dead now, sweetie.
但她死了  寶貝
She's dead and she's not going anywhere.
她死了  哪都不能去
She'll still be dead by the time we get to London, okay?
等我們去到倫敦  她依然是死的
Captain Ted! Captain Ted, all right, look.
泰德船長  聽好了
We're going to Monaco. Monaco now, okay?
我們現在改去摩納哥  知道嗎
Monaco, right.
摩納哥  好的
We're going to Monaco so that we can drive to Switzerland
我們先去摩納哥  然后再轉去瑞士
so they don't stamp our passports.
就能免去那些出入境手續了
Take care of business here, we'll drive back to Monaco,
辦完事后  我們再開回摩納哥
take a flight over to London to catch the funeral
坐飛機到倫敦  參加葬禮
and be in New York in three fucking business days!
三個辦事日后回到紐約
That's the fucking plan.
這就是計劃
I just want you to know that we might run into some chop.
我們可能會遇到海上風暴
Chop? We can fucking handle chop, right?
小小的風暴  我們能搞定的吧
I mean, it's a 170-foot yacht.
我們的游艇足足有170英尺長
No, no, no. We're not going
不不不  我們哪兒也不去
anywhere unless he says it's safe, all right.
除非他說安全
- Don't worry about the chop. - It's safe.
-別擔心風暴  -那很安全
You don't know shit about chop.
你壓根就不懂什么是風暴
Oh, really? And you do? You're a fucking expert on that.
就你懂  你什么時候成風暴專家了
I'll chop your fucking credit card in half. How about that?
要不我把你的信用卡額度減半  怎么樣
Chop is fine. Trust me. Chop is fine.
小小的風暴沒事的  相信我
Is chop fine, Captain Ted?
不用擔心風暴  對吧泰德船長
Yeah. I mean, if we take it slow.
如果我們開慢點的話  就不用怕了
Yeah, we're gonna take it slow.
對的  我們開慢點就好了
It's a little uncomfortable. Tell them it's safe.
就是有點不舒適罷了  安全的
It's gonna be safe.
還是安全的
We'll batten down the hatches and secure the deck.
我們把艙口封了  確保夾板安全
And we're looking at a few... maybe a few broken dishes.
可能會打碎幾個碟子
Few broken dishes.
就打碎幾個碟子
What's a few broken dishes?
打碎幾個碟子是什么概念
Does that sound fucking awesome or what?
聽起來很安全嘛  不會有事的
No. Not really.
才不是
We're gonna have a fucking good time!
我們一定會玩得很開心的
Let's go to fucking Monaco now!
讓我們現在就出發去摩納哥
Let's fucking move! Let's go!
趕緊動起來  起程吧
Hold on!
穩住
What the fuck is going on out here?
現在是什么情況
The Jet Skis just went overboard!
摩托艇翻倒在甲板上了
Oh, Jesus Christ! Honey, you okay?
我的天啊  寶貝  你還好嗎
Gale warning! Gale warning!
大風警報  大風警報
The waves are 20 feet high and building!
海浪已升至20英尺高  并持續上升
Turn around, let's go the other fucking way.
掉頭吧  我們走別的路線
- We can't! - Go!
-不行  -掉頭
We'll get broad-sided. It'll tip over!
現在掉頭的話  會翻船的
I am a master diver. You hear that?
我是個潛水大師  你聽到嗎
I'm a master diver!
我是個潛水大師
No one's gonna fucking die!
沒有人會死
I got you, baby. I got you. Trust me, okay?
有我在  寶貝  有我在  相信我
I love you.
我愛你
I love you, baby. Just hold on tight.
我愛你  寶貝  抓緊了
Okay.
好的
Donnie!
唐尼
Hold on, baby!
堅持住  寶貝
- What? - Hold on, baby.
-什么  -堅持住  寶貝
Get the fucking ludes.
把安眠酮拿來
I don't wanna die, Jordan!
我不想死  喬丹
I did a lot of bad shit.
我干了那么多壞事
I'm going to hell, Jordan!
我要下地獄了  喬丹
I fucked up! I fucked up so bad!
我死定了  這次真的死定了
Get the ludes! Downstairs!
到樓下把安眠酮拿來
What are you saying?
你說什么
Fuck!
該死的
Get the ludes!
去把安眠酮拿來
I can't go down there, Jordan. It's flooded.
我下不去  下面被淹了  喬丹
It's three feet of water down there!
下面的水有三尺深
I will not die sober!
我不要清醒得死去
Get those fucking ludes!
把那些該死的安眠酮拿來
Okay!
好的
- Go! - Okay.
-快去  -好的
- Where's he going? - Hold on, baby!
-他要去哪里  -抓緊  寶貝
Donnie! Is he fucking crazy?
唐尼  他瘋了嗎
He's just warning everybody!
他只是去警告其他人
Jesus Christ!
天啊
Hold on!
抓穩了
Get away from the window!
離窗戶遠點
Rogue wave!
大浪要打過來了
Mayday!
求救
This is Captain Ted Beecham aboard the yacht Naomi!
我是內奧米號的船長泰德·比切姆
- We are going down! - I got 'em!
-我們要沉了  -我拿到了
I got 'em!
我拿到了
Give me one for the nerves!
給我一顆  緩解下情緒
We're going down!
我們要沉了
This is a fucking Mayday!
求救  求救
We require immediate assistance!
我們要求立即救援
Hold on!
抓緊了
Watch out!
小心
The nice thing about getting rescued by Italians
被意大利人救起來的好處就是
is that they feed you, make you drink red wine,
他們會喂飽你  給你喝紅酒
then you get to dance.
最后還會跟你跳舞
Did you see that?
你看到了嗎
That was the plane I sent to come get us.
那架飛機是我叫來接我們的
I shit you not, it exploded when a seagull flew into the engine.
你一定想不到  一只海鷗撞上了機翼
Three people killed.
飛機在空中爆炸  死了三個人
You want a sign from God?
你希望上帝給你指引嗎
Well, after all this, I finally got the message.
這次之后  我終于得到了指引
Do you dream of becoming financially independent
你夢想過財政獨立
but struggle every month just to pay your bills?
卻每個月都有還不完的債嗎
Would you like to own a home like this,
你想要擁有這樣一棟房子
but can barely afford to pay your rent?
卻只能勉強付得起房租嗎
My name is Jordan Belfort,
我是喬丹·貝爾福
and there's no secret to wealth creation.
創造財富  并沒有什么秘密
No matter who you are, no matter where you came from,
無論你是誰  來自哪里
you too can become financially independent
都可以在幾個月內
in just a matter of months.
實現財政獨立
All you need is a strategy.
你需要的是一套策略
When I was 24 years old,
在我24歲那年
I made a decision not just to survive, but to thrive.
我做了個決定  我不僅要生存還要發達
At first I didn't feel like deals like these were possible.
一開始  我沒想過這一切會成真
But we have the house and we have a $33,000 profit.
但我們現在有了房子  還掙了三萬三
I certainly believe now.
我現在相信了
Think about it for a second.
好好想想
If you don't have the guts to attend Jordan Belfort's
如果你沒勇氣撥打喬丹·貝爾福熱線
Straight Line Persuasion System Seminar,
參加他們的研討會
then how do you expect to make any money?
又怎么可能創造財富呢
If you want to be a millionaire someday,
如果你想成為百萬富翁
have some guts. Make a decision.
鼓起勇氣  做個決定吧
Jordan Belfort's setup worked for me
喬丹·貝爾福的方案很適合我
because I worked hard for it.
因為我很努力工作
And if it doesn't work for you, it's because you're lazy.
如果對你不起作用  那就證明你太懶了
And you should get a job at McDonald's.
你只配在麥當勞工作
There's nobody holding you back from financial freedom.
沒有人能在財政獨立上拖你后腿
And there's nobody stopping you from making millions.
也沒有人能阻止你掙大錢
Don't just sit at home,
坐在家里  無所事事
or the life of your dreams will sail right past you.
只會讓你想要的生活與你失之交臂
I changed all these people's lives and I can change yours, too!
我改變了這些人的命運  也能改變你的
So come to my seminar!
來參加我的研討會吧
The life of your dreams is only...
你夢想中的生活
Good to see you again, Jordan.
好久不見  喬丹
You're under arrest!
你被逮捕了
You gotta be joking!
開什么玩笑
You're kidding me.
你別開玩笑了
Hey, get the fuck away from me!
放開我
Turn that camera off.
把攝像機關了
I'm fucking shooting a fucking infomercial here,
我他媽在拍宣傳片呢
you fucking cocksucker!
你們這群混球
- Fuck you, you motherfucker! - Shut the fucking camera off.
-去你的  你個混球  -關掉攝像機
You don't got shit on me, you hear me!
別碰我  聽到了嗎
Go fuck yourself!
都給我滾
I'm making an honest living, you fucking piece of shit!
我掙的都是老實錢  你們這群混球
Hey, Jordan, let me give you a little legal advice.
喬丹  讓我給你點法律建議
Shut the fuck up!
給我閉嘴
Oh, fuck you, you fucking prick!
去你的  你個混球
I'm making an honest living, you motherfucker!
我掙的都是老實錢  你們這群混球
I clean up my act. I did rehab. I'm a TV personality.
我改過自新  成了電視名人
I'm sober for two years. And this happens!
兩年滴酒不沾了  卻發生這事
Rugrat goes and gets busted down in Miami.
魯格拉特在邁阿密被逮捕了
I'm Swiss, I'm not communist.
我是瑞士人  不是共和黨人
And guess who the fuck with? Saurel.
猜猜誰也被捕了  索雷爾
- You gonna beat me? - No, sir.
-你要揍我嗎  -不  先生
Yeah, I know your country. You're gonna beat me.
我了解你們國家  你們會揍我的
I mean, what are the fucking odds?
這是什么鬼幾率
There had to be 10,000 Swiss bankers in Geneva,
日內瓦有上萬個瑞士銀行家
and Rugrat gets the one dumb
魯格拉特就找了一個
enough to get himself arrested on U.S. Soil.
讓自己在美國本土上被逮捕的笨蛋
I know.
我知道
I'm so sorry.
很抱歉
Even more fucked was that
更扯淡的是
he got busted for shit that had nothing to do with me.
他被逮捕  跟我一點關系都沒有
It had nothing to fucking do with me.
跟我沒有半毛錢關系
Something about laundering drug money
說是一起通過海外龍舟賽
through offshore boat racing
進行的販毒洗錢事件
and a guy named Rocky Aoki,
一個叫洛奇·青木的人
you know, the founder of Benihana.
紅花餐館創始人
Benihana.
紅花餐館
Beni-fucking-hana!
紅你個頭啊
Why?
為什么
Why, why, God?
為什么啊  老天爺
Why would you be so cruel
你為什么那么殘忍
as to choose a chain of fucking hibachi restaurants
要我和一家鐵板燒連鎖餐廳
to take me down?
一起倒臺
Long story short. Saurel rats me out.
長話短說  索雷爾把我供了出來
But not before he rats out Brad's wife, Chantalle,
但他首先供出了布拉德的老婆  仙黛爾
who, it turns out,
結果發現
he'd been fucking every time she went to Switzerland!
她每次去瑞士  都要跟他通奸
- No, no, no, it's impossible. - Oui, oui, oui.
-不不不  這不可能  -是的是的
All right!
好吧
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit securities fraud.
一起合謀證券欺詐罪
Two counts securities fraud.
兩起證券欺詐罪
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit money laundering.
一起合謀洗錢罪
Twenty-one counts money laundering.
21起洗錢罪
One count obstruction of justice.
一起妨礙司法罪
Bail is set at $10 million.
保釋金是一千萬
Uncle Donnie's here!
唐尼叔叔來咯
Rocky. How you doing?
洛奇  過得還好吧
I hate that fucking dog.
我恨死那只狗了
Yeah, he's getting old and decrepit.
是啊  老了  變得毫無節制
Starting to shit in the house again.
又開始在家里隨地大小便了
- Me, too. - Come here, buddy.
-我也是  -抱一個  兄弟
- It's good to see you, pal. - Yeah, you, too.
-很高興見到你  兄弟  -我也是
Good to see you. Sit down. Oh, man.
很高興見到你  坐吧
How you doing, brother?
過得怎樣  兄弟
You know.
你懂的
Shitty, pal.
糟透了  兄弟
But I'm hanging in there.
但還是能撐住的
My new piece of jewelry. Check that out.
看看我的新腳鏈
Can't leave the house, you know?
不能踏出家里半步
Starting to get cabin fever already.
都快得幽居病了
Fucking Rugrat.
該死的魯格拉特
That wig-wearing faggot.
那帶假發的死基佬
I can't believe that fucking guy. I wanna kill him.
就不該相信那混球  真想殺了他
Swear to God, I want to choke him to death.
對天發誓  我真想掐死他
Irresponsible little prick.
不負責任的賤貨
I'll tell you one thing.
我要告訴你一件事
I'm never eating at Benihana again.
不管是誰的生日
I don't care whose birthday it is.
我都不去紅花餐館吃飯了
Where's Naomi? How's she doing?
內奧米在哪  她還好吧
That's her in the house there.
在哪邊
You could say hi, but she probably won't wave back.
你跟她打招呼  估計她也不會理你
Naomi, sweetheart!
親愛的內奧米
What's up her ass?
她怎么了
- Is she mad at me? - No, you know...
-她在生我的氣嗎  -不  你懂的
We probably have to mortgage the house
為了交保釋金
in order to make bail.
我們應該要把房子抵押了
Probably end up selling the
或許還要賣些東西
thing in order to pay for all the lawyers.
才能給律師們發工資
It's been a nightmare, buddy, to tell you the truth.
說實話  這真是一場噩夢  兄弟
What are you gonna do, right?
要不然能怎么辦呢  對吧
Anyway, how's Stratton? That's more important.
斯特拉頓才是重點  情況如何
How's morale?
士氣如何
They all pissed off 'cause they have to make money legally now?
現在要合法掙錢  他們都氣壞了吧
Jordan.
喬丹
I got the founding partners together.
我把創始人都找來了
I talked to them about everything.
跟他們說明了情況
And I got you.
有我在呢
What do you mean, you got me?
有你在是什么意思
The house, money, don't worry about it. I got you.
房子和錢的事都別擔心  有我在
- All right. - I love you, buddy.
-好了  -我愛你  兄弟
- You know I'd do it for you, right? - I know.
-我也會為你這樣做的  -我知道
- You know that, right? - I know.
-你知道的  對吧  -我知道
I could fucking kiss you all over.
真想親遍你全身
All right, enough, enough.
好了  夠了  夠了
You want a beer, pal?
想喝啤酒嗎  兄弟
What are you drinking?
你在喝什么
I got this non-alcoholic shit.
不含酒精的東西
What's that?
那是什么
A non-alcoholic beer. It's got no alcohol.
不含酒精的啤酒
- It's a beer? - Yeah, with no alcohol.
-是啤酒嗎  -是的  不含酒精
But if you drink enough,
如果你喝多了
if you drink a lot, they get you fucked up?
如果你喝很多的話  還是會醉嗎
No, there's no alcohol. That's the fucking point.
不會的  不含酒精  這才是重點
I'm not a scientist.
我不是科學家
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
不知道你在說什么
I can get you a beer if you want a fucking beer.
你想喝啤酒的話  我可以給你拿
I know, but I don't drink. You remember?
我知道  但是我不喝酒了  記得嗎
I don't drink anymore.
我已經戒酒了
Oh, you wanna go inside and blow some lines of baking powder?
你想進屋里吸點發酵粉嗎
Or baking soda.
或者是蘇打粉
Can't imagine ever not enjoying getting fucked up.
無法想象再也不能嗑嗨的日子啊
- Yeah. - I love it.
-是啊  -我愛死那些日子了
How's being sober?
戒酒的日子怎樣
- Fucking sucks. - Boring, right?
-糟糕透了  -很無聊  對吧
So boring. I wanna kill myself.
無聊到我想自殺了
There's a term, and we don't like to use it
有個詞  我們不太想用
unless circumstances dictate,
除非在特殊情況下
and I think they do dictate in this case,
我認為這個案子夠特殊的了
and the term is "Grenada."
那個詞就是  格林納達
Have you ever heard of Grenada?
你聽說過格林納達嗎
No. No, I haven't.
沒聽過
Grenada's very interesting because it is a small island nation
格林納達是個很有趣的小島國
that was invaded by the United States of America in 1983.
1983年的時候被美國侵略
It's about 90,000 people.
大約有九萬人
And essentially, it means
換句話說
this case is unloseable.
這個案子我們不可能輸
Okay?
懂嗎
So, you know,
也就是說
we can come in, we can have our dick hanging out of our pants.
就算我們光著褲子走上法庭
Nobody gives a fuck.
也沒有人會在乎
I'm gonna win.
我贏定了
You, sir,
而你呢
are what's known as a Grenada.
就是格林納達
You're looking at real prison time.
你就等著判刑吧
Money laundering can get you as much as 20 years.
洗錢至少要吃20年牢飯
And our case couldn't be stronger if we caught you
如果不是抓到你往海外塞錢
shoving cash in your mattress.
這案子也不會那么簡單
Is that right?
真的嗎
Hey, Jordan. Jordan.
喬丹
Your rotting away in jail till your kids get out of college,
你要在牢里等死  直到孩子大學畢業
that's not our ambition here.
那并不是我們的目的
There's other people involved in this, too.
還有其他人參與洗錢的勾當
We think they need to see their day in court as well.
我們認為他們也應該被送上法庭
Why do I sense there's an offer in the air?
我怎么覺得你們是要提條件呢
Look at him. He's got a sense. What are you, Kreskin?
你看他多聰明  你是心靈感應大師嗎
Full cooperation. He provides us with a comprehensive list
全面配合  也就是過去七年間
of all the co-conspirators spanning the last seven years,
所有同謀的詳細名單提供給我們
and he also agrees to wear a wire.
還要同意帶竊聽器
Wait...
等會
did you just say "wear a wire"?
你剛才說讓我"帶竊聽器"嗎
A wire.
竊聽器
What does that mean?
什么意思
You want me to rat? Is that it?
你想讓我告密  是嗎
No, I want you to cooperate.
不  我想讓你合作
No. You want me to rat, right?
不  你就是想讓我告密
Yes. We want you to rat.
沒錯  就是讓你告密
That's fucking exactly what we want you to do. To rat.
我們還就他媽的想讓你干這件事  告密
How was Cristy's party?
克里斯蒂的派對怎么樣
Fine.
不錯
Good.
那就好
Babe, I spoke to the lawyers again today.
寶貝  我今天又去見過律師了
I have some really, really great news.
我有非常非常好的消息要告訴你
Turns out you're completely off the hook, honey.
看來這件事完全不會涉及到你  親愛的
I know that already.
這我早就知道
Right. Exactly.
沒錯  也是
You never did anything wrong in the first place, right?
你本來也就沒做過什么錯事  對吧
It turns out, all the FBI really
鬧了半天  聯邦調查局
wants from me is to cooperate.
真正想讓我做的就是跟他們合作
You know?
你知道嗎
Turns out I have so much
因為我手上掌握了很多
information about the stock market and Wall Street,
關于股票市場和華爾街的內幕
I could save the government years of heartache,
我可以給政府省好幾年的心
not to mention countless dollars.
更別提數以百萬的經濟損失了
But it gets even better, babe.
但是更好的還在后頭呢  寶貝
Because if I do decide to cooperate,
如果我決定跟他們合作的話
I might only be looking at four short years,
我只能只需要蹲個短短四年就行了
in which case, you know,
這樣一來
we could start fresh, maybe sell the house.
我們可以重新來過  也許把房子賣了
And any fines that I'd have to pay
我要交的任何罰款
wouldn't be due till after I serve my term,
也是等到我刑滿出獄后才用交
so we'd still have plenty of money left over, you know?
所以我們還會剩下很多錢
The only thing that of course bummed me out a little bit
當然了  唯一讓我有點不爽的就是
is this whole idea of
他們想讓我
having to give information about my friends.
提供關于我朋友的信息
Like you said, "There's no friends on Wall Street." Right?
你不是說過"華爾街上無朋友"嗎
Right. Right. Exactly.
是的  是的  沒錯
There's a silver lining to that, too, honey.
這件事也有好的一面  親愛的
Because they said eventually...
因為他們說最終
eventually everyone's
最終所有人
gonna have to give information on this case.
都必須提供關于這個案件的信息
So, at the end of the day,
所以到了最后
it might not even be a factor. You know?
我告密的事也不算什么了
Well, that's good news. Right?
這是好消息  對吧
Yeah, yeah.
沒錯  沒錯
I'm really happy for you.
我真為你高興
What do you mean, happy for me, sweetheart?
什么叫為我高興啊  親愛的
You should be happy for the both of us. Right?
你應該為咱倆高興啊  對吧
- Yeah, right. - All right.
-沒錯  -好的
Come here, baby.
過來  寶貝
Give me a kiss, sweetheart.
親親我  甜心
Jordan...
喬丹
Oh, come on, baby.
來吧  寶貝
I haven't made love to you in so long. Please.
我都好久沒跟你做愛了  求你了
- No. Jordan, stop it. - Come on, honey, please.
-喬丹  不要  -親愛的  求你了
No! Jordan, stop it!
不要  喬丹  夠了
I've loved you since the moment I saw you.
我第一眼看到你就愛上你了
I fucking hate you, Jordan.
我他媽的恨死你了  喬丹
- Get off me! - Baby... don't do that.
-給我下去  -寶貝  別這樣
You know how much I love you, right?
你知道我有多愛你  對吧
Stop that, sweetie. Please.
別這樣對我了  親愛的  求你了
You wanna fuck me, Jordan?
你想上我嗎  喬丹
You wanna fuck me?
你想上我嗎
Good.
很好
Go ahead.
來吧
Go ahead and fuck me.
盡管來上我吧
I want you to fuck me real hard.
我要你狠狠地上我
I want you to fuck me like it's the last fucking time.
我要你把這當成是最后一次一樣操我
- Why are you moving like that? - Come on.
-你為什么要這么動  -來啊
Please hold still.
別動
'Cause I want you to come for me, baby.
因為我想讓你射給我啊  寶貝
Come on, babe.
來啊  寶貝
Come for me, baby.
射給我啊  寶貝啊
I want you to come for me
我要你把這當做是最后一次一樣
like it's the last fucking time.
狠狠地射給我
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-是嗎  -是
Come on, baby. Come for me. Come for me, baby.
來啊  寶貝  射給我  寶貝
Come on, baby.
來啊  寶貝
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-你喜歡這樣  -是啊
- Yeah, baby, come. - You want me to come for you?
-寶貝  射啊  -你想讓我射給你
Yeah.
是
- You want me to come for you? - Yeah!
-你想讓我射給你  -是
Huh? You want me to come for you?
你想讓我射給你嗎
Oh, God, baby. Yeah!
天啊  寶貝
Oh, God. Oh, God.
天啊  天啊
Oh, God.
天啊
Jesus.
上帝啊
Oh, baby.
寶貝
That was so fucking great!
真是爽死了
Oh, God!
天啊
That was the last time.
這是最后一次了
What do you mean, baby?
什么意思  寶貝
I mean that was the last time we ever have sex.
我是說  剛才那就是我們的最后一次了
What are you talking about?
你在說什么呀
I want a divorce.
我要離婚
What do you mean, you want a divorce?
你這是什么意思  你要離婚
What's that supposed to mean, you want a divorce?
你在說什么啊  你要離婚
Get off me! I want a divorce.
放開我  我要跟你離婚
You just made love to me.
你剛剛才跟我上完床
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你他媽的是什么毛病啊
I don't love you anymore, Jordan!
我不愛你了  喬丹
Oh, you don't love me?
你不愛我了
You don't love me anymore, huh?
你已經不愛我了
Well, isn't that just fucking convenient for you!
你還真會挑時候啊
Now that I'm under federal indictment,
我現在被聯邦政府起訴
with an electronic bracelet around my ankle,
腳脖子上還綁著個電子監控器
now you decide you don't fucking love me anymore.
然后你他媽的決定不愛我了
- Is that right? - No, no.
-是嗎  -不  不
What kind of person are you? Tell me.
你到底是什么人啊  說啊
You married me!
是你娶的我
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
你這話是他媽的什么意思
Jordan, this is how it's gonna go.
喬丹  接下來這么安排
I'm gonna take custody of the kids.
孩子的監護權歸我
If you agree to the divorce right now, I will allow visitation.
你同意離婚  我還可以讓你探望孩子
- Okay? Don't try to fight it. - Oh, my God.
-好嗎  你別想著跟我爭  -天啊
It'll save us both a lot of money
我們好聚好散  也能給咱倆省點錢
and I got a feeling you're gonna need it.
而且我覺得你以后用錢的地方還多著呢
You're not taking my kids, sweetheart. You hear me?
你別想帶走我的孩子  親愛的
I've already talked to the lawyer.
我已經找律師問過了
He said even if you don't get convicted,
他說就算你不被定罪
I've got a good chance of getting them.
孩子的監護權歸我的可能性也很大
I got news for you.
我告訴你
You're not fucking taking my children,
你他媽的別想帶走我的孩子
you vicious fucking cunt, you!
你這個惡毒的蕩婦
Fuck you, you fucking bitch!
操你  你他媽的臭婊子
You're not fucking taking my goddamn fucking kids!
你他媽的別想帶走我的孩子
You hear me? Fuck you!
聽見了嗎  操你
Fucking bitch!
該死的臭婊子
Fucking whore!
該死的雞
Fucking bitch! Piece of shit fucking whore!
他媽的臭婊子  該死的雞
Look at yourself, Jordan.
看看你的德行  喬丹
You're sick!
你變態
You're a sick man!
你就是個變態
Fuck you! I told you, you're not taking my fucking kids!
操你  我告訴你  你別想帶走孩子
You think I would let my kids near you?
你認為我會讓我的孩子待在你身邊嗎
Look at yourself!
看看你這個德行
You know what my lawyer said?
你知道我的律師怎么說嗎
My lawyer said that you're going to prison for 20 years, Jordan.
我律師說你要蹲二十年大牢  喬丹
Twenty fucking years! You're never gonna see the kids again!
二十年啊  你別打算再見到孩子了
You don't think I'm not gonna see my...
你以為我再也見不到……
No, I'm not fucking letting you near my kids!
不  我才不會讓你接近我的孩子呢
You don't think I'm gonna see my fucking kids again, huh?
你以為我再也見不到我自己的孩子了
Don't you fucking touch them!
你他媽的別碰他們
Don't you fucking touch me!
你他媽的別碰我
Sweetheart? You're coming on a trip with Daddy, all right?
寶貝  爸爸帶你出去玩  好嗎
You're coming on a trip with Daddy.
你要跟爸爸出去玩了
Don't you fucking touch her, Jordan.
你別他媽的碰她  喬丹
I swear to God, I will fucking kill you!
我對天發誓  我他媽的會宰了你的
It's all right, baby.
沒事的  寶貝
You and Daddy are gonna go on a little trip together, okay?
爸爸帶你出去玩  好嗎
- A little trip together. - Violet!
-咱倆一起去玩  -瓦奧萊特
Violet!
瓦奧萊特
- Get the key! Get the key! - I got it!
-去拿鑰匙  去拿鑰匙  -好的
Jordan, you open this fucking door
喬丹  你他媽的趕緊
- right now! Open the door! - Put your seat belt on.
-把門打開  開門  -系上安全帶
There you go. Get your legs in.
好了  把腿放進來
I'm taking her with me!
我要帶她走了
I told you I'm taking her with me, you fucking bitch!
我告訴你  我要把她帶走了  臭婊子
You're not gonna stop me! You're not gonna stop me!
你阻止不了我  你阻止不了我
We're going on a little trip, honey.
咱們去玩  寶貝
No! No!
不  不
Get the hell out of here!
你給我滾開
Leave that baby alone!
別煩孩子
Violet! Garage door! Close it!
瓦奧萊特  車庫門  把車庫門關上
Mommy!
媽咪
- Get out of here! - Open the fucking door!
-給我下車  -把門給我打開
No!
不
Oh, Lord! Oh, my heavens...
天啊  上帝啊
Get the baby!
去抱孩子
Naomi, get the baby!
內奧米  去抱孩子
- Mommy. - Honey, it's okay.
-媽咪  -寶貝  沒事了
It's gonna be okay.
沒事了
Oh, Mr. Jordan has lost his mind.
喬丹先生已經瘋了
- Baby... - It's all right, honey.
-寶貝……  -沒事的  親愛的
She all right?
她沒事吧
What's the matter with you?
你搞什么呀
Paragraph one.
第一自然段
The defendant shall plead guilty
被告將對美國聯邦地方法院
to all counts of the indictment currently pending against him
美國東區地方法院
in the United States District Court
對其提起的一切指控
for the Eastern District of New York.
認罪
Paragraph two.
第二自然段
Talk normally.
講話自然點
The defendant shall participate in undercover activities...
被告將參與臥底行為……
Breathe normally.
呼吸自然點
... including wearing a recording device, also known as a wire...
包括隨身佩戴錄音設備  也就是竊聽器
After five minutes, you'll forget you even have it on.
五分鐘以后  你就會忘記它的存在了
...in conjunction with the investigation...
配合調查……
Fucking brutal.
太他媽的殘忍了
Quit your bitching.
少抱怨了
Paragraph four. The defendant must not commit,
第四自然段  被告嚴禁繼續
or attempt to commit, any further crimes.
或是試圖繼續犯下任何進一步的罪行
Please. Let me just sign the fucking thing already.
拜托  直接讓我簽了這該死的文件吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Just here?
簽在這就行了
That'd be good.
那就行了
Thank you.
謝謝
It wasn't even a choice.
我根本別無選擇
For the next six hours, I came up with a list.
接下來的六個小時里  我列了張名單
Friends, enemies, business associates.
朋友  敵人  商業伙伴
Anybody who'd ever known me or
所有曾認識我的人或是
taken so much as a stock tip.
從我這里得到過一丁點股票建議的人
Wolfie! Wolfie! Wolfie!
狼哥  狼哥
The first name on the list was Donnie.
名單上的第一個人就是唐尼
Jordan, do you know how
喬丹  你知不知道
good it is to have you back in this office?
你能回來是件多好的事
It's not the same when you're gone.
你不在的時候一切都感覺不一樣了
It's sad, you understand? It's like...
很悲傷的感覺  你明白嗎  像是
That fucking Steve Madden, huh?
該死的史蒂夫·麥登
I can't...
我無法……
Swear to God, I can't even think about it.
我對天發誓  我連想都不能想這件事
Every time I think about him, my blood boils.
我每次一想到他  我就氣得血液沸騰
I can't even say his name.
我都不能說他的名字
- I know. - It's, like, disgusting.
-我明白  -太惡心了
I grew up with this guy and he betrays me like that.
我跟他一起長大  他卻這樣背叛我
He ever get back to you about that...
他后來有沒有……
about that account?
有沒有跟你說過那個賬戶的事
You remember.
你記得的
It was like four or five mil, something like that, right?
差不多有四五百萬的  對吧
He was supposed to kick back four or five mil, was it?
他應該要退還四五百萬  對吧
Actually, I was...
實際上  我那個時候
I was fucked up, Jordan,
我那時候嗑藥磕得一團糟  喬丹
- so I don't really remember. - Yeah.
-所以我什么都不記得了  -是啊
Yeah, right. Stupid.
是啊  你個傻瓜
Well, if he calls you, you make sure and contact me, okay?
如果他打來  你就通知我  好嗎
- Yeah. Of course. - Yeah.
-當然了  -好
Of course, yeah. No, of course.
當然  當然
You gonna eat that last piece of yellowtail, bud?
最后那塊黃獅魚你還吃不吃  伙計
No, it's all yours.
不吃了  都給你吧
Can I get this?
我能蘸這個嗎
So, what else is...
那么  還有什么……
Well, how's Naomi and everything?
內奧米和其它一切都還好嗎
You know how it is.
你也知道
She hates my fucking guts.
她現在恨死我了
How's Hildy? Good?
希爾迪怎么樣  她還好嗎
She's still alive, so my life is fucked, you know?
她還活著  所以活的也很糟
Yeah.
明白
Mr. Jordan.
喬丹先生
Mr. Jordan, you got a visitor.
喬丹先生  有客人找您
What?
什么
You've got a visitor.
有客人找您
I need you to get dressed.
你馬上穿好衣服
Why? What the fuck's going on?
為什么  這是搞什么
You're going to jail.
你要去蹲監獄了
All right.
好吧
I'll get some clothes on.
我去穿衣服
We'll give you a hand with that.
我們幫你
Okay.
好吧
FBI!
聯邦調查局
Everybody sit down.
所有人坐下
Put your hands where they can be seen, and shut up!
把手舉起來  不許出聲
Don't you fucking touch me.
你他媽的別碰我
Get your fucking hands off me!
你他媽的放開我
Don't get out of your seats!
不許離開你們的座位
It's fucking Chanel!
這他媽的可是香奈兒
I gave up everyone.
我告發了所有人
And in return,
作為回報
I got three years in some
我在內華達的一個我從來沒聽說過的
hellhole in Nevada I'd never even heard of.
鬼地方蹲了三年
Like my pops, Mad Max, had said,
就像我父親瘋狂麥克斯曾經說過的
"The chickens had come home to roost."
"惡有惡報"
Whatever the fuck that means.
隨便他什么意思吧
I hope Your Honor would agree
我希望法官大人認同
that Mr. Belfort has distinguished himself
貝爾福先生在跟聯邦調查局合作方面
in terms of his cooperation.
有出色的表現
Mr. Belfort has helped the government win convictions
在貝爾福先生的協助下
of over two dozen serious offenders
政府給二十四余名重罪犯定了罪
and helped them recover millions of dollars
并且追回了成百上千萬美金
to be made available for restitution to their victims.
用以補償受害者
The sentence of the court shall be
法庭對被告的判決為
36 months in federal prison.
在聯邦監獄關押三十六個月
Please remand the defendant.
請把被告押回去
I'm sorry.
抱歉
That's okay.
沒關系
I'm not ashamed to admit it.
我承認  當我們到監獄的時候
When we arrived at the prison,
我快嚇死了
I was absolutely terrified.
我不覺得這有什么丟人的
Belfort, on your feet.
貝爾福  站起來
But I needn't have been.
但實際上我用不著害怕
You see, for a brief fleeting moment,
有那么很短的一瞬間
I'd forgotten I was rich.
我忘了自己曾富得流油了
And I lived in a place where everything was for sale.
而我住在消費的世界里
Wouldn't you like to learn how to sell it?
你難道不想學一下怎么把它們賣掉嗎
So listen. I've met some bad motherfuckers in my life.
聽好了  我這輩子見過不少混蛋
I'm talking about rock stars, professional athletes, gangsters.
搖滾明星  專業運動員  黑幫分子
I'm telling you, some real bad motherfuckers.
真的是一些壞得透頂的混蛋
But this guy, my good friend,
但是這家伙  我的好朋友
Mr. Jordan Belfort, is the single
喬丹·貝爾福先生真的是
baddest motherfucker I have ever met.
我這輩子遇見過的最最最最最壞的混蛋了
So I want you right now
所以我現在希望你們
to give a warm Auckland, New Zealand welcome
向我的好朋友  世界上最棒的銷售員
for my good friend and the world's greatest sales trainer,
獻上新西蘭奧克蘭最誠摯的歡迎
Mr. Jordan Belfort!
有請喬丹·貝爾福先生
Thank you.
謝謝你們
Sell me this pen.
向我推銷這支筆
It's...
這是……
It's an amazing pen.
這是一支很棒的筆
For professionals, it's a...
對于專業人士來說  這是一支……
Sell me this pen.
向我推銷這支筆
Well, it's a nice pen.
這是支好筆
You can use the pen
你可以用這支筆
to write down thoughts from your life so you can...
記下生活的點點滴滴  這樣一來你就能
Sell me this pen.
向我推銷這支筆
Well...
那個……
This pen works and I personally love this pen...
這支筆很好用  我個人也很喜歡